Here we are, ma'am. Crawley House.
For good or ill.
I still don't see why I
couldn't just refuse it.
There's no mechanism
for you to do so.
You WILL be an earl, you
WILL inherit the estate.
Of course, you can throw it away
when you have it, that's up to you.
Can I help?
I'm Molesley, sir.
Your butler and valet.
- Mr. Molesley, I'm afraid...
- May I introduce ourselves?
I am Mrs. Crawley, and this is
my son, Mr. Matthew Crawley.
I'll just give Mr. Taylor
a hand with the cases.
- I can...
- Thank you, Molesley.
I won't let them change me.
Why would they want to?
Mother, Lord Grantham has
made the unwelcome discovery
that his heir
is a middle-class lawyer
- and the son of a middle class doctor.
- Upper middle class.
He wants to limit the damage by
turning me into one of his own kind.
When you met him in
London you liked him.
I simply do not understand
why we are rushing into this.
Matthew Crawley is my heir.
Patrick was your heir.
He never lived here.
Patrick was in and out of this
house since the day he was born.
You saw how many of the village
turned out for the service.
- Nothing's settled yet. It
- Is settled, my dearest one,
whether you like it or not.
I wouldn't say that.
Not while your mother breathes air.
Oh, Ellen,
this is much better than
I thought it would be.
- You have done well.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Would you like this in here,
ma'am, or taken up to your room?
In here, thank you.
So, are you the whole
of our new household?
There's a local girl, ma'am, Beth.
She's to double under-housemaid
and kitchen maid.
- This is ridiculous.
- Thank you very much, Molesley.
- Might we have some tea?
- Very good, ma'am.
- Well, he can go right now.
- Why?
Because we do not need a butler,
or a valet if it comes to that.
We've always managed perfectly
well with a cook and a maid,
- and they cannot expect us to...
- What they expect, Matthew,
is that we won't know how to
behave, so if you don't mind
I would rather not
confirm their expectations.
I have to be myself, Mother.
I'll be no use to anyone
if I can't be myself.
And before they, or you,
get any ideas,
- I will choose my own wife.
- What on earth do you mean?
They'll push one of
the daughters at me.
They'll have fixed on that when
they heard I was a bachelor.
Lady Mary Crawley.
I do hope I'm not interrupting.
- Lady Mary.
- Cousin Mary, please.
Mama has sent me down to welcome you
and to ask you dine with us tonight.
Unless you're too tired.
- We would be delighted.
- Good.
Come at eight.
Won't you stay and have some tea?
Oh, no. You're far too busy.
And I wouldn't want to push in.
Lynch, I think we'll go
back by the South Lodge.
Very good, m'lady.
Lady Mary, I hope you
didn't misunderstand me.
I was only joking.
Of course. And I agree.
The whole thing is a complete joke.
So what do you think
we'll make of them?
I shouldn't think much.
She hasn't even got a lady's maid.
It's not a capital offence.
She's got a maid. Her name's Ellen.
She's not a lady's maid.
She's just a housemaid
that fastens hooks and
buttons when she has to.
There's more to it
than that, you know.
Daisy!
We want some very precise
reporting when dinner's over.
- Are we to treat him as the heir?
- Are we 'eck as like!
A doctor's son from Manchester?!
He'll be lucky if he gets
a civil word out of me.
We're ALL lucky if we get
a civil word out of you.
Gwen, parcel for you.
Came by evening post.
Thank you, Mr. Carson.
William.
Have you seen them yet, Mr. Carson?
By "them", I assume you mean the
new family. In which case, no.
I have that pleasure to
look forward to this evening.
Daisy, did you hear me call or
have you gone selectively deaf?
- No, Mrs. Patmore.
Then might I remind you
we are preparing dinner
for your future employer?
And if it goes wrong,
I'll be telling them why!
Why are they here at all
when you're going to undo it?
Your father's not
convinced it can be undone.
But you'll still try.
Granny and I are willing to try.
And Papa is not?
We'll bring him round, you'll see.
We're trying to find a
lawyer who'll take it on.
So what are they like?
She's nice enough,
but he's...very full of himself.
- Why do you say that?
- Just an impression.
Let's go down and you
can decide for yourself.
Hello again.
It's a pleasure to meet
you at last, Mrs. Crawley.
We're delighted to be here.
- Aren't we, Matthew?
- Delighted.
Welcome to Downton.
Thank you. You've been so kind.
What a reception committee!
Yes. Thank you.
This is Carson. We'd
all be lost without him.
Mama, may I present Matthew Crawley
and Mrs. Crawley?
My mother, Lady Grantham.
What should we call each other?
Well, we could always start with
Mrs. Crawley and Lady Grantham.
Come into the drawing room and
we can make all the introductions.
Thank you, Carson.
Do you think you'll
enjoy village life?
It'll be very quiet
after life in the city.
Even Manchester.
I'm sure I'll find
something to keep me busy.
- You might like the hospital.
- What sort of hospital is it?
How many beds?
Well, it isn't really a hospital.
Don't let Dr. Clarkson hear you.
He thinks it's second
only to St Thomas's.
It's a cottage hospital, of
course, but quite well equipped.
Who pays for it?
Oh, good. Let's talk about money!
My father gave the building
and an endowment to run it.
In a way, he set
up his own memorial.
But how splendid.
And Mr. Lloyd George's new
insurance measures will help.
Please don't speak that man's name.
We are about to eat.
I will hold it steady and
you can help yourself, sir.
Yes, I know.
Thank you.
You'll soon get used to the
way things are done here.
If you mean that I am accustomed
to a very different life from this,
then that is true.
What will you do with your time?
I've got a job in Ripon.
I said I'll start tomorrow.
A job?!
In a partnership. You might have
heard of it. Harvell and Carter.
They need someone who understands
industrial law, I'm glad to say.
Although I'm afraid most of it
will be wills and conveyancing.
You do know I mean to involve
you in the running of the estate?
Well, don't worry. There are
plenty of hours in the day.
And of course I'll
have the weekend.
We'll discuss this later.
We mustn't bore the ladies.
What is a weekend?
- Why shouldn't he be a lawyer?
- Gentlemen don't work, silly.
Not real gentlemen.
- Don't listen to her, Daisy.
- No, listen to me!
And take those kidneys
up to the servery before I
knock you down and serve
your brains as fritters!
Yes, Mrs. Patmore!
I wonder what that Mr.
Molesley makes of them.
Poor old Molesley. I pity
the man who's taken that job.
Then why did you apply for it?
I thought it might help me
to get away from you, Mr. Bates.
I'm so interested
to see the hospital.
Well, you would be, with
your late husband a doctor.
Not just my husband.
My father and brother too, and I
trained as a nurse during the war.
Fancy.
I'd love to be
involved in some way.
Well, you could always help with
the bring-and-buy sale next month.
That would be most appreciated.
I should say so.
She's a match for the old lady.
She wasn't going to give in.
What old lady are you
referring to, Thomas?
You cannot mean her ladyship
the Dowager Countess.
Not if you wish to
remain in this house.
No, Mr. Carson.
William.
Are you aware the seam at
your shoulder is coming apart?
I-I felt it go a bit earlier
on. I'll mend it when we turn in.
You will mend it now! And you
will never again appear in public
- in a similar state of undress!
- No, Mr. Carson.
To progress in your
chosen career, William,
you must remember that a
good servant at all times
retains a sense of pride and dignity
that reflects the pride and
dignity of the family he serves.
And never make me
remind you of it again.
I'll do it.
And cheer up. We've all
had a smack from Mr. Carson.
You'll be the butler
yourself one day.
- Then you'll do the smacking.
- I could never be like him.
I bet he comes from
a line of butlers
that goes back to the Conqueror.
He learned his business,
and so will you.
Even Mr. Carson wasn't
born standing to attention.
I hope not, for his mother's sake.
This was at the back door.
Thank you, William.
It's kind of you
to take an interest.
I'm afraid it's a case of
the warhorse and the drum.
You know my late
husband was a doctor.
I do. I'm familiar
with Dr. Crawley's work
on the symptoms of
infection in children.
Even I studied nursing
during the South African war.
Really?
Very distressing.
Young farmer. John Drake.
Tenant of Lord Grantham's.
He came in today.
It's dropsy, I'm afraid.
- May I see him?
- Yes, by all means.
Is the dropsy of the
liver or the heart?
Everything points to the heart.
Alright, Mr. Drake.
You're in safe hands now.
What will happen to his wife?
She may try to keep the farm on.
Grantham is not a
harsh landlord, but...
her children are young.
What can I do to help?
If I'm to live in this village,
I must have an occupation.
Please. Let me be useful.
He chooses his clothes himself.
He puts them out at night
and hangs the ones he's worn.
I get to take the linen down to
the laundry, but that's about all.
That's all?
"I'll do this," he says. "I'll
take the other." "I'll tie that."
And I'm just stood
there like a chump,
watching a man get dressed.
To be honest, Mr. Bates,
I don't see the point of it.
- I thought you didn't like him.
- So what?
I have plenty of
friends I don't like.
Would you want Mary
to marry one of them?
Why do you always have to pretend
to be nicer than the rest of us?
Perhaps I am.
Then pity your wife,
whose fortune must go
to this odd young man
who talks about weekends and jobs.
If Mary were to marry him,
then all would be resolved.
- What have you got there?
- Nothing.
What kind of nothing?
You haven't got an admirer.
I might have. Why shouldn't I?
Don't tell Mrs. Hughes.
She'll bring the vicar
round to have you exorcised.
How are we supposed
to find husbands
if we're never allowed to see
any men?
Perhaps she thinks
the stork brings them.
'Ey, Lady Mary's in for a surprise.
Thomas was in the library when
old Violet came in from the garden.
Seems they want to fix
her up with Mr. Crawley.
Well, it makes sense. She
was gonna marry Mr. Patrick.
Would she have, though,
when it came to it?
That's the question.
Ah, there you are, dear.
I was hoping you'd be home in time.
In time for what?
I've been paid the
compliment of a visit.
- Hello!
- Good afternoon, Cousin Matthew.
Good afternoon.
We were just saying how
charming this room is now.
Mm. It always seemed rather dark
when my mother-in-law lived here.
But then she made
everything rather dark!
Sir.
No, thank you.
- Cup of tea, sir?
- It's alright, I'll help myself.
So, Molesley,
how do you find being home again?
Your father must
be glad you're back.
He is, your ladyship.
- Might I give you this cup?
- Ma'am.
I'm afraid we must be going.
Thank you.
You'll think about it?
Oh. I thought no one was here.
Can I help, Mr. Carson?
No. No thank you, Anna.
May I?
I must compliment
you, Mrs. Crawley.
When you made your offer I thought
you might be a Great Lady Nurse
and faint at the sight of blood,
but I see you're
made of sterner stuff.
It's definitely the heart.
It's almost too
quiet to hear at all.
I'm afraid so.
I've been thinking about
the treatments that are available.
Considerable success has been
achieved over the last few years
by draining the pericardial
sac of the excess fluid
and administering adrenalin.
Mrs. Crawley, I appreciate
your thoroughness...
But you're unwilling to try it?
Injection of adrenalin is a
comparatively new procedure.
It's a while ago now, but
I saw my husband do it.
- I know how.
- Please, Mrs. Crawley,
don't force me to be uncivil.
We will be setting
an impossible precedent.
When every villager could...
could demand the
latest fad in treatment
for each new cut and graze.
I would remind you that we're
not talking of a cut or a graze,
but the loss of a man's life
and the ruin of his family.
Of course.
But I beg you to see
that it is not reasonable.
I'm sorry, but I have standards.
I've just seen
something ever so odd.
If anyone thinks I'm going to
pull my forelock and curtsey
to this Mr. Nobody from nowhere...
O'Brien!
Were you discussing Mr. Crawley?
Yes, m'lady.
Is it your place to do so?
I've got my opinions,
m'lady, same as anybody.
Can I help your ladyship?
This is the button we're
missing from my new evening coat.
I found it lying on the gravel.
But... I was shocked
at the talk I heard as I came in.
Mr. Crawley is his
lordship's cousin and heir.
You will, therefore, please accord
him the respect he is entitled to.
But you don't like
him yourself, m'lady.
You never wanted him...
You're sailing perilously
close to the wind, O'Brien.
If we're to be friends, you
will not speak in that way again
about the Crawleys or any
member of Lord Grantham's family.
Now I'm going up to rest.
Wake me at the dressing gong.
I don't think that's fair.
Not here in the servants' hall.
I agree. If she was a real lady,
she wouldn't have come down here.
She'd have rung for me
and given me the button.
This isn't her territory. We
can say what we like down here.
- Who says?
- The law.
And parliament.
There is such a
thing as free speech.
Not when I'm in charge!
Don't push your luck, Thomas.
Now, tea's over. Back to work.
You'd better take this.
Friends!
Who does she think she's fooling?
We're not friends.
- No?
- No!
And you're not friends
with the girls neither.
We're servants, you and me.
And they pay us to do as
we're told. That's all.
- May I...?
- I can manage.
Where have I put my cuff links?
- I thought these would make a change.
- Where are my usual ones?
I know I'm a disappointment
to you, Molesley,
but it's no good.
I'll never get used to being dressed
like a doll.
- I'm only trying to help, sir.
- Of course.
And if I've offended
you, I apologise.
But surely you have
better things to do.
This is my job, sir.
Well, it seems a very silly
occupation for a grown man.
Look, I'm sorry if I'm...
I'm sorry.
Why are you so against him?
Aside from the fact he's
planning to steal our inheritance?
Your inheritance.
It makes no difference
to Sybil and me.
We won't inherit, whatever happens.
He isn't one of us.
Cousin Freddy's
studying for the bar.
And so is Vivian MacDonald.
At Lincoln's Inn!
Not sitting at a dirty
little desk in Ripon.
Besides, his father was a doctor.
There's nothing wrong with doctors.
We all need doctors.
We all need crossing sweepers
and draymen too,
it doesn't mean
we have to dine with them.
Whom don't we have to dine with?
Mary doesn't care for
Cousin Matthew.
Sybil, be a dear and fetch
my black evening shawl.
O'Brien knows which one.
And Edith, can you see that
the drawing room's ready?
I'm glad to catch you alone.
- You've driven the others away.
- Perhaps I have.
Pretty.
The point is, my dear, I
don't want you, any of you,
to feel you have to dislike Matthew.
- You disliked the idea of him.
- That was before he came.
Now he's here, I don't
see any future in it.
Not the way things are.
I don't believe a woman can be
forced to give away all her money
to a distant cousin
of her husband's.
Not in the 20th century.
It's too ludicrous for words.
It's not as simple as that.
The money isn't mine anymore.
- It forms a part of the estate.
- Even so, when a judge hears...
For once in your life,
will you please just listen!
I believe there's an answer.
Which would secure your future
and give you a position.
You can't be serious.
Just think about it.
I don't have to think about it!
Marry a man who can barely hold
his knife like a gentleman?!
Oh, you exaggerate!
You're American, you don't
understand these things.
Have you mentioned this
to Granny? Did she laugh?
Why would she? It was her idea.
Have you been able to explore
the village?
Indeed I have.
And I thought the hospital
a great credit to
your father's memory.
But I'm afraid the good doctor
and I did not see eye to eye.
Oh! You amaze me!
He's treating one of your
tenants, John Drake, for dropsy.
But seems reluctant to embrace
some of the newer treatments.
Drake is a good man and
far too young to die,
but I suppose the doctor
knows his business.
Not as well as Mrs.
Crawley, apparently.
By the way, if ever you want
to ride, just let Lynch know
and he'll sort it out for you.
Oh, Papa,
Cousin Matthew doesn't ride.
I ride.
- And do you hunt?
- No, I don't hunt.
I dare say there's not much
opportunity in Manchester!
Are you a hunting family?
Families like ours are
always hunting families.
Not always. Billy Skelton
won't have them on his land.
But all the Skeltons are mad.
- Do you hunt?
- Occasionally.
I suppose you're more interested
in books than country sports.
I probably am.
You'll tell me that's
rather unhealthy.
Not unhealthy. Just unusual.
Among our kind of people.
I'm changing round
the dessert services.
We're missing a sugar sifter.
I know I put three out.
I was talking to Anna earlier.
Why? What's she been saying?
- Whatever's the matter?
- What did Anna say?
Only that she thinks
Thomas is bullying William.
Ah. Yes, she may have a point.
I'll keep an eye out.
Here it is.
I've been studying the story of
Andromeda. Do you know it?
- Why?
- Her father was King Cepheus,
whose country was
being ravaged by storms.
And in the end, he decided
the only way to appease the gods
was to sacrifice his eldest daughter
to a hideous sea monster.
So they chained her
naked to a rock...
Really, Mary!
We'll all need our
smelling salts in a minute.
But the sea monster
didn't get her, did he?
No.
Just when it seemed he was the only
solution to her father's problems,
she was rescued.
- By Perseus.
- That's right.
Perseus.
Son of a god.
Rather more fitting,
wouldn't you say?
That depends.
I'd have to know more about the
princess and the sea monster in question.
I wish I could dance like that.
Like what?
Don't you know the Grizzly Bear?
The Grizzly Bear! As if you do.
Certainly I do. Miss
O'Brien, shall we show them?
Not likely!
William, give us a tune.
Come on, Daisy.
Hands up.
Daisy! Daisy!
Stop that silly nonsense
before you put your joints out!
See to the range and go to bed.
Thank you. That was beautiful.
I'm sorry, Mary was
rather sharp this evening.
I doubt if Cousin Mary and I
are destined to be close friends.
I don't blame her.
Her father's home and her mother's
fortune are to be passed to me.
It's very harsh.
Well, what would you say...
... if the entail were
set aside in Mary's favour?
I should try to accept it with
as good a grace as I could muster.
Would you?
Good evening, Taylor.
- Good evening, m'lady.
- Thank you.
I'll say good night, Mr. Carson.
Look at that scratch.
I'll have to get that sorted
out while they're up in London.
- You can hardly see it.
- Well, I'll know it's there.
Are you alright now? Only you
seemed a little upset earlier.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
I'm just um...
... a bit tired.
And no wonder.
Did the dinner go well?
Oh, well enough.
They won't make a match between
them, if that's what they're thinking.
Lady Mary doesn't like him.
And why should she like the
man she's been passed over for?
And why has she been?
- That's what I'd like to know.
- It's the law.
Well, it's a wicked law.
Why does Mr. Carson let you do that?
Because my dad was a clock maker.
Did you really ask him for
the job with the Crawleys?
I'm sick of being a footman.
I'd rather be a footman
than wait on someone
who ought to be a footman himself.
But Mr. Carson shouldn't
have told Bates.
How are things with Lady G?
Same as usual.
Yes m'lady, no m'lady,
three bags full.
I'd like to give her three bags
full, preferably on a dark night.
Will you hand in your notice?
And let her ruin me
with a nasty reference?
Oh, I think not.
I don't want to exaggerate. She's
been very generous, in many ways.
Generous?
To instruct you
in your own practice?
She may even have a point.
But it does not
seem to me realistic.
Well, nor is it!
Put an end to her meddling.
I am your President and
I say get rid of her.
Will that not be awkward?
She's planning to stay in the
village for the foreseeable future.
No one can foresee the future,
Doctor.
Not you, not I, and
certainly not Mrs. Crawley.
You do not love the place yet.
- Well, obviously it's...
- No, you don't love it.
You see a million
bricks that may crumble,
a thousand gutters and pipes
that may block and leak,
and stone that will
crack in the frost.
But you don't?
I see my life's work.
Was it ever in danger?
Many times.
My dear Papa thought the balloon
would go up in the 1880s.
What saved it?
Cora.
Where is everyone?
They've gone down to the village.
Some travelling salesman set
up at the pub for the afternoon.
Alone at last.
We shouldn't be
without both footmen.
Does Mr. Carson know?
Mrs. Hughes does.
She's gone with them.
They won't be long.
So, you see to the girls
and you're supposed
to be head housemaid.
You should put in for a raise.
What do you mean "supposed to be"?
I said they shouldn't
have let both footmen go.
Well, you'll have to answer it.
Mr. Carson wouldn't like a
maid answering the front door.
Sorry to have kept
you waiting, sir.
I'm here to see Lord Grantham.
- Is he expecting you?
- No.
But he'll be very interested
in what I have to tell him.
His lordship is not at home, but
if you will leave your name...
Don't come all high
and mighty with me.
I don't know who you are, but
you're certainly not the butler
so don't try and make out you are.
How do you know?
Because Charlie Carson's
the butler round here.
Does your business concern him?
It might do.
Excuse me for one moment, sir.
Fetch Mr. Carson
as fast as you can.
Use the front door.
- If you would like to follow me, sir.
- No, no.
If you think you're
tucking me away somewhere
you've got another think coming.
- You'll be more comfortable, sir.
- Sorry, chum.
Oh, aye,
I'll not mind waiting in here.
Bates?
This gentlemen is an acquaintance
of Mr. Carson, m'lady.
What's he doing in here?
He says he has urgent
business with his lordship.
Urgent.
I've sent for Mr.
Carson to come at once.
Then I'll stay with you.
In case explanations are needed.
(Thank you.)
Mr. Carson!
You're needed at
once in the library.
How long are you
expecting me to wait?
I'm a very busy man, you know.
If you could just be patient
for a little longer, sir.
May I ask who this is and
precisely what is going on?
Mr. Bates, what are you...
I'm sorry, your lordship.
- Mr. Bates, you may go now.
- Stay where you are.
Nobody's going anywhere.
Do I take it you know this man?
Don't try and deny it.
No, I won't deny it.
I do know him, my lord,
but not what he is
doing in the library.
I tried to take him downstairs out of
sight, Mr. Carson. But he wouldn't come.
Yes, thank you,
that was thoughtful.
But who is he?
Will you tell him, or shall I?
His name is Charles Grigg.
We worked together at one time.
Oh, I'm a little more than
that, aren't I, Charlie?
- We're like brothers, him and me.
- We are not like brothers.
We were a double act.
On the halls.
You were on the stage?!
Carson, is this true?
It is, my lord.
The Cheerful Charlies,
that's what they called us.
We did quite well, didn't we?
Until you couldn't keep
your hands out of the till.
- Would you like us to go, Mr. Carson?
- No.
You know it now.
You might as well bear witness
to my shame.
He turned up in the village
with no warning some days ago.
On the run. Asking for somewhere
to hide and, of course, for money.
God in heaven.
He is wanted for some petty crime,
of which he is, of course, guilty.
Here, steady on.
He threatened... to expose my past,
to make me a laughing
stock in this house.
And in my vanity and pride,
I gave him what he wanted.
You did not!
I put him in an empty cottage
and fed him from the kitchens.
I couldn't buy food in the village,
it would raise to many questions.
I stole.
I'm a thief.
She...saw it.
- I've never have said anything, Mr....
- And now my disgrace is complete.
My lord, you have my resignation.
Really, Carson, there's no need
to be quite so melodramatic.
You're not playing Sidney Carton.
So why have you come here
if he has done everything
you asked of him?
Because he hasn't.
He wouldn't give me any money.
If I had, how could I prevent
his returning to Downton
once it was spent?
My dear Mr. Grigg...
Oh, it's nice to see
someone's got some manners.
Hold your tongue!
I'll tell you what
is going to happen.
When I have given you £20, you
will leave Downton immediately
and we will never
set eyes on you again.
I'll have to see about that.
If you return to this area,
I will personally ensure your
conviction for theft and blackmail.
- Just a minute.
- You will serve from five to 10 years
in His Majesty's custody.
You think you're such
a big man, don't you?
Just cos you're a lord, you think
you can do what you like with me.
I think it...
... because it is true.
You'll not always be
in charge, you know!
The day is coming when your
lot will have to tow the line
- just like the rest of us!
- Perhaps.
But happily for Carson,
that day has not come yet.
I... take it my resignation
has not been accepted.
My dear fellow, we all have chapters
we would rather keep unpublished.
To be honest, Carson...
... I'm rather impressed.
Did you really sing and
dance in front of an audience?
I did.
And do you ever miss it?
Not in the least, my lord.
Poor Mr. Carson.
We'll have to treat him like a
god for a month to calm his nerves.
He'll be afraid this will
change the way we think of him.
- Then we mustn't let it.
- Oh, but it will.
The Cheerful Charlies?!
For all his talk of dignity,
we know his story now.
- And admire him more because of it.
- Maybe.
But it will change the way we
think of him. It always does.
I don't see why.
I shouldn't care what
I found out about you,
whatever it was.
It wouldn't alter
my opinion one bit.
But it would. It certainly would.
We're running out of options!
The lawyers I write
to only huff and puff.
They echo Murray and
say nothing can be done.
Or they don't want the
bother of opposing him.
Precisely.
I wish Mary wasn't so confident
it could all be put right.
Meanwhile, we have to watch
that dreadful woman
parade around the village
as if she owned it.
- I think she means well.
- Meaning well is not enough.
Poor Dr. Clarkson.
What has he done to
deserve that termagant?
I think he's in for an
uncomfortable afternoon.
Really? Why?
On my way here, I saw
her go into the hospital.
She looked extremely determined.
Not as determined as I am.
I have the adrenalin
here in my hand.
Will you really deny the
man his chance of life?
I just wish it was a treatment
I was more familiar with.
Will that serve as your
excuse when he dies?
Nurse!
Will you prepare Mr. Drake
for his procedure, please?
Well, Mrs. Crawley,
I have a feeling
we will sink or swim together.
Mr. Drake, your heart
is not functioning properly.
And as a result, the
pericardial sac is full of fluid.
I am proposing first
to withdraw the fluid
and then to inject the adrenalin
to stimulate the heart and
restore normal activity.
Is it dangerous, Doctor?
The draining may stop the heart.
And the adrenalin may
not be able to restart it.
Mrs. Drake, the choice is simple.
If your husband endures
this procedure, he may life.
If not, he will die.
- He's with a patient.
- No, let me pass!
I must see the doctor...at once!
Your ladyship.
It is just as I thought.
Doctor Clarkson,
tell me you will not
permit this amateur
to influence your
professional opinion.
- Amateur?
- My dear woman,
do not let them bully you.
They'll not disturb the peace
of your husband's last hours
if I can help it.
But that's just it, my lady.
I don't want them
to be his last hours.
Not if there's a chance.
Please, Doctor,
do what you must.
As...
Steady.
Yep, alright.
Nice and steady.
As President of this hospital,
I feel I must...
Valve.
..tell you...
... I shall bring this to
the attention of the board.
You're doing very well.
Have you no pity?
Adrenalin.
Quickly, quickly.
His heart's stopped.
Ready?
Yes.
Oh, John!
My dear.
You don't have to worry...
she may be President,
but I am the Patron
so you're quite safe with me.
Please.
My mother was right, then.
The man's life was saved.
Well, I like to think
we were both right.
But I'm not sure Lady Grantham
will be so easily convinced.
Then we must
strengthen the argument.
Cousin Isobel wants
something to do? Very well.
Let's make her
Chairman of the Board.
- She'd like that, wouldn't she?
- Certainly she would.
Then my mother will
have to listen to her.
She's been an absolute
ruler there for long enough.
It's time for some loyal opposition.
Well, if you're quite
certain, my lord.
What were you going to say?
Well, at the risk
of being impertinent,
on your own head be it.
About your scheme for
restoring the estate cottages.
You don't mind my interfering?
My dear fellow,
I brought you here to interfere.
In fact, why don't you stay for
dinner and we'll talk about it?
We'll send down to
Molesley for your clothes.
I better not.
My mother's expecting me.
In fact, I've been meaning to
speak to you about Molesley.
Would you find me very ungrateful
if I dispensed with his services?
Why? Has he displeased you
in some way?
Not at all. It's simply that he's
superfluous to our style of living.
Is that quite fair?
To deprive a man of his livelihood
when he's done nothing wrong?
- Well, I wouldn't quite put it...
- Your mother derives satisfaction
from her work at the hospital, I
think, some sense of self-worth?
- Well, certainly.
- Would you really
deny the same to poor old Molesley?
And when you are master here, is the
butler to be dismissed, or the footman?
How many maids or kitchen
staff will be allowed to stay?
Or must every one be driven out?
We all have different
parts to play, Matthew.
And we must all be
allowed to play them.
Why must we all go to the hospital?
I'm afraid Papa wants
to teach Granny a lesson.
Poor Granny. A month ago,
these people were strangers.
Now she must share power with the
mother and I must marry the son.
You won't marry him
though, will you?
What, marry a sea monster?
We shouldn't laugh.
That's so unkind.
But he must marry someone.
Edith, what are you thinking?
You know, I don't dislike
him as much as you do.
Perhaps you don't
dislike him at all.
Perhaps I don't.
Well, it's nothing to me.
I've bigger fish to fry.
What fish? Are we talking about E-N?
How do you know that? Have you
been poking around in my things?
Of course not. Come on.
Who is he? It's not
fair if you both know.
You won't be any the wiser,
but his name is Evelyn Napier.
The Honourable Evelyn Napier.
Son and heir to Viscount Branksome.
Who wants an old sea monster
when they can have Perseus?
If you're going to the ceremony,
I thought we might walk together.
Certainly I'm going.
I want to see the old bat's
face when they announce it.
I must try not to
look too cheerful.
Or shouldn't I talk like
that in your presence?
Do you find me very ridiculous,
Mrs. Hughes?
Putting on airs and
graces I've no right to?
What's brought this on?
Nothing.
Except at times I wonder
if I'm just a sad old fool.
Mr. Carson,
you are a man of
integrity and honour,
who raises the tone of this
household by being part of it.
So no more of that, please.
Come on! We mustn't be late!
I wondered if you'd like
to walk with me down to...
Is Thomas going?
Well, I think everyone is.
Sorry, what were you saying?
Nothing. Doesn't matter.
Put this away before you go.
- And never mind your flirting!
- I wasn't flirting. Not with him.
William's not a bad lad.
He's nice enough,
but he isn't like Thomas.
No, he's not.
Cuff links, sir?
Those are a dull option
for such an occasion.
Don't you agree?
Might I suggest the
crested pair, sir?
They seem more appropriate,
if you don't mind me saying.
They're a bit fiddly. I
wonder if you could help me.
Certainly, sir.
Oh, I see you got that mark out
of the sleeve. How did you do it?
I tried it with this and tried
it with that until it yielded.
Very well done.
Thank you, sir.
You go in, Mrs. Hughes. I want
a quick word with Mr. Bates here.
Mr. Bates.
I must thank you,
both for what you did
and for keeping silent afterwards.
It was kind of you, and Anna.
It was nothing, Mr. Carson.
Well, I hope you don't
judge me too harshly.
I don't judge you at all. I have
no right to judge you, or any man.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to this happy event..
the investiture of our first
Chairwoman, Mrs. Reginald Crawley,
who has graciously agreed to share
the duties of our beloved President,
the Dowager Countess of Grantham.
Our little hospital must
surely grow and thrive
with two such doughty
champions united as they are
by the strongest ties of
all... family and friendship.
Lady Mary Crawley, I presume.
Mary has more suitors tonight
than the Princess Aurora.
Is that one mine?
I hope the day's living
up to your expectations.
Exceeding them in every way.
itfc subtitles
www.tvsubtitles.net