Hurry up, girls. Come on.
Come on, come on! You
should be done here!
They'll be back from the
station any second now!
I haven't had a chance
to ask. How was London?
Oh, much as usual.
Dirty, noisy. Quite enjoyable.
There was no need for you
to come back a day early.
I'm perfectly capable of getting
the house ready.
Of course you are. But I'd like
to have the heavy luggage back and
unpacked before they get here.
I suppose... Steady, William!
This isn't a race.
- Poor lad.
- But he did see her?
I was worried when I
took him to King's Cross.
Yes, he had time to say goodbye.
How is he now?
Well, you've only got
one mother, haven't you?
They're here, Mrs. Hughes!
Hello, William. It's
good to have you back.
What a relief to be home.
Don't listen when His Lordship
pretends not to enjoy the season!
When in Rome...
Will Lady Mary be back soon?
She's staying on with my sister
for a couple of weeks.
So Grantham House is closed?
It will be by the end of this week.
Dear Mrs. Hughes,
I hope you've had some time to
yourself while we've been away.
I've tackled a few jobs that get
forgotten when the house is full.
- Any local news?
- The main topic here
is the murder of the Austrian
Archduke.
Here and everywhere else.
I'm afraid we haven't
heard the last of that.
- How's William?
- Bearing up.
Poor chap. He has our sympathies.
I think I'll wash the
train off before dinner.
Very good, my lord. I can
unpack while you're bathing.
I'll see you up there.
Mrs. Hughes, have you thought about
the garden party for the hospital?
I've started on it, but there
are things we need to talk about.
Oh, dear. That sounds like trouble.
I'll take my hat off.
Sybil?
You were a great success in
London, darling. Well done.
- You never say that to me.
- Don't I?
You were very helpful, dear.
Thank you.
I hate to spoil
Her Ladyship's homecoming,
but what are we going
to do about Mrs. Patmore?
She's worse than when
you left. Much worse.
And I meant to ask,
is there a decision
about Mr. Bates leaving?
Not yet. His Lordship
wants the facts
and Mr. Bates won't give them.
So what are you going to say to
Her Ladyship about Mrs. Patmore?
I'm not sure. I don't want
the poor woman sacked, but...
things cannot go on as they are.
There's nothing like an English
summer, is there?
Except an English winter.
I'm sorry you haven't
received more invitations.
But then, after
four seasons, one is
less a debutante than a survivor.
My dear, is there anything
you're not telling me?
- No.
- Only, one hears stories.
There's nothing, Aunt Rosamund.
So, have you decided...
whether or not to
marry Cousin Matthew?
There's no secret Cora can
keep for more than a month.
You'd be surprised.
I've told him I'll give him
my answer the day I get back.
Well, it would be very tidy.
At least we can say that.
- Fancy a smoke?
- Don't mind if I do.
There they go... Guy
Fawkes and his assistant.
- Which is which?
- Here you are.
Surely, if His Lordship
hasn't done anything until now,
it means he doesn't want
to take it any further.
Anna's made me an armband,
Mr. Carson.
For my mother. Can I wear it?
I daresay. Not when
we're entertaining,
but otherwise...
Hello, Doctor. I didn't
know you were here.
No. Lady Grantham sent a message.
- Why? She's not ill, is she?
- Not... ill, exatly.
Would you mind waiting
in the library?
Pregnant?
You needn't be quite so shocked.
Give me a moment.
You haven't been
pregnant for 18 years!
And I'm pregnant now!
I don't understand what
we've done differently.
Stop right there! If you want to know
more, go and offer the doctor some whisky.
I can't take it in.
But...you're pleased?
Of course...
Of course I'm pleased.
I didn't think she'd do it.
I told you she would.
I could see she was interested.
I was speaking as one lady's maid
to another. That means something!
Course, we thought we had him
before but he's a slippery devil.
It's unusual, obviously.
Unusual? It's Biblical!
Not quite.
You understand that women go
through a...certain change.
Thank you. I know quite as much
as I need to about all that.
Well, sometimes it can result in
a surge of...
fertility, for want
of a better word.
- But the child will be healthy?
- There's no reason why not.
How long has she...?
Hard to be precise. Things
had become irregular, but...
- Please...
- I'd say she's about four months gone.
It'll begin to show soon.
And I don't suppose there's any
way of knowing... if it's a...
I do beg your pardon, my lord.
I thought you were alone.
Please come in, Mrs. Hughes.
- I'm just leaving.
- William?
Well, thank you, Doctor.
- I'd better write some letters.
- Show Dr. Clarkson out.
I didn't want to bother Her
Ladyship if she's not well...
She's resting, but tell me anyway.
It's Mrs. Patmore, my lord.
The time has come when we
really have to make a decision.
- Now do you believe me?
- Careful, Thomas.
Your position is not a strong one.
Don't punish us, Mr. Carson.
It's Mr. Bates who's wanting here.
Tell me, Mr. Carson, do you think it right
a man like that should
live and work at Downton?
Mr. Napier, my lady.
What a surprise!
I'm afraid you've
just missed my aunt.
I know.
I watched her leave.
How are your wedding plans going?
Not very well.
In fact, we've
decided to call it off.
Really?
It seemed quite
fixed at Sybil's ball.
What a shame... Please.
- It'll be better in the long run.
- Perhaps.
I know what high hopes you
have of the institution.
The thing is, Lady Mary, I...
I'm here today because I needed
to tell you something face to face,
before you went to the country.
Face to face? Gracious me.
I've recently heard
gossip about the time
when I came to Downton
with Kemal Pamuk,
gossip that I believe has
made life difficult for you.
I've also heard it said that
I am the source of these stories.
It is very important to me that
you should know that I am not.
From that day to this, I have
never spoken one word on the matter.
Then who did?
It seems to have come from the
Turkish Embassy,
from the Ambassador himself,
in fact, and his wife.
But who told them, if not you?
This is the hard part.
When I discovered the answer, I
debated whether I should relay it,
but in the end, I
feel you ought to know.
The suspense is killing me.
It was your sister, Lady Edith,
who wrote to the Ambassador.
That is why people
accept the story.
Edith?
It's very hard to believe.
Harder for you than for me.
I love the thought of a baby in
the house, but if it's a boy...
It'll be very hard on Mr. Crawley.
I know. I was no great
champion when he first arrived.
But it seems to me he's tried his
best and he's done the decent thing.
I can't see that coming off.
You don't mean the engagement?
But it's not an engagement yet,
is it?
She'd never throw him over!
Mr. Carson, Lady Mary Crawley does
not deserve you.
And she is not been in
touch with cousin Matthew?
Not that I heared.
Wonderful news, of course.
You must look after yourself.
Don't worry. O'Brien has me
wrapped in silk and feathers.
You're lucky.
I have a horrible feeling
Simmons is about to
hand in her notice.
She's looking very fidgety lately,
and I saw her hurrying
to meet the postman.
Oh, you poor thing.
Is there anything worse
than losing one's maid?
Why would she want to leave me?
I've been as gentle as a lamb.
Most of the time.
I want to say I'll
make provision for you
if it's a boy and
you get pushed out.
Don't worry. I know you can't.
If any man living understands the
strength of the entail, it's me.
I can give you Crawley House
for life, if it's a help.
- Have you heard from Mary?
- No. Have you?
By the way, I want to ask a favour.
What's the name of your cook,
the one you brought
with you from Manchester?
Mrs. Bird?
- I'll get it, Mrs. Patmore!
- Don't fuss me!
- Is that everything?
- Yeah.
How are you feeling?
Well, most people's
parents die before them,
- and so they should.
- Oh, give it a rest.
Your mother knew how to drag
it out. I'll say that for her.
- What?
- Thomas!
Get up to the servery.
- You gave me the wrong cloth!
- Sit down, Mrs. Patmore.
I can't when I've got
the luncheon to finish!
It was not a suggestion. Sit!
Daisy and I will finish
the luncheon.
So he'll give us this house
for life, will he? How generous!
It is generous. He doesn't have to.
But it's made me think.
You must stay here if you want.
But I wonder if it
mightn't be better all round
if I went back to Manchester.
It may not be a boy.
Oh, really, Mother! You never
approved of it all in first place!
If it is a boy,
you should see it as a release,
not a disappointment.
What does Mary say?
Nothing yet.
You wanted to see Mrs. Bird, sir.
Yes. Mrs. Bird, Lord Grantham
has rather a favour to ask of you.
I'm surprised Lord Grantham
knows that I exist, sir.
- I'm sorry to disturb you.
- Quite all right.
Mr. Bates, it's about your
somewhat startling confession.
As you'll have surmised, His
Lordship has yet to make a decision.
His delay is generous.
However, it will be
no surprise to you
that Miss O'Brien has been
unwilling to let things drop.
It seems that when we were in
London, she made a new friend...
a lady's maid in the house of a
colonel in your former regiment.
Please tell me that this account
is false, at least in part.
I wish I could.
I'll have to show this
to His Lordship.
Of course you will. I do not like
to play the part of Pontius Pilate,
Eu não gosto de fazer o
papel de Pontius Pilate,
but I'm afraid I must.
Lord Grantham will decide
what's to be done.
Mr. Bates,
I hope you do not feel
that I treated you unjustly.
On the contrary, Mr. Carson,
I am astonished at your kindness.
Of all of you,
Sybil might find joy in a cottage,
but not you.
- We don't know it'll be a boy.
- Exatly.
So ask Matthew to wait
until the child is born.
If it's a girl, you
can wed him happily
and all will be as it was before.
But if I delay, won't he think I'm
only after him for his position?
Besides, I'm not sure
I want to put him off,
even without the title.
We get on so well, you know.
And he's terribly clever.
He might end up Lord Chancellor.
And he might not.
Oh, come along, Mary, be sensible.
Can you really see yourself
dawdling your life away
as the wife of a country solicitor?
But why would we ever want a
telephone at Downton, my lord?
Well, they have their uses.
You could speak to the housekeeper
in London.
That'd be helpful, surely?
I hope I have not failed in my
management of the recent move?
Not at all. But the
telephone is here now,
and the girls got used to
it when we were in London.
Besides, none of us know what
the next few months will bring.
Because of the Archduke's death?
Austria won't get what
it wants from Serbia.
And now Russia's
starting to rumble.
Well, there's not much
we can do about that.
So, will you take care
of the telephone man?
Oh, about Mr. Bates, my lord.
I expect you've had time to
consider the contents of that letter?
Yes. But I find it very odd.
Regimental silver?
I could more easily
see Bates as an assassin
- than a petty pilferer.
- I agree.
And while the letter
is hard to argue with,
I wouldn't put anything
past Thomas or Miss O'Brien.
- So, what did we miss?
- Nothing much.
Although you'd have had
more invitations than I did.
- Have you thought about Matthew?
- Of course.
- But Aunt Rosamund says...
- No!
She's written to
me. Pay no attention.
But Granny, she has got a point.
Mary can't be completely naive.
- I don't need your help, thank you.
- Mary, listen to me.
If you take Matthew now,
when his whole future is at risk,
he will love you to
the end of his days.
Why, Granny, you're a romantic!
I've been called many things,
but never that.
And what happens if
the baby is a boy?
- And Matthew loses everything?
- Mary can always change her mind.
I can't do that to Matthew.
It's not how we are together.
I'm going upstairs
to help Anna unpack.
I'll come with you.
Edith, why don't you go too?
Sir Anthony Strallan
was at Lady Wren's party.
He asked after you.
Is she really serious about him?
Any port in a storm...
By the way, I must
right about my maid.
She's leaving, to get married.
- How could she be so selfish?
- I do sympathise.
Robert's always wanted me to get
rid of O'Brien, but I can't face it.
Anyway, she's so fond of me.
Well, I thought
Simmons was fond of ME!
What am I to do?
I'll put an
advertisement in The Lady.
It's always the
best place to start.
That's so kind. Thank you.
I really must be going.
Now, don't let Mary wait for
the baby
before she gives
Matthew her answer.
I'm sure it's another girl.
I know those men of
the moral high ground.
If she won't say yes
when he might be poor,
he won't want her
when he will be rich.
Maybe we should knit something.
Oh, yes, I'm sure
they'd love a pair
of bootees knitted by you.
- Or what about a Christening mug?
- They can buy their own silver.
- Anything in the paper?
- They've arrested Princip and his gang.
All Serbian and members
of the Black Hand.
The Black Hand? I don't like
the sound of that.
I don't like the
sound of any of it.
- War is on the way.
- Then we'll have to face it...
- as bravely as we can.
- Thank you, Mr. Cannon Fodder.
Don't YOU think a war's coming?
Oh, there'll be a war,
and it's time to prepare for it.
- The country, do you mean?
- No. Me.
You never disappoint.
Daisy, run and find Mrs. Patmore.
His Lordship wants to see her
in the library.
His Lordship wants Mrs.
Patmore to go up to the library?
That is what I said.
And Anna, you're to come too.
And we thought the assassination
of an archduke was a surprise.
Mrs. Patmore, my lord.
Your Lordship, I know things
haven't been quite right for a while,
- but I can assure you...
- Come in, Mrs. Patmore.
I promise you, my lord,
if I could just be
allowed a bit more time...
Mrs. Patmore, I have not asked
you here to give you your notice.
- Haven't you?
- No.
I understand you've had
some trouble with your sight.
That's just it!
- I know I could manage better if...
- Please, Mrs. Patmore!
Let him speak!
- Beg pardon, my lord.
- Don't apologise.
Now, on Dr. Clarkson's
recommendation,
I'm sending you up to London to see
an eye specialist at Moorfields.
Anna will go with you and you'll
stay with my sister Rosamund
in her new house
in Belgrave Square.
I'm afraid I'm going to have to
sit in your presence, my lord.
Of course.
But how will you get on here?
Well,
Mrs. Crawley is lending
us her cook... Mrs. Bird.
She's coming over tomorrow.
You will be good enough to
show her how things work.
Are the Crawleys to
starve while I'm away?
They'll eat here every evening.
Now, my sister's butler
will look after you.
He's very nice.
Anna, you won't mind
a visit to London?
No, my lord. Thank you.
It'll be an adventure.
One with a happy ending, I hope.
Let me get this clear.
At Sybil's ball you said
you'd give me your answer
the day you got back,
- and now you say you will not!
- Why do we have to rush into it?
- I need to be sure, that's all.
- But you WERE sure.
Should I tell I think altered you.
My prospects!
- Because nothing else has changed!
- No!
Yes!
If your mother's child is a boy,
then he's the heir
and I go back to living on my wits!
And you rather not follow me.
Oh, Mathew! You always make
everything so black and white!
I think this IS black and white!
Do you love me enough to
spend your life with me?
If not, then say no.
- If you do, then say yes.
- I want to...
Granny told me I
should say yes now,
then withdraw if
you lost everything.
To make that work, you'd
have to be a good liar.
Are you a good liar?
Not good enough to try, apparently.
How could you not have realised
they'd discover the loss at once?
And to keep them in your house...
- But you only served two years?
- That's right, my lord.
So, clearly the judge thought
there was some mitigating fator.
I just want to know the truth.
I cannot speak of it, my lord.
You must decide whether I stay or go
on the basis of the
evidence before you.
I will respect that.
I'm sorry.
I don't believe it.
How can you say that?
When I've confessed to the crime?
Well, His Lordship obviously doesn't
think that's all there is to it,
and I don't either.
Anna, are you set for the
nine o'clock train tomorrow?
All packed and ready.
You'll be met at King's Cross
by Lady Rosamund's chauffeur,
which I think is generous, but
after that, you're on your own.
Right. I must get on. I'm acting
referee for Mrs. Patmore and Mrs. Bird.
Best of luck.
Will you miss me?
Try not to miss me.
It'll be good practice.
I expect it'll be hard
adjusting to this kitchen,
after the one you're
used to. Not to worry.
I'm sure I can have it
cleaned up in no time.
- Cleaned up?
- I'm not criticising.
With your eyesight, it's a wonder
you could see the pots at all.
- You'll have met Daisy and the others?
- I have.
Though what they all find
to do is a mystery to me.
Are you not used to
managing staff, Mrs. Bird?
I'm used to getting it done with
one kitchen maid, Mrs. Patmore,
but I suppose, in
a house like this,
you expect to take it easy.
Do you think we should erect a ring
and let them fight it out?
She's all right, Mrs. Bird.
She's more of a
general than a trooper,
but you need that in a cook.
Mrs. Patmore's the Generalissimo.
Well, I'm very sad.
I thought Mary was
made of better stuff.
Don't speak against her.
Of course, she's taken advice from
someone with false
and greedy values.
- Mother!
- And we don't have to go too far
- to know who that is!
- Mother!
- I've a good mind...
- You do not go near Cousin Violet.
That is an order.
- Something's not right about it.
- I agree.
Having a silver thief in the house
does not seem right at all,
even if he COULD walk.
But Carson isn't keen
to get rid of him either,
and he normally comes down on
this sort of thing very hard.
- What's his reasoning?
- He blames Thomas and O'Brien.
He says they've been working against
Bates since he got here.
So I should sack O'Brien instead?
You'll hear no argument from me.
This should do the trick, my lady.
Ten years of my life.
That's what I've given her.
- Ten bloody years!
- But did she say she'd sack you?
- It's obviously what he wants.
- So when will they tell you?
When they've found a replacement.
Heaven forefend she should have
to put a comb through her own hair!
- And if I'm going, you won't be far behind.
- Oh, so what? Sod 'em.
There's a war coming
and war means change.
- We should be making plans.
- What are you talking about?
Well, put it like this. I don't
want to be a footman any more,
but I don't intend to be
killed in battle neither.
I'm not saying poison them!
Just make sure they don't find
her food all that agreeable.
- By poisoning it?
- Will you stop that?
You don't want it to taste nice.
I want them to be glad
when I get back, that's all.
At this will be for the family and
the one in my pantry for the
staff or more precisely... me.
We don't know if
we can provide two.
Then perhaps we should
find another supplier.
Oh, all ge...
Right, where the seat
of the other telephone.
Yeah. In the out of hall.
- Good afternoon, Carson. Is Lady Edith in?
- I am!
I most certainly am!
- I was just driving past.
- Yes?
I thought you might
like to come for a spin.
If you're not too busy.
Wait till I get my coat.
Is it all right if
I make some notes?
- I'm so sorry, Mr...?
- This is Mr. Bromidge, my lady.
He's here about the telephone.
Oh, please make your notes,
dear Mr. Bromidge.
We're so looking forward to it.
What an exciting business to be in!
- You must be expanding every day.
- Oh, we are, sir.
But that brings its problems.
Training up men for the work,
when many have no aptitude.
I can't even find a secretary
who can keep pace at the moment.
- What?
- It's hard with a new concept.
Too old, and they can't change.
Too young, and
they've no experience.
Have you filled the post yet?
Because I know just the woman.
Well, she must hurry up. We'll
close the list tomorrow night.
You'll have her
application. I promise.
- This isn't bad at all, is it?
- I don't know.
No-one told me
there'd be an actual operation.
What did you think?
They were just going to make
magic passes over your eyes?
All right, Mrs...Patmore?
She'll be fine. Thank you.
And you've been sent to
us by the Earl of Grantham?
That's right.
Very good.
You can leave now.
We'll keep her in for a week.
You can collect her next Friday.
- I'll be in to visit every day.
- What about the rest of the time?
Don't worry!
You'll be fine.
- Bates, you say?
- John Bates.
He must have left the
army about eight years ago.
Wait here, please.
- Have you finished the soup?
- I think so, Mrs. Bird.
- And the sauce for the fish?
- Yes, Mrs. Bird.
You can put them in the warmer.
You don't mean John Bates,
who went to prison for theft?
That's correct.
Well, I know who
he is right enough.
That was an odd business.
Why odd?
Never mind.
So you're his cousin and
you'd like to be in touch?
Very forgiving.
I've got no address
for him or his wife.
But I have got one for his mother,
which should still be good.
I've written it down for you.
Thank you for your trouble.
Is it true you wrote to the
Turkish Ambassador about Kemal?
- Who told you?
- Someone who knows that you did.
Then why are you asking?
Because I wanted to give you one
last chance to deny it.
And what if I did?
He had a right to know
how his countryman died.
In the arms of a slut.
How's that advertisement
getting on for new maid?
Well, it's only just come out.
William and I can manage here now.
Tell Mrs. Bird we'll have
our dinner in 20 minutes.
Carson, be sure to say to Mrs. Bird
the dinner was really delicious.
- So, how was the drive?
- It was lovely.
Only...
Yes?
Well,
he said he had a question for me.
He told me he'd ask
it at the garden party
and he hoped I'd say yes.
You must think very carefully
what your answer will be.
Yes, I should think very
carefully about a lot of things.
- Do your neighbours have one?
- Yes, they do in London, anyway.
It seems wise to
get a telephone now.
If there is a war, it may be hard
to have one installed in a house.
Let me show you where
we're going to put it.
First electricity now telephones.
Sometimes I feel as if I were
living in an HG Wells novel.
But the young are all so calm
about change, aren't they?
Look at Matthew.
I do admire him.
Do you?
- What have I done wrong now?
- Oh, please.
Don't pretend Mary's
sudden reluctance
can't be traced back to you.
Well, I shall pretend it.
I told her to take him.
Your quarrel is with my daughter
Rosamund, not me.
So put that in your
pipe and smoke it!
Mr. Molesley.
- What are you after?
- I want a word with Mr. Carson.
I'm here to have my dinner.
- You don't want much, do you?
- What are you doing?
Mr. Carson dropped his
wallet in the passage.
I was replacing it.
But everything seemed so settled
between you at Sybil's ball.
Things have changed since then.
Not necessarily.
I don't seem to be much
good at making boys.
Any more than I'm
much good at building
my life on shifting sands.
You do know I should be very
proud to have you as my son-in-law,
whatever your prospects?
Unfortunately, sir,
your daughter is more
practical than you.
- Will you join us, Mrs. Bird?
- I don't mind if I do.
I'm not sure Mrs. Patmore
would like that, Mr. Carson.
Cook always eats separate,
that's what she says.
Not in our house.
There's only four of us.
Well, you're going any minute. She's
advertised for your replacement.
That filthy, ungrateful cow.
Let the kitchen maids
have theirs on their own.
You stay with us.
Her Ladyship said to tell you
that the dinner was delicious.
- She can't have!
- Daisy? Does that surprise you?
What have you done with
this, you little beggar?
I knew it! That's why I
said it was for upstairs.
Come on! Tell us what's in it!
Just... water and a bit of soap.
And you've put something
in the fish sauce as well?
Only... mustard and aniseed.
Why, Daisy? Why would
you do such a thing?
Mrs. Patmore was worried they'd
prefer Mrs. Bird's cooking
and they wouldn't
want her to come back.
Is that likely?
When they've taken such
trouble to get her well?
I'm sorry!
There, there.
There are worse crimes on earth
than loyalty.
Dry your eyes,
and fetch the beef stew
I was making for tomorrow.
You've not had a chance
to spoil that, I suppose?
I was going to mix in
some syrup of figs,
but I've not done it yet.
At least we'd all
have been regular.
Carson said you were here.
Just checking that everything's
being done right, my lady.
Only, we never heard back.
That is, Miss Dawson
never heard back from you,
about an interview.
Yes, we got the
young lady's letter.
But the trouble is,
she didn't have any
experience of hard work.
But she's a very hard worker!
I couldn't find any proof of it.
And she gave you as a reference,
when you don't run
a business, my Lady.
Well, not that I'm aware of.
Lily? Can you find Gwen and
tell her to come to the hall now?
Yes, my lady.
The reason Gwen didn't
give any more details
is because she works
here, as a housemaid.
And you thought that'd put me off?
But she's taken a postal course
and has good speeds in typing
and Pitman shorthand. Test her!
I will, if I like the look of her.
So, young lady.
You thought I'd turn up
my nose at a housemaid?
- Well, I did, sir.
- Well,
my mother was a housemaid.
I've got nothing
against housemaids.
They know about hard work and
long hour, that's for sure.
I believe so, sir.
Right, well, is there somewhere
we could talk?
Gwen, take Mr. Bromidge to the
library.
I'll see no-one disturbs you.
Sorry, Papa, you can't go in there.
Why on earth not?
Gwen's in there with Mr. Bromidge.
She's being interviewed.
I cannot use my library
because one of the housemaids is
in there applying for another job?
That's about the size of it.
So, what is it you want to know?
I want to know the truth about
the case against him.
I want to know why the officer
thought it was "odd".
I want to know what Mr. Bates isn't
saying.
Because you don't
believe him to be guilty?
No, I don't.
I know he's not.
Well...
You're right, of course.
Then who was it?
Who was the thief?
His wife. Vera.
Who do you call? No-one
you know has got one!
But they will have. You'll see.
Might I enquire why my pantry
has become a common room?
Sorry, Mr. Carson.
But...do you know how it works?
- Of course I do.
- Could you show us?
Certainly not.
A telephone is not a toy,
but a useful and valuable tool.
Now, get back to your work.
She worked at the
barracks sometimes,
helping at big dinners and so on.
That night her opportunity
came and she took it.
They knew it was her.
Someone even saw her
with a big carryall.
But why did he confess?
Well...
John wasn't the same man in those
days.
The African war had shaken
him up and made him angry.
He'd been wounded
and he drunk a lot more
than was good for him.
- Was he violent?
- No. No, not violent.
He could hard at times,
with a tongue like a razor.
He felt he'd ruined Vera's life,
Miss Smith.
- Do you agree with him?
- No.
I thought she was a
nasty piece of work.
That's why he took the blame.
Surely, if everyone knew
- he was innocent...
- But he confessed!
There was nothing
anybody could do once
he'd confessed.
Could I ask you something, sir?
Only, I get the feeling
that a war's on the way.
I'm afraid we all do.
And when it comes, I want to be
really useful to my country.
- How heartening.
- So I've been thinking,
what could be more
useful than what you do?
Bringing people back
to health, back to life.
I see.
Well, erm, we are
looking for volunteers
to train for the
Territorial Force hospitals,
- if that's what you mean.
- It's exatly what I mean.
- Will you not be missed here?
- Maybe. But we'll all be going, won't we?
The younger men, anyway.
As you wish. I'll make enquiries.
Thank you very much, Doctor.
Mr. Molesley walked in and there
he was, as bold as brass,
taking my wallet
out of my change coat.
Mr. Molesley would have no
reason to make it up, my lord.
He doesn't know Thomas.
Why would he lie?
So Thomas has been
caught red-handed.
Well, we knew he was a thief.
And now we have unimpeachable proof.
I'm afraid he has to go.
I hate this sort of thing,
with Lady Grantham's
condition and everyrhing.
Can we at least wait
until after the garden party?
Very well, my lord. But
then I think we must act.
How long will you wear them?
A week or so.
But I can see much better
already, even with them on.
Thanks heaven.
Now, we need to talk
about the garden party.
Mrs. Bird and I
have made some lists.
Mrs. Bird?
I think we can manage without
any help from Mrs. Bird.
Can you?
Well, if you want your garden party to be
run by Blind Pugh, that's your business.
Mrs. Patmore, there's a lot to be done
and you're only just up on your feet.
We really cannot manage
without Mrs. Bird.
If you say so.
Now, I've been checking the stores
and I've ordered what
you'll need for the baking.
That's very kind, Mrs. Hughes, but
I believe WE should
check the stores,
when it's convenient.
Mrs. Bird, at Downton Abbey,
the housekeeper manages
the store cupboard, but...
I've never not run my own
store cupboard in my life.
Separate the cook from
the store cupboard?
Where's the sense in that?
How long have I been
saying this, oh, Lord?
We're the ones who cook it.
We should be the ones to order it.
Mrs. Bird, I shall be very glad
of your help with the garden party.
I'm sure we can manage it easily...
between the two of us.
Hello?
This is Downton Abbey.
Carson the butler speaking.
Hello.
This is Mr. Carson, the
butler, of Downton Abbey.
To whom am I speaking?
But I'm not shouting!
Who are YOU?
Mrs. Gaunt.
No, I don't want to place a call.
I was practising my answer.
Well, I daresay a lot of the things
you do sound stupid to other people!
I've written to your mother.
She's very anxious, naturally.
- She suggested coming over.
- Oh, God.
Well, that's what I thought.
So I put her off. Told her
to come and admire the baby.
- I'll just run Your Ladyship's bath.
- Thank you, O'Brien.
- Have you had any answers about the position?
- Quite a few.
So what did they sound like?
One I think has real possibilities.
She learned to do hair in Paris
while working for the Ambassadress.
Sounds promising.
- Carson, I've been meaning...
- Your Lordship?
- Anna, you're back safely, then?
- Yes, thank you, my lord.
And Mrs. Patmore's
fighting fit again.
"Fighting fit" is the phrase!
Is something the matter?
I wanted to see Your
Lordship because...
Please.
While I was in London, I learned
something about Mr. Bates.
- Not bad, I hope.
- No. Not bad at all.
I'd have told Mr. Carson, but
I thought you might like
to hear it from me first.
Go on.
I went to call on
Mr. Bates's mother.
O'Brien,
how long do you think it takes
a lady's maid to settle in?
Depends on the maid, my lady.
Of course it does.
Sorry.
The other half's under the bath.
Never mind. Thank you.
I'll just go and sort
out your clothes, my lady.
Thank you.
Sarah O'Brien, this
is not who you are.
My lady, if you could just wait...
The doctor's gone, Your Lordship,
but he's coming back after dinner.
Lady Mary's with her now.
Thank you.
I don't suppose
you'll want to change.
But is there anything
else I can do to be useful?
It was a boy.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to embarrass you.
I'm not embarrassed.
I just wish
you could have been spared this.
I know you do.
Thank you.
By the way, Anna's told me what
she learned in London.
Has she?
She's not told me.
Well, the good news is
you won't be leaving Downton.
And I need some good news today.
That poor wee babe.
How's Her Ladyship doing?
I'll take her up
a tray in a minute,
but I dare say she won't touch
a bite.
What about you, Miss O'Brien?
What about me?
It must have been quite a shock.
Yes. Yes it was.
I think you'd better dine with us,
Mr. Branson.
We can't know
if you might be needed later.
Well, I'm to go for the doctor at ten.
What a long-faced lot!
Kindly show some respect.
Come on, Mr. Carson!
She'll get over it.
They're no
bigger than a hamster at that stage.
Will you shut up?
I agree. What is the matter
with you, Thomas?
I don't know. I suppose all
this makes me feel claustrophobic.
I'm sorry, of course I am,
but why must we live through them?
They're just our employers.
They're not our flesh and blood.
Thomas, don't be so unkind.
Is there nothing left on earth
that you respect?
OK.
Blimey, if he carries on
like this for the unborn baby
of a woman who scarcely knows
his name,
no wonder he fell to pieces
when his old mum snuffed it.
William!
Thomas! William! Parem!
Does it enough!
Come Here!
Calm down!
Thomas!
I've done as I promised.
General Burton is commanding
a division at Richmond.
I think I may have a place there
for you.
And Colonel Cartwright.
These are the papers.
When you're ready,
pop to the local recruiting office
and they'll take it from there.
As a matter of fact, I'm
being drafted back
in as a Captain. So...
- I'll try to keep an eye on you
- That's very kind of you, Doctor.
With any luck,
there may be some advantage
in your having volunteered so early.
Hang on a minute.
Now give me yours and take
this one at the same time.
William, I'm sorry I've been
unkind to you lately.
That's all right.
Not, it is not. I don't know
why I said those things.
You were under an evil spell.
I'm not under it now.
- I'm glad.
- Friends?
Always friends.
I think we should start
the ices now.
If you agree, Mrs. Patmore.
Certainly, Mrs. Bird.
My Lord! Listen to that!
It's like the cry of the banshee.
Mr. Carson's telephone's ringing.
Isn't someone going to answer it?
I wouldn't touch that thing
with a ten-foot pole.
Well, I will, then.
No, Mr. Carson's busy,
but can I take a message?
I wish I supose.
I've got news, milady.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Bromidge has rung!
You've done it, Gwen!
You've got the job!
You could take it? Take it!
Something to calebrate?
I've got the job, Mrs. Hughes!
I'm a secretary! I've begun!
I'm very happy for yoy, Gwen,
and we'll celebrate after
we've finished today's work.
Of course, Mrs. Hughes.
- I don't supose...
- Lady Sybil.
Her Ladyship was asking after you.
Be carreful, my lad.
Or you'll end up with no job
and a broken heart.
What do you mean?
I don't seem to be able to find
your sister.
I wonder where she is.
Of course
she may have been cornered.
I know there was some old bore
she was trying to dodge.
Who is that?
I'm not sure.
He's simply ghastly, apparently.
But he's promised to propose today.
I can't tell you how funny she was
when she acted it out.
She ought to go on the stage.
Really?
How amusing.
Well done. Mrs. Hughes.
Beautifully executed as always.
The key is in the planning.
Mr. Carson, probably
this isn't the moment,
but I've heard from Dr. Clarkson I've
been accepted for a training scheme
for the Army Medical Corps.
- Have you indeed?
- Yes, I know want to do it.
So I'll be handing in my notice.
I'll serve out the month, of course.
Thank you, Thomas.
We can talk abou it later.
And you couldn't have planned
that any better either.
You can't be leaving yet!
I'm afraid I must.
Please, make my excuses
to your mother.
But I...
I wish you'd come inside, milady.
No.
People mustn't think I'm really ill.
I don't want to cast a dampener
on the party.
Very well.
But are you sure you have
everything you need, milady?
Dear O'Brien.
How sweet you are.
O'Brien! O' Brien.
Can I have a word?
I need a favour and I don't want
to bother Lady Grantham with it.
Certainly, my Lady.
She's been
helping me find a new maid
and we've had quite a few answers
from her advertisement.
Can you find where she's put them, and get
Branson to bring them to the Dower House?
Her Ladyship was helping you find
a new lady's maid?
Yes.
We should have asked you, really.
You might take a look at the letters
if you have a minute.
There was one we liked the sound
of who'd been trained in Paris.
Do you know
where she might have put them?
The answers?
Yes, milady. There are only two
or three places they could be.
Thank you, O'Brien. You
are a treasure. Thank you.
I didn't know a garden party
was a spectator sport.
Pretty, though, isn't it?
Hard to believe the clouds
are gathering on a summer's day like this.
Mr. Bates,
I know you think I was
wrong to call on your mother...
I don't think that.
She likes you, by the way.
I had to find out the truth.
But, you see, you don't
know the whole truth.
Even now. You know
my mother's truth.
But not your wife's...
Where is she now?
I couldn't tell you.
I'd better get back.
Are you here, Mr. Molesley?
I didn't know that.
Just helping out.
Nice girl, that Anna.
Do you know if she's got anyone
special in her life?
I'd like to say she hasn't.
I would, truly.
But I'm afraid there is someone.
And do you think he's keen on her?
Or is it worth a go?
Well, he keeps himself to himself
and he's very hard
to read at times. But...
I'd say he's keen.
I'd say he was very keen, indeed.
Daisy!
I said ices not iced cakes.
Now, unclog your ears and get Mr.
William before they turn into soup.
But I don't understand.
Nothing's changed.
Everything's changed.
You can't be sure I
was going to refuse you,
even if it had been a boy,
because I'm not.
That's the point.
I can't be sure.
Of you or of anything, it seems.
The last few weeks
have taught me that.
But you can't leave Downton.
I can't stay.
Not now.
Well, what will you tell Papa?
That I'm grateful
for what he's trying to do.
But the experiment is at en end.
I'm not a puppet
and I must take charge
of my own life again.
Would you have stayed...
if I'd accepted you?
Of course.
So I've ruined everything.
You've shown me I've been living
in a dream.
And it's time to to return
to real life.
Wish me luck with it, Mary.
God knows I wish the best for you.
Well, Rosamund?
I'm afraid your
meddling has cost Mary
the only decent offer
she'll ever get.
I'm sorry mama, but you know me.
I have to say what I think.
Why?
Nobody else does.
Are you quite well, milady?
Of course.
You know me, Carson.
I'm never down for long.
I know you have spirit, milady.
And that's what counts.
It's all that counts, in the end.
There.
So Mary is to be denied her
Countess's coronet after all.
Don't crow at me.
I think she was very foolish
not to take him when she could.
I told her so.
If I'm perfectly honest,
I wonder if Mathew
isn't making the same
mistake right now.
Are you warm enough?
I am when you're holding my hand.
Your Lordship,
this has just arrived for you.
Thank you.
I'm happy to tell you
that Thomas
has just handed in his notice.
So we'll be spared any unpleasantness
on that score.
What a relief.
Please! Will you stop, please?
My lords, ladies and gentlemen,
can I ask for silence?
Because I very much regret
to announce...
... that we are at
war with Germany.
ITFC Subtitles
www.tvsubtitles.net