- When does it open?
- Tomorrow afternoon.
Well, let's get up a party, in the
evening. If Mrs. Hughes lets us.
- After we've had our dinner.
- You're right.
It doesn't come often.
- And it doesn't stay long.
- What about you, Mr. Bates?
I don't see why not.
There's Lady Mary.
You go on ahead. I'll
see you back at the house.
Right you are, then.
Good day, milady.
Is her ladyship all right?
Has she recovered from...?
If you think she'll ever recover
from carrying the body of Mr. Pamuk
from one side of the house
to the other,
then you don't know her at all.
Well, I didn't mean
recover exactly. Just...
get past it.
She won't do that,
either.
When she dies they'll
cut her open and
find it engraved on her heart.
What about you?
What about your heart?
Haven't you heard?
I don't have a heart.
Everyone knows that.
Not me, milady.
You wanted to see the
new chauffeur, milord?
Yes, indeed. Please send him in.
Come in. Come in.
Good to see you again.
- Branson, isn't it?
- That's right, your lordship.
I hope they've
shown you everything,
and delivered whatever
we promised at interview.
Certainly, milord.
Won't you miss Ireland?
Ireland, yes, but not the job.
The mistress was a nice lady,
but she only had one car,
and she wouldn't let me drive
it over 20 miles an hour.
So, it was a bit...
well, boring, so to speak.
You've got a wonderful library.
You're very welcome to
borrow books, if you wish.
Really, milord?
There's a ledger that
I make everyone use,
even my daughters.
Carson and Mrs. Hughes
sometimes take a novel or two.
What are your interests?
History and politics, mainly.
Heavens.
Carson, Branson is going
to borrow some books.
- He has my permission.
- Very good, milord.
Is that all, milord?
It is.
Off you go, and good luck.
He seems a bright spark
after poor old Taylor.
And to think Taylor's
gone off to run a tea shop!
I cannot feel it will make for a
very restful retirement, can you?
I would rather be
put to death, milord.
Quite so. Thank you, Carson.
How about some house parties?
She's been asked to one next
month by Lady Anne McNair.
That's a terrible idea. She
doesn't know anyone under 100.
I might send her to visit my aunt.
She could get to know New York.
Oh, I don't think things
are quite that desperate.
Poor Mary. She's been terribly
down in the mouth lately.
She was very upset by the
death of poor Mr. Pamuk.
Why? She didn't know him.
One can't go to pieces at
the death of every foreigner.
We'd all be in a state of collapse
whenever we opened a newspaper.
Oh, no. Of course,
Mary's main difficulty
is that her situation
is unresolved.
I mean, is she an
heiress or isn't she?
The entail's unbreakable.
Mary cannot inherit.
No, what we need is a lawyer
who's decent and
honour-bound to look into it.
I... I think, perhaps,
I know just the man.
- Are you going to the fair?
- I shouldn't think so, sir.
But I don't mind
it. I like the music.
Goodness, what's
happened to your hands?
- It's nothing, ma'am.
- They look very painful.
Oh, no, ma'am. Irritating
more than painful.
Have you been using anything new
to polish the silver or the shoes?
- No.
- May I?
Leave him alone, Mother.
It looks like erysipelas.
- You must have cut yourself.
- Not that I'm aware of.
We'll walk to the
hospital tomorrow.
- Really, ma'am...
- I insist.
If you've got a cold,
I want you out of here.
Anna, they are. You
know I'm out tonight?
Because I don't want to
come home to any surprises.
That'll be the day.
We thought we might
go to the fair later.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you, Daisy?
Now, you ought to go. She's
been that down in the mouth
since the death of poor Mr. Pamuk.
- Don't say that.
- Well, she has!
We could all walk down together
after the servants' dinner.
You won't be walking anywhere.
She's got minutes to
live, by the sound of it.
Go to bed at once.
Yes, Mrs. Hughes.
I'll bring up a Beechams powder.
Right, if there's anything
you want to ask me,
it'll need to be before I go.
What would I want to ask you?
I'm preparing a meal for Lord
and Lady Grantham and the girls.
No-one is visiting.
No-one is staying.
Well...
that's settled, then.
I'm afraid Dr. Clarkson's
out delivering a baby.
We don't know when he'll be back.
No matter. If you open
the store cupboard,
I can easily find what I need.
- Well...
- You can tell the doctor
that you opened it for
the chairman of the board.
I assure you he will raise
not the slightest objection.
This should do it...
tincture of steel, 10 drops
in water three times a day.
And this is solution
of nitrate of silver.
Rub a little in morning and night.
How long before it's better?
Erysipelas is very hard to cure.
We should be able to reduce the
symptoms, but that might be all.
Oh, and you must wear
gloves at all times.
I couldn't...
wait a table in gloves
I'd look like a footman.
You may have to do.
The tincture and
the salve will help.
Try it for a week, and we'll see.
Someone to see you, Mr. Crawley.
Well, there's nothing in my diary.
It's Lady Grantham.
Well, in that case,
show her in at once.
Cousin Cora, to what do I owe the...
I hope I'm not a disappointment.
I thought it might be nice
to cheer it up a bit.
Easier said than done.
Perhaps a flower or a
bit of veil or something.
I can find you a veil, if you like.
I hope you're not
expecting ME to do it.
Not if you're busy, of course.
Good.
And Miss O'Brian?
I've sent Anna to bed with a cold,
so I need you to manage
the young ladies.
What, all three of
them? I'm not an octopus.
Why can't Gwen do it?
Because she is not a lady's maid.
- I am not a slave.
- Just do it, Miss O'Brien.
Just do it.
I'll pay you the compliment that I
do not believe you wish to inherit
just because nobody's
investigated properly.
- No, but...
- Nor can Mary
accuse you of making trouble
when you will suffer
most from a discovery.
You're right that I don't wish
to benefit, at Mary's expense,
- from an ignorance of the law.
- Putting it bluntly,
do you think Robert has thrown
in the towel prematurely?
Good heavens! What am I sitting on?
A swivel chair.
- Another modern brainwave?
- Invented by Thomas Jefferson.
Why does every day involve
a fight with an American?
- I'll fetch a different one.
- No, no. No, no.
I'm a good sailor.
It will depend on
the exact terms
of the entail and
of the deed of gift
when cousin Cora's money
was transferred to the estate.
That is all I ask, to
understand the exact terms.
Is Daisy going to the fair
tonight with the others?
Why don't you ask her?
She needs taking out of herself.
- What's it to you?
- Nothing.
Daisy, I was hoping...
Would you like to go to
the fair with me, Daisy?
There's a few of us going later on.
Do you mean it?
Daisy, don't let it get cold!
Come on, come on, come on!
You bastard.
Why is Sybil having a
new dress and not me?
Because it is Sybil's turn.
Can it be my choice this time?
Of course. As long as
you choose what I choose.
Branson, you'll be taking
Lady Sybil to Ripon tomorrow.
- She'll be leaving after lunch.
- Certainly, your ladyship.
Poor old Madam Swann.
I don't know why we
bother with fittings.
- She always makes the same frock.
- What do you want to make?
- Something new and exciting.
- Heavens, look at the time!
Not a minute to change.
And Granny's invited herself
for dinner.
Then, she can jolly well wait.
So, women's rights
begin at home? I see.
Well, I'm all for that.
I'm just off, Mr. Carson.
According to the wine book,
we should have six dozen of this.
But I'm beggared if I
can find more than four.
Look again before you jump
to any nasty conclusions.
Long time since you
last took a night off.
- You don't think I ought to stay?
- Certainly not. Be off with you.
And Anna's in bed with a cold,
so I'm afraid it's all down to you.
Go.
I wanted to have a
go before I went home.
- How about you?
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Do you know is your father
doing anything this evening?
- He's not coming to the fair.
- Seriously.
We're having dinner
with his family.
Could I look in afterwards?
May I ask why?
Your grandmother paid me a
visit this afternoon, and I'm...
Well, never mind. But
I would like to see him.
Granny came to see you?
Is it all part of the great matter?
So, are you enjoying your new life?
Yes, I think so.
I know my work seems
very trivial to you.
Not necessarily.
Sometimes I rather envy you,
having somewhere
to go every morning.
I thought that may have
been very 'middle-class.
You should learn to
forget what I say.
I know I do.
How about you?
Is your life proving satisfactory?
Apart from the great
matter, of course.
Women like me don't have a life.
We choose clothes and pick halls
and work for charity
and do the season.
But, really, we're
stuck in a waiting room
until we marry.
I've made you angry.
My life makes me angry.
Not you.
I never put the Sauternes on ice.
Mrs. Hughes goes out for one
night and we all fall to pieces!
Mr. Carlson, we
wondered if we could walk
down to the fair after dinner.
I suppose so.
But don't be too late.
- Where do you think she's gone?
- None of your business.
Like most of what
goes on round here.
Well caught that man...
though I say it myself.
Thanks ever so.
Yes?
- You've cheered up a bit.
- He's so agile, in't he?
He could have been
a sportsman.
Who?
- Thomas, of course.
- Really?
Which sport did he have in mind?
I ran into cousin Matthew
in the village.
He wanted to call
on you after dinner.
Apparently,
Granny's been to see him.
Did you tell him she's
coming here this evening?
I didn't know she was.
When he arrives, do your best
to keep her in the drawing room.
Well, I'd like to see you try.
Don't stay too long.
Let them have an early night.
Sybil, darling, why would you
want to go to a real school?
You're not a doctor's daughter.
Nobody learns anything
from a governess.
Apart from French
and how to curtsy.
What else do you need?
Well, there's...
Are you thinking of
a career in banking?
No. But it is a noble profession.
Things are different in America.
I know. They live in wigwams.
And when they come out of
them, they go to school.
If you wait in the library,
I'll tell Papa you're here.
Thank you.
Elsie?
- It is Elsie, isn't it?
- It is.
Though there's very few left
to call me that, Joe Burns.
Well, I'm flattered
that I'm one of them.
Where's Thomas?
I'm fear I let the servants
go down to the fair, milord.
I didn't know we'd have
any visitors tonight.
Well, that's all right.
They don't have much fun.
You should join them.
So... what did you say to Mama?
I haven't spoken to her
since her visit,
but I have looked
through every source,
and I can't find one reason
on which to base a challenge.
I could have told you that.
I'm not quite sure how to
phrase it when
I tell her.
She shouldn't have put
you on the spot like that.
It was unkind.
I'm afraid she'll think I've failed
because I don't want to succeed.
She will think that, but
I don't. And nor will Cora.
Of course, it's
impossible for Mary.
She must resent me so bitterly.
I don't blame her.
Yes, it must have been
hard for you when Ivy died.
It took some getting used to.
What about your son?
Do you see much of him?
Peter? No.
I would have given him a share
of the farm if he wanted it,
but... he's joined the army.
Well, I never!
Aye, he seems happy.
But it's left me on my own.
- Shall I take your plates, then?
- Thank you.
- So, how's life treated you?
- Oh, I can't complain.
I haven't travelled.
But I've seen a bit of
life, and no mistake.
I notice you call yourself missus.
Housekeepers and cooks
are always missus.
You know better than anyone
I haven't changed my name.
Well, I know you wouldn't
change it to Burns
when you had the chance.
You shouldn't have eaten with us.
The chauffeur always eats
in his own cottage.
Steady on. You can cut him a
bit of slack on his second day.
I'm waiting to take
old Lady Grantham home.
Even then,
Taylor never ate with us.
You're taking advantage
of Mrs. Hughes' absence.
What are you doing?
I'm sorting the collars.
Removing the ones that
have come to an end.
What happens to his
lordship's old clothes?
What's it to you?
Clothes are a valet's
perk, not a chauffeur's.
I get some, but mostly it goes
into the missionary barrel.
I know it's meant to be kind,
but I can think of better
ways of helping the needy
than sending stiff
collars to the equator.
I thought Anna might have
come down for her dinner.
And show she's ready
to start work again?
Not a chance.
- Is she still in bed, then?
- She is.
While I'm sat here sewing like a
cursed princess in a fairy tale,
and not down at the
fair with the others.
Would you like me to ask Branson
to bring the car round, milady?
Where's Robert?
He can't have been
drinking port since we left.
He'd be under the table by now.
His lordship's in the library.
- All alone? Oh, how sad.
- No, he's...
We can say goodbye to
Papa for you, Granny.
He's what?
He's with Mr. Crawley, milady.
The question is, what do
I say to cousin Violet?
Don't worry about that.
I can handle her.
Really?
Well, if you can, you must
have learned to very recently.
Anna?
Sr. Bates?
Can you open the door?
I daren't.
No-one can open that
door except Mrs. Hughes.
Just for a moment. I've
brought you something.
I don't know what...
What I don't understand
in all this is you.
You seem positively glad
to see Mary disinherited.
You speak as if we had a choice.
Thank you, Branson.
I'm worn out. Tell Lady Mary
and Mr. Crawley I've gone to bed.
Shall I tell them now, milord?
No. Wait until they ring.
I like this one.
- Yes, sir?
- I ought to start back.
- This is very late for me.
- Aw, not yet.
It's a long time since I've had a
girl to show off for at the fair.
So, I take it you never get lonely?
Well, that's working
in a big house.
Though, there are times when
you yearn for a bit of solitude.
We have a winner!
Thank you.
Right, well, er... something
to remind you of me.
I don't need help to remember you.
But what happens when you retire?
I should think if I stay
here they'll look after me.
Suppose they sell the estate.
Suppose there's a tidal wave.
Suppose we all die of the
plague. Suppose there's a war.
What did I tell you?
She's found her Romeo.
He might be her brother.
She hasn't got one,
or we'd know.
Just a sister in Lytham St Anne's.
You know everything, don't you?
Everything my foot!
You're hiding behind him,
but he's not what you think he is.
Oh, go home, William.
If you're gonna be
such a spoilsport...
All right, I will.
Come back. She didn't mean it.
I must go.
But... it's been lovely
to see you again, Joe.
Really.
And you know what I'm asking?
You haven't asked anything yet.
But you know what it is? When I do.
I'm going to stop here at
the pub until I hear from you.
Oh, and take your time.
I'd rather wait a week
for the right answer, then...
get a wrong one in a hurry.
Think about it carefully.
I will.
I promise you that.
To break the entail, we'd need
a private bill
in Parliament?
Even then, it would only be passed
if the estate were in danger,
which it's not.
And I mean nothing in all this?
On the contrary, you
mean a great deal.
A very great deal.
- You rang, milady?
- Yes, Carson.
Mr. Crawley was just leaving.
Do you know where his lordship is?
Gone to bed, milady.
He felt tired after he put
Lady Grantham into the car.
I bet he did. Thank you, Carson.
I'm sorry. I wish I could think of
something to say that would help.
There's nothing.
But you mustn't let it trouble you.
It does trouble me.
It troubles me very much.
Then, that will be
my consolation prize.
Good night, cousin Matthew.
Good night.
I hope I haven't
kept you up too late?
I'm afraid we've
interfered with your dinner.
It's been rather a
chop-and-change evening downstairs.
Lady Grantham got off all right?
"All right" is an optimistic
assessment, sir.
It's very difficult, Carson.
For her, for Lady Mary.
- For everyone.
- It is, Mr. Crawley.
But I appreciate your saying so.
Well, that's her greatness
done and dusted for the night.
Will, have you had a good night?
I'm off to bed.
Wait.
- What happened?
- Nothing. Doesn't matter.
How was your evening, Mrs. Hughes?
Very enjoyable, thank you.
The others are just behind me,
so you can lock up in a minute.
Well, I'll say good night.
- Good night, Mrs. Hughes.
- Good night.
Night, Mrs. Hughes.
Good night, Mrs. Hughes.
I was right when I said she
was looking sparkly eyed.
I beg your pardon, Thomas?
He can disapprove all he likes.
Mrs. Hughes has got a fancy man.
Him, a fancy man?
Don't be so nasty, Daisy.
It doesn't suit you.
I reckon there's a
job vacancy coming up.
Miss O'Brian,
do you fancy a promotion?
Very droll. If she's
got a boyfriend...
I'm a giraffe.
Leave me alone, Mr. Bates.
I know you mean well,
but let me be.
What chance did he have
up against a champion?
Well, you listen.
You filthy little rat.
If you don't lay off, I
will punch your shining teeth
through the back of your skull.
Is this supposed to
frighten me, Mr. Bates?
Because if it is, it isn't working.
I'm sorry, but it's
just not working.
Daisy? Chafing dishes now.
Right in front of
you, Mrs. Patmore.
Are you trying to trick me?
Anna's still not well. O'Brien,
you'll need to dress
the girls this morning.
All we know about Lady Mary,
and here I am waiting
on her hand and foot!
- Will we do anything with that?
- Maybe, but not yet.
What do you look like?
Daisy, what do you
think he looks like?
Do your buttons up.
Well, go on, then.
What do you want?
I've got a message
for Lady Sybil.
From her ladyship.
Thank you, O'Brien.
I'll manage now.
Odious woman.
What does Mama want?
I just said that to get rid of her.
This came today.
I knew they would want to see you.
It's your reference what's done it.
How am I going to get there?
They won't let me take a day off.
You're going to be ill.
They can't stop you being ill.
What?
No-one has seen
Anna for a whole day.
They won't notice if you
vanish for a couple of hours.
The only one who never sticks
up for me in all this is you.
Why is that?
You are my darling
daughter, and I love you.
Hard as it is for an
Englishman to say the words.
Well, then.
If I had made my own fortune
and bought Downton myself,
it should be yours without question.
But I did not.
My fortune is the work of others
who laboured to
build a great dynasty.
Do I have the right
to destroy their work?
Or impoverish that dynasty?
I am a custodian, my
dear, not an owner.
I must strive to be worthy
of the task I've been set.
If I could take Mama's money
out of the estate,
Downton would have to be sold
to pay for it.
Is that what you want?
To see Matthew a landless peer
with a title but no
means to pay for it?
So, I'm just to find a
husband and get out of the way?
You could stay here
if you married Matthew.
You know my character, Father.
I'd never marry any
man that I was told to.
I'm stubborn. I wish
I wasn't, but I am.
Will you have your own way,
do you think? With the frock.
Only I couldn't help
overhearing yesterday.
And from what her ladyship said,
it sounded as if you
support women's rights.
I suppose I do.
Because I'm quite political.
In fact, I brought some pamphlets
that I thought might interest you.
About the vote.
Thank you.
But please don't mention this
to my father. Or my grandmother.
One whiff of reform, and she hears
the rattle of the guillotine.
It seems rather unlikely,
a revolutionary chauffeur.
Maybe.
But I'm a socialist,
not a revolutionary.
And I won't always be a chauffeur.
Mrs. Crawley. How nice.
You're busy. We
can come back later.
Molesley?
What are you doing
here? Are you ill?
Poor old Mr. Molesley.
How's it going?
The solution doesn't seem
to make it any better.
My imagination's running riot.
I've got erysipelas, your ladyship.
I am sorry.
Mrs. Crawley tells
me she's recommended
nitrate of silver
and tincture of steel.
Why, is she making a suit
of armour?
But I take it there's
been no improvement?
Not really.
And you're sure it's erysipelas?
That is Mrs. Crawley's
diagnosis.
What it is to have
medical knowledge.
It has its uses.
I see your father has been
making changes at home.
He has, milady. He's got
no use for the herb garden
now my mother's gone.
- And you've been helping him?
- I have.
Grubbing out the old rue hedge?
How did you know that?
Because this is not erysipelas.
This is a rue allergy.
If Molesley wears gardening gloves,
it'll be gone in a week.
Please don't think we're ungrateful
for your enthusiasm, Mrs. Crawley,
but... there comes a
time when things are best
left to the professionals.
- But I...
- And now I really,
I really must go.
Good day.
Thank you, your ladyship.
I hope cousin Violet has
recovered from last night.
Whatever she says, my
mother is as strong as an ox.
It's high time she let go of her
scheme for upsetting everything.
Time we all did.
I can't deny I'm
pleased to hear it.
Are you beginning to
see a future here, then?
In a way, this business
has forced me to recognise
that I do want Downton
to be my future.
I'm glad.
You must have thought me an awful
prig when I first arrived.
Not a prig, just a man thrust into
something he never
wanted or envisaged.
I could only see the
absurdity of the whole thing.
- I'm sorry.
- Well, there are absurdities involved,
as I know well enough.
Possibilities, too.
And I was blind to them.
I was determined
not to let it change me.
It was absurd.
If you don't change, you die.
Do you think so?
I'm not sure. Sometimes
I think I hate change.
At least we can comfort ourselves
that this will still be here.
Because we saved it.
Thomas is lovely, in't he?
He's funny and handsome.
- He's got such lovely teeth.
- He's not for you, Daisy.
Course not. He's too good for me.
I know that.
No! He's not too good.
- What, then?
- He's not the boy for you,
and you're not the girl for him.
In't that what I just said?
And why would he be, when
he's seen and done so much,
and I've been nowhere
and done nothing?
Perhaps, Thomas has seen and
done more than is good for him.
He's not a lady's man.
- Well, in't it a blessed relief?
- Daisy!
Thomas is a troubled soul.
I don't know what you
mean, Mrs. Patmore.
Nothing.
I don't mean anything.
Except, if I don't get
the ice cream started,
they'll be dining at midnight.
Golly, my corset's tight.
Anna, when you've done that,
be an angel and loosen it a bit.
The start of the slippery slope.
I'm not putting on weight.
It didn't shrink in the draw.
Are you coming down?
I don't know why we
bother with corsets.
Men don't wear them, and they look
perfectly normal in their clothes.
- Not all of them.
- She's just showing off.
She'll be on about
the vote in a minute.
If you mean do I think
women should have the vote,
of course I do.
I hope you won't chain
yourself to the railings,
and end up being
force-fed semolina.
What do you think, Anna?
I think those women are very brave.
Hear-hear.
How did you get on
with your dressmaker?
- Find anything?
- I did.
And she says she can
have it done by Friday.
I'm sorry I couldn't come, but
I didn't want to put Matthew off.
EDITH: Were you pleased with
the work on the cottages?
I think they're making
a very good job of them.
You must all go and see.
You'll restore a few every year?
It was Matthew's idea.
Old crips was rather reluctant,
but I'm pleased we went forward.
- I suppose it's worth it.
- Of course it is.
Because of the people
who will live in them.
I be glad to hear
Matthew's conscience
is much more energetic than mine.
Excuse me, I'm going to
bed. I've rather a headache.
Of course.
- Should I bring you something for it?
- No, I'll be perfectly fine.
If I can just lie down.
Mary.
Oh, my darling.
What is it?
You heard him,
"Matthew this, Matthew that,
Matthew, Matthew, Matthew!"
Oh, Mother, don't you see?
He has a son now. Of course he
didn't argue with the entail.
Why would he when he's
got what he always wanted?
Your father loves you very much.
He wouldn't fight for me, though.
Because he knew he couldn't win.
- You're no better.
- What?
You don't care that
Matthew gets everything,
because you don't
think I'm worthy.
Mary!
I wish you'd just
admit it.
I'm a lost soul to you.
I took lover with no thought
of marriage... a Turk!
Oh, think of that! Oh, my dear!
Don't worry, Mama.
You can go down now.
Everything will look
better in the morning.
Isn't that what you usually say?
I say it because it's usually true.
Papa will wonder where you are.
- Don't quarrel with Matthew.
- Why shouldn't I?
Because one day you may need him.
Oh, I see.
When I've ruined myself,
I must have a powerful
protector to hide behind.
I'd tell you off...
... but I like to hear you play.
- Where are they all?
- Busy, I suppose.
Haven't you got anything to do?
Yes, I have.
Of course I have.
You mustn't let
Thomas get you down.
He's just jealous.
Everyone likes you better than him.
Not everyone.
Then, she's a foolish girl,
and she doesn't deserve you.
Though, why am I encouraging you?
Forget all that for
10 years at least.
You're a kind woman, Mrs. Hughes.
I don't know how this house
would run without you.
I don't, truly.
Stopped flannelling and get on.
Before I betray you
to Mr. Carson.
Is there anything more
thrilling than a new frock?
I suppose not, milady.
You shall have one, too.
I thought this would be suitable
for your interview.
- I won't be wearing it, milady.
- Of course you will.
We have to make you look like
a successful, professional woman.
What is it? What's happened?
Well, I won't wear it
because I'm not going.
They've cancelled the appointment.
They found someone more
"suited for the post".
- And better qualified.
- This time.
Let's face it.
There will never be anyone
less suited for the post
or worse qualified than I am.
That isn't true.
You'll see. We're not giving up.
No-one hits the bull's-eye
with the first arrow.
I've put out the Rundle
candlesticks for dinner tonight.
Oh. I'm sorry. I'll
come back later.
No, stay. Please.
I've got something I'd
like to talk to you about.
If you've a minute.
Before I first came here
as head housemaid,
I was walking out with a farmer.
When I told him I'd
taken a job at Downton,
he asked me to marry him.
I was a farmer's daughter from
Argyll, so I knew the life.
He was very nice.
But then I came
here, and I did well,
and I didn't want to give
it up, so I told him no...
and he married someone else.
She died three years ago,
and last month he wrote
asking to see me again.
And I agreed, because all this time
I've wondered.
Go on.
I met him the other night.
We had dinner at the Grantham Arms,
and after, he took me to the fair.
And he was horrible
and fat and red-faced,
and you couldn't think
what you ever saw in him?
He was still a nice man.
He is still a nice man.
Well, he was a bit red-faced,
and his suit was a little tight,
but none of that matters.
In the real ways,
he hadn't changed.
And he proposed again...
and you accepted?
In many ways, I wanted to accept.
But I'm not that
farm girl any more.
I was flattered, of course, but...
... I've changed, Mr. Carson.
Life's altered you,
as it's altered me.
And what would be
the point of living
if we didn't let life change us?
You won't be leaving, then?
You'd better come. Mrs.
Patmore's on the rampage.
She wants the key to
the store cupboard.
You know how angry she
gets she hasn't got one.
Nor will she have, not
while I'm housekeeper here.
Leaving? When would
I ever find the time?
... I have to go cap in
hand to Mary Queen of Scots!
Whatever is holding Sybil up?
She was going on
about her new frock.
We'd better go in without her,
or it's not fair on Mrs. Patmore.
Oh, is her cooking
so precisely timed?
You couldn't tell.
I think her food is delicious.
Naturally.
Good evening, everyone.
Why should you be burdened
with Mary's secret?
There's a rumour in London
that you are not virtuous.
I wish you'd just come out with it.
With what?
Whatever it is
you're keeping secret.
Isn't it possible I should
win the thing on merit?
I think the appropriate
answer to that is: "Yes, dear".
- Maybe I'll shine by comparison.
- Maybe you will.
ITFC Subtitles
www.tvsubtitles.net