Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
Come here, you!
Out you get.
Untie these ropes
as quickly as you can.
What do you think, Mary?
Perfect.
Daisy! Get downstairs with those now!
I say!
Mary! Happy Christmas!
And to you.
Anna, this is for you.
The usual cloth for a frock,
I'm afraid.
But I hope you like the other thing.
I'm sure I will, m'lady. Thank you.
We all prayed for him
in church this morning.
Happy Christmas, Anna.
I can't wait for you to open this.
Thank you, Your Ladyship.
Happy Christmas.
What did Her Ladyship say?
She was just being kind.
Happy Christmas.
I wish I could tell you
not to worry.
My husband's on trial for his life,
Mrs Hughes. Of course I worry.
Well, I'm old-fashioned
enough to believe that
if they can't prove him
guilty, then he's not.
This is for you.
Thank you, m'lady.
The Royal Families Of Europe.
I shall find this very interesting,
my Lord.
Good.
I don't want to spoil their fun.
But I couldn't wear a paper hat.
Not with poor Mr Bates locked away.
His Lordship said much the same.
Is Mr Bates the one Lady Rosamund
told me about? The murderer.
Mr Bates has most unjustly
been accused of murder.
That is all.
All?! I should think that's
quite enough for most people.
Thank you.
Would you like tea?
Why do we have to help ourselves
at luncheon?
It's a Downton tradition.
They have their feast at lunchtime
and we have ours in the evening.
Why can't they have their lunch
early and then serve us?
Because it's Christmas Day.
It's not how we'll do it at Haxby.
Which I can easily believe.
This is ni... This is...
What is it?
What does it look like?
Something for getting stones
out of horses' hooves.
It's a nutcracker.
We thought you'd like it.
To crack your nuts.
Who's coming on New Year's Day?
The usual guns. Us three and some
locals. You'll know all of them.
Have you asked Anthony Strallan?
I tried. I gave him three dates
but he said no to all of them.
Perhaps he's given it up.
But he was so keen before the war.
Perhaps he's had enough banging
for one life.
And Rosamund's forced me
to invite Lord Hepworth.
Really?
I told him I was coming down here
and he dropped hint after hint!
Perhaps he has nowhere to go.
It can be a lonely time of year.
Jinks Hepworth lonely?
I find that hard to believe.
Hepworth men don't go in
for loneliness much.
How do you know him?
I knew his father
in the late Sixties.
Mais ou sont les neiges d'antan?
Isobel told me you were telephoning
for news of Mr Swire.
How is he?
Not good.
I am catching the train
first thing in the morning.
I hope I'm in time.
Is it as bad as that?
I'm so sorry.
Matthew is going to London tomorrow.
Lavinia's father is ill.
Better warn Robert
if you'll miss the shoot.
I'll be back by New Year's Day.
He won't last that long, I'm afraid.
Forgive me if I'm casting a gloom.
Don't be silly. We're all under
the shadow of Bates's trial.
Will any of you have to testify?
Only Papa and some of the servants.
But I'm going to support Anna.
Would you like me to come with you?
To explain what's happening.
Or will you do that?
Richard wants to go back to work
the day after the shoot.
Don't you?
Yes, I do.
Now, Thomas.
What's this?
It's a board for planchette.
What's that?
A game. Well, not quite a game,
more a method of communication.
How?
Never mind.
I'll take it if you like.
Sybil's favourite.
A happy Christmas to us all!
Happy Christmas!
Don't forget to make a wish.
Let's all make a wish.
A wish and a prayer.
Is this about Bates again?
My new maid says the servants' hall
is full of it. How terrible it is.
We mustn't lose faith.
He's been wrongly accused.
I'm sure you hope so.
We know so.
How has Mr Murray managed
to have the trial held in York?
I don't know, but thank God he has.
And he's confident?
He seems to be.
Lawyers are always confident
before the verdict.
It's only afterwards
they share their doubts.
Is anyone there?
You must take it seriously,
otherwise they'll be offended.
What is it?
We're talking to the dead.
But how? They can't talk back.
They can. That's the whole point.
Come on, Daisy.
No, I don't think it's right.
If you'll all be quiet,
I'll try again.
Is there anyone there?
Yes, someone is there.
What is going on?
We're just playing a game.
An unsuitable game, Miss O'Brien.
Especially on Christmas night.
Please put it away at once.
I'm surprised at you, Daisy.
Are you sure there's nothing in it?
Quite sure, thank you.
Don't you believe in spirits, then?
Well, I don't believe
they play board games.
You're reading.
For heavens' sakes, yes,
I'm reading. It's a book title.
No talking.
I know, but honestly!
Five words.
Fourth word.
Two syllables.
First syllable.
Fighting!
Banging!
Drum!
They'll never get it.
Shake! Mad!
Do you always play charades
on Christmas night?
This isn't charades,
this is the game.
Trip!
Do you enjoy these games in which
the player must appear ridiculous?
Sir Richard, life is a game in which
the player must appear ridiculous.
Not in my life.
Fall past.
Fell! Wildfell!
The Tenant Of Wildfell Hall!
Isis!
Richard, your turn. Come on.
How soon your maxim will be tested.
If Mr Bates should not come back...
I am not replacing Bates.
What were you going to say?
Only that I know that Thomas
is keen to be promoted.
The trouble is, being dressed and
undressed is an intimate business.
We've forgiven Thomas
his early sins, I know.
But I cannot imagine I would ever
quite feel trust.
Say no more, my Lord.
I'm sure Mr Bates will
be home soon, which
will settle the matter.
We're running out of time now.
Did you make all that?
Yes, why?
And you're still
only the kitchen maid?
I don't know what I am.
You could be a sous chef at least
in London.
I don't know what a sous jeff is.
Or a cook.
Maybe not in a house like this.
But you wouldn't have to go far down
the ladder before they'd snap you up.
Daisy, find Thomas and tell him
the tea's ready to go up.
Then we should get started on the
mixture for the cheese souffles.
Does Daisy cook the souffles too?
What's it to you?
What do you mean, you've
invited Anthony Strallan?
I thought it was just us.
Getting important!
He never used to use a chauffeur.
Well, you were so disappointed
that he wouldn't come shooting.
Good afternoon, Lady Grantham.
Lady Edith!
What a charming surprise.
It's been far too long.
It's so nice to see you.
It's such a relief
to see any of our
friends who've made
it through unscathed.
I'm afraid I haven't quite.
I took a bullet in the wrong place.
Seems to have knocked out my right arm.
But not forever surely?
The upshot is, I'm afraid, the wretched
thing is now no use to man or beast.
Well, now we know why you didn't
want to come shooting.
Indeed.
So how is everyone?
Lady Sybil is married, I hear.
Living in Ireland.
How was the wedding?
Quiet.
It was in Dublin.
They didn't want a big affair.
Did you all get over?
Mary and I did. Papa...
No, we were all ill. Isn't it sad?
What's he like?
He's political.
As long as he's on the right side!
So does he shoot?
I'm... sure he does.
But I don't think pheasants.
Mr Murray thinks a reference
from an earl will go in my favour.
I'm not sure such things matter
when it comes to murder.
I think it will help.
Because you want to think so.
Anna, you must prepare for the worst.
I'm not saying it will happen,
but you must prepare for it.
I know it could happen.
I do.
But the time to face it
is after it has happened.
And not before.
Grant me that?
Lady Grantham, Lady Rosamund.
Hello, Lord Hepworth. Welcome.
Thank you.
Will your man be coming on
from the station, my Lord?
I haven't got one with me.
Is that a nuisance? I'm so sorry.
Not at all, my Lord. Thomas will
take care of you while you're here.
Splendid.
Do come in.
Thank you.
This came for you
in the evening post.
It's from Sybil.
You must go up and change.
So what do you make
of Rosamund's pal?
He seems agreeable enough.
I suspect he's in the profession
of making himself agreeable.
O'Brien says Rosamund's maid
speaks very highly of him.
That seems a good reference to me.
What is it?
Sybil's pregnant!
I see.
So that's it, then.
No return. She's crossed the Rubicon.
She crossed it when she married him,
Robert.
She says we're not to tell anyone,
not even the girls.
I wondered why she didn't ask
to come for Christmas.
Would you have allowed it?
Well, well. So we're to have
a Fenian grandchild.
Cheer up.
Come the revolution, it may be useful
to have a contact on the other side.
I say.
This is very cosy, isn't it?
What is?
To find ourselves next door.
I'm not certain it's quite proper
to remark on such things.
You remember my maid, Shore.
Certainly I do.
I hope they've got a jolly party
planned downstairs.
Why would they?
It's New year's Eve, of course.
That. I doubt it, my Lord.
But I don't mind, I make my own fun.
If that's everything, my Lady, I'll go
down now and see you after midnight.
I wish I could say the same.
Only joking.
I wonder if she'll remember me.
She will.
Good evening, Lady Grantham.
I don't suppose you remember me.
Of course I do.
How is dear Hatton?
I have such happy memories
of it from the old days.
I'm not often there,
not since my mother died.
Perhaps it needs a woman's touch.
Don't we all?
How very like
your father you are!
It's almost as if he were standing
here before me!
I hope you'll come to tea.
Then we can talk about him.
I should love it, Lady Grantham.
If they'll release me.
They'll release you.
What are those for?
We have a glass of wine
at midnight on New Year's Eve.
Very civilised.
In my last place, we
were expected to be
upstairs and serving,
New Year's Eve or not.
Were you not a lady's maid, then?
How long have you been with
Lady Rosamund, Miss Shore?
Two months.
I see. Quite a new girl.
I can read Mr Carson's hint.
His Lordship doesn't trust me.
Because of the stealing, you mean.
So what should I do?
Get him to trust you.
That's easy to say. But how?
Make him grateful.
Do him a good turn.
Hide something he loves,
and find it and give it back.
Miss O'Brien!
Not long now.
Does everyone have a glass?
Anthony Strallan was at Grannie's
for tea the other day.
So I know why he wouldn't shoot.
He's hurt his arm.
Shame. Well, we shall try again
next year.
I am sorry I started that.
Now don't encourage it.
She'd spend her life as a nursemaid.
He's got no use.
Once again, the servants are
downstairs and we're on our own.
In the whole year, we
fend for ourselves
at Christmas lunch and
on New Year's Eve.
It doesn't seem much to me.
You haven't had to fight
for what you've got.
Do try to get past that.
It makes you sound so angry
all the time.
I hope London wasn't too grim.
I got down there in time,
which is the main thing.
And I was with him when he died.
So he wasn't alone.
I'm so sorry, and so glad.
Here we go.
- Happy new year!
Happy new year.
Happy new year, Mama.
1920! Is it to be believed?!
I feel as old as Methuselah!
But so much prettier.
When I think what the last
ten years has brought,
God knows what we're in for now.
He's pushing his luck.
How?
He wants me to speak up for him
to Lady Rosamund.
If I were you, I'd keep out of it.
We'll walk to the first drive
then use the wagonette.
Splendid. I hope you're going to
stand by me.
I thought I'd chum my brother.
Cora's coming after luncheon.
The second drive, then.
You ladies will have to
distribute your charms
fairly as there are only three of you.
Lady Mary?
Lady Mary will stand by me.
Now just...
You said you were going to stand
by me for the first drive.
Did I?
Yes, I think I did.
And one for you. Splendid.
Why don't you have a loader?
Barnard would have found you one.
I'm not very good at it.
This or double guns,
and I don't want a witness.
I'm a witness.
Then please don't spread the word
of my incompetence.
I never know which is worse,
the sorrow when you
hit the bird or the
shame when you miss it.
Thank you for intervening
back there.
Before I said something rude.
He does rather beg to be teased.
The awful truth is, he's starting
to get on my nerves.
Still, you're not the person
to burden with that.
You're still going to marry him
though.
Of course! Why wouldn't I?
Ha! I think I might have
got that one.
You must promise faithfully to lie
when they ask you how I did.
Daisy, you've got a visitor.
I were visiting the grave.
I thought to myself, 'Why
not go and see her now?'
Take William's blessing with me.
Why not go and sit for a moment
in the servants' hall?
We're sending out the shooting lunch.
As soon as we've finished, Daisy
can bring you a cup of tea.
You won't mind, will
you, Mrs Hughes?
Indeed I will not. This way.
He's here now. So I think
I should make things clear.
Don't, Daisy, please. William
wouldn't thank you for it.
He won't thank me for bamboozling
his old dad neither.
I know you're going to say no,
but I was just passing
and I suddenly thought,
'Why don't we go for a
drive, like we used to?'
I don't think I should.
I really can't spare the time.
Would you like a cup of something?
All right. Yes, thank you.
That would be nice.
Is everyone well?
Quite well.
Lady Edith will be joining me
for tea.
Certainly, sir.
As a matter of fact, I'm glad I've
got you to myself for a moment.
I feel it gives me the chance
to make some things clear.
I'm not sure I was that clear
when we met the other day.
It's been worrying me.
I don't understand.
You see, I couldn't bear for you
to think that we might...
take up together again.
When, of course, we can't.
Because of what Mary said that time?
Because you know it wasn't true.
She only said it to spite me.
No, it's not because of that.
And if you say it wasn't true,
I'm sure it wasn't.
You see, the thing is...
I'm far too old for you.
I don't agree.
Of course I am. And now...
I'm a cripple. I don't need a wife,
I need a nurse.
And I couldn't do that to someone
as young and as lovely as you.
I don't accept a single word
of that speech.
Lady Edith...
If you think I'm going to give up
on someone who calls me lovely...
I'm afraid you must.
Lovely.
I'd like you to know
the place he grew up.
He always wanted
to work with animals.
Horses really.
But his mother saw him as a butler.
Lording it over a great house.
He loved you both so much.
I'm only grateful
his mother went first.
She couldn't have borne it.
No, but she would have had to face
it, wouldn't she? Like you.
We all have to face the truth,
don't we?
We do, lass. Hard as it may be.
Because I want to tell you
the truth.
William and me were
friends for a long time
before we started to
feel something more.
That's always the best way,
isn't it?
To know that there's friendship
as well as passion.
Yes, but you see, I didn't.
I didn't feel the love...
so soon.
So I'm afraid I wasted some of the
time we could have spent together.
No, you didn't, Daisy.
You gave him the thrill
of the chase.
He talked of nothing but you from
dawn till the cows came home!
And when he saw you felt the same,
well,
the pleasure was all the sweeter
the waiting. I promise you.
Good.
So when are you going to come
to the farm?
I'll let you know.
Shall I get you some more hot water?
More lies.
Were they?
That's the horn.
Where's the damn loader?
Looking for your damn peg,
I imagine.
Why were you laughing with Matthew
at the end of the first drive?
I suppose he said something funny.
Am I never to be free of him?
Of course not. You know
how families like ours work.
And he'll be head of it one day.
I might understand if you
let me think for a solitary
minute that you preferred
my company to his.
I have tried, Mary. I've done
everything I can to please you.
You mean you bought a large
and rather vulgar house.
Don't talk to me like that!
What have I done to deserve it?!
Is something the matter?
Richard's loader
seems to have got lost.
And this is one of the best drives.
He's missing all the fun.
I see.
Where the bloody hell have you been?
Sorry, sir.
I'm afraid Sir Richard's
rather anxious to begin.
I'd better get back to my post.
There you are, sir.
Robert, Matthew is going to York
for Bates's trial.
And... Well, I wondered
if I might come as well.
Of course, if you want to.
Cora's told me she's not going.
And I feel I just might be useful
as part of the bucking-up brigade.
That's kind, thank you.
It's odd, isn't it,
us just chatting away here
while that poor man
waits to hear his fate.
Please don't make me feel any worse
than I do already.
Have we time to serve the coffee
or not?
I'm not sure, Mr Carson.
We could have used
one of the maids today.
Maids at a shooting lunch?!
Hardly!
Anna's very grateful
you're coming with us.
Well, I have to go to London,
but I'll be back.
What are you going for?
Reggie Swire's funeral.
He wanted his ashes to be buried
in Lavinia's grave.
I'll bring them back.
What does Mr Travis say?
I haven't asked him.
I thought I'd do it myself one day.
Let me know when.
I'd like to be there.
If you don't mind.
No, I don't mind.
This is very nice of you to spare
some time for a poor old woman.
Won't they miss you at the tea?
I'll regain some novelty value
at dinner.
Very well.
What shall we talk about?
Hatton?
Shall we discuss
why you never go there now?
Or Lougherle?
Or what about Hepworth House
in Grosvenor Square?
I spent so many happy evenings there.
With your father in hot pursuit!
I see it's time for some honesty.
A change is as good as a rest.
I think you know that Hatton's gone.
So has Lougherle.
And Hepworth House
had so many mortgages...
I could only sell it at a loss.
So my spies tell me.
So you want Rosamund...
Or rather, the fortune of the late
Mr Painswick to come to the rescue.
My feelings for Lady Rosamund
are sincere.
I admire her immensely.
I do not doubt it. My only fear
is that you admire her money more.
Lady Rosamund is too young
to be alone.
You'll concede there are many
varieties of happy marriage.
Maybe.
But they are all based on honesty.
I insist you tell the truth about
your circumstances to Rosamund.
After that, it's up to her.
Have you thought of a date?
When the men go through,
can I steal you for a moment?
There's something I should tell you.
Something nice, I hope.
Not very nice, no. But you can make
the nastiness go away.
Curiouser and curiouser.
I'd like to get married
in the spring or the summer.
I am only asking to set a date.
But what's the hurry?
Hurry?
Glaciers are fast
compared to you on this, Mary.
I warn you.
Even my patience has its limits.
Mary.
Can I help?
After today, I won't insult you
by asking what you mean.
You don't have to marry him,
you know.
You don't have to marry anyone.
You'll always have a home here
as long as I'm alive.
Didn't the war teach you
never to make promises?
Anyway, you're wrong.
I do have to marry him.
Why? Not to prove you've broken
with me surely?
We know where we stand.
No need for gestures.
If I told you the reason,
you would despise me.
And that I couldn't bear.
Mary?
Rosamund wants to play bridge
until the men come through.
Of course.
It says you're too fat.
My Archie never said that!
You're pushing the thing!
Come away, Daisy.
We've got work to do.
I hope it's rewarding work, Mrs Patmore.
Something to challenge our Daisy.
Leave it alone.
What did she mean, Miss Shore?
Nothing.
Who was telephoning so late?
Murray. He apologised.
He's going to come here
the day before the trial
to talk it all through with
Mrs Hughes, O'Brien and me.
Why have they been chosen and not
the others? What do they know?
Search me. I've told Carson.
Will Mr Murray be staying?
No, he wants to get to York.
We'll meet him there
the following day.
My dear.
I hope you can be strong
if it goes against him.
It won't.
There was an awkward
moment tonight between
Mary and Carlisle at
the end of dinner.
Did you notice it?
I'm sure Mary has him under control.
Does she?
I look at her and all I can see is a
tired woman with a tiresome husband,
not a bride on the brink of heaven.
I wish I could understand
why she goes on with it.
Do you think there's some element
I might have overlooked?
Yes.
Cora, if there is something and you
know what it is, tell me, please.
Perhaps it's time.
I was hoping you'd say I was wrong.
You're not wrong. But if I do tell you,
swear not to fly off the handle.
And try not to be too hurt.
Now you must tell me because nothing
could be worse than my imaginings.
Very well. Do you recall a Turkish
diplomat who stayed here before the war?
I think I can be relied
on to remember any guest
who is found dead in
his bed next morning.
Well, that's the thing.
I wanted to explain
how it will work.
You'll both have received official
notification through the post.
But why have I been called?
What's it to me? I know nothing.
Since you are summoned
as witness for the
prosecution, the police
would obviously disagree.
But I'm there for the
prosecution too when
I have no doubt of Mr
Bates's innocence.
How can that be?
It will be made clear on the day.
Where does Anna stand in all this?
A wife cannot be compelled to
testify against her husband.
That's a mercy anyway.
As far as I could make out,
he was talking to his lawyer.
He seemed to be blaming his wife
for cancelling the divorce.
You heard this yourself?
I wasn't eavesdropping.
He was speaking loudly.
But I don't think you can blame him.
Just answer the questions, please,
Miss O'Brien.
When John Bates returned from London
on his final visit to Mrs Bates,
did you notice anything
about his appearance?
He had a scratch on his cheek.
But he might have got that...
I believe the maid, Anna Smith,
asked him how the meeting had gone.
Well, she and he were...
And how did he answer?
He said it had been worse
than she could possibly imagine.
And what did he call her?
I shouldn't have been listening
in the first place.
I had no right to be there.
But you were listening, Mrs Hughes.
So please tell us what he
called her when he grew angry.
He said she was a... bitch.
Did it sound as if he threatened
to strike her?
But what people say in an
argument...
Did he threaten to strike her?
I'm afraid he did, yes.
Every case looks as black as night by
the time the prosecution has finished.
We've heard nothing
in Bates's defence yet.
I can't believe Mrs Hughes
would say those things.
Miss O'Brien maybe,
but not Mrs Hughes.
It's difficult to lie on oath.
Few of us can manage it.
She looked as if she were in hell.
It does sound worse than I expected.
It's a great pity he didn't
speak up about buying the poison.
I told him to. I begged him to.
He should have listened.
Then it's down to me
to convince them that
this crime is simply not
in Bates's character.
So you have no doubt at all.
None whatsoever.
We served in the African war.
And I owe my life to
John Bates, who acted to
protect me without any
care for his own safety.
Is this a man who could plot
to kill his wife? Absolutely not.
Lord Grantham.
Did John Bates ever speak to you
about his wife?
Not that I recall.
Never?
He never once spoke one
word of this wife who'd
prevented all his dreams
from coming true?
Well... You know, one talks about
this and that.
Did he give you the impression he
was losing patience with Mrs Bates?
Around the time she had prevented
the divorce?
Were you aware that he was angry
at what had happened?
I suppose so.
Did he ask permission to travel to
London to see her that last time?
I believe he did.
And did you recommend restraint
in his dealings with his wife?
I don't think so.
You're absolutely sure?
Well...
Perhaps I may have done.
You did, Lord Grantham.
Mr Bates has, in his interviews,
stated that you prescribed discretion.
His case is that
he followed your advice.
But I wonder why the defence has
chosen not to refer to this.
I can't tell you.
No.
And was there one statement
of his that prompted
you to advise him to
moderate his behaviour?
I can't remember. Not precisely.
Give us an approximate.
I must urge that the witness
gives an answer.
I... said...
I hoped his trip to London was to
do with some property he owned.
And not to do with
the former Mrs Bates.
And how did he answer?
He said...
Lord Grantham.
He said,
'If only she was the former.
Or better still, the late.'
I don't know what to say, ma'am.
They twist your words.
You had to answer their questions.
I wish to God I'd never listened.
Well...
I suppose Anna is very bitter.
I wonder if you would tell her...
I know you're both praying for her.
Mrs Crawley, the jury has returned!
Are you all agreed?
We are, My Lord.
The prisoner will stand.
Do you find the prisoner to be
guilty or not guilty as charged?
Guilty.
John Bates, you have been found guilty
of the charge of wilful murder.
You will be taken from here
to a place of execution.
Where you will be hanged
by the neck until you are dead.
And may God have mercy
upon your soul.
No! This is wrong! This is
terribly, terribly wrong!
Take him down.
Anna!
Did you know this Bates well?
No, not really.
I saw him once.
It was when I went to talk to Matthew
in his bedroom just before dinner.
That sounds rather risque.
Alas, I am beyond impropriety.
There'll be a stink in the papers.
To be honest, I'm surprised
there hasn't been one already.
Perhaps Richard had a hand in it.
While we're on the subject
of unsuitable spouses...
Lord Hepworth is not unsuitable,
Mama.
You are unjust.
He's hardly the consummation
devoutly to be wished.
Did he tell you what I asked him
to tell you?
I know he has no fortune,
if that's what you mean.
No fortune? He's lucky not to be playing
the violin in Leicester Square.
He's fond of me, Mama.
I'm tired of being alone.
And I have money.
He's a fortune-hunter, my dear.
A pleasant one, I admit.
But a fortune-hunter.
Still, it's your decision.
So have you made it?
Not quite.
I'm going to ask Robert to get him
back for the servants' ball.
Will that happen after today?
Well, he can come and stay.
Whether or not we feel like dancing.
Thank you. We don't need anything.
Do sit down, Anna.
You mustn't think
that this is the end.
For the judge to pronounce a death
sentence is a matter of routine.
Routine?
He means the judge had no choice.
If a man is found guilty of murder,
he must be sentenced to death.
But there are many reasons
for it to be commuted. Many reasons.
Is being innocent one of them?
We have to work to change the
sentence to life imprisonment.
Life imprisonment!
Because it won't demand a retrial
or an overthrow of the Crown's case.
Once we have that, we can begin to
build a challenge to the verdict.
Do you understand?
Yes, m'lady, I do.
I still can't believe it.
I'm afraid you must.
We'll need you to write a letter
to the Home Secretary, Mr Shortt.
I'll leave for London at once
and put it into his hand myself.
He's a Liberal, isn't he? Pity.
He's a decent man.
The flaw in their case is
the question of premeditation.
Even if Mr Bates had
run to the cellar for
the poison and pushed
it into her food,
we can argue strongly
he didn't plan it.
He didn't plan it
because he didn't do it.
And we'll stress the circumstantial
nature of the evidence.
There may still be elements
that come to light.
What chance do you think we have?
It's not a good chance, Mrs Bates.
But there's still a chance.
When will they be back?
I'm not sure.
They took Anna to an inn
to help her catch her breath.
How will we ever face her?
With kindness, I hope.
When will he be hanged?
Her Ladyship wondered if you could
give her an account of the day.
Of course.
I'd like to say I may have been
called for the prosecution,
but I do not believe
in Mr Bates's guilt.
What about you, Miss O'Brien?
You're very quiet.
I'm sorry to have been part of it.
There'll have to be a new valet now,
won't there?
I don't often feel selfless,
but when I listen to you, I do.
His Lordship will be so upset.
We're all upset downstairs, m'lady.
Of course you are.
His Lordship and Lady Mary won't
want to change, so we won't either.
Please ask Mrs Patmore to serve
dinner 20 minutes after they arrive.
Very good, m'lady.
Mrs Hughes.
This is a time of grief for us.
Of grief and heartbreak.
I suppose it's down to me again.
What is?
To produce dinner 20
minutes after they arrive
and we don't know if it's
in two or ten hours.
What's got into you all of a sudden?
Nothing. I know I'm a dogsbody but...
How can you choose today of all
days to complain about your lot?
I expect Mr Bates would
rather be wondering
how to keep a roast chicken warm
than sitting in a lonely cell
facing his maker!
You've been hiding from us.
I couldn't do any more chatter.
Are the Crawleys still here?
They went ages ago.
Mama and Edith have gone up.
I'm so dreadfully,
dreadfully sorry about today.
I know you are. How's Anna?
I sent her to bed.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
Do you stay with Carlisle
because he threatened to
expose the story of Mr
Pamuk dying in your bed?
When did you find out?
Your mother told me when
I asked why you were
still with Carlisle when
you are so tired of him.
How very disappointed you must be.
Your mama chose her moment well.
And you're not the first Crawley
to make a mistake.
To answer your question, it is...
partly true, though not entirely.
In Mama's phrase,
I am damaged goods now.
Richard is, after all, prepared
to marry me in spite of it.
To give me a position.
To give me a life.
And that's worth it?
Even though he already
sets your teeth on edge?
What about Matthew?
How does he view the late Mr Pamuk?
He doesn't know.
So that is not what split you apart.
I thought it might have been.
No, there were other reasons
for that.
To do with Lavinia.
I see.
And those reasons are final?
They are final for Matthew.
So, yes, they are.
Here is what I think.
Break with Carlisle.
He may publish but we'll be a house
of scandal anyway with Bates's story.
Go to America, stay with your
grandmother until the fuss dies down.
You may find the New World
is to your taste.
He'll keep my secret if I marry him.
Once, I might have thought that
a good thing.
But I've been through a war
and a murder trial since then.
To say nothing of your sister's
choice of husband.
I don't want my daughter to be married
to a man who threatens her with ruin!
I want a good man for you.
A brave man.
Find a cowboy in the Middle West and
bring him back to shake us up a bit.
Papa!
Have you got a minute, Mr Carson?
Only a minute. I have to go up
and attend to His Lordship.
Well, that's the point. This news
is going to change things, isn't it?
I have every hope that Mr Bates's
sentence will be commuted.
His Lordship is doing everything...
I know.
And I hope he's successful.
But even if he is, Mr Bates won't be
coming home this weekend, will he?
I'm afraid not.
So I... I wondered if you'd given
any more thought to my application.
I'm sorry, but I have spoken
to His Lordship and he
thinks you are more suited
to your present position.
He doesn't trust me, does he?
Because of the stealing.
I knew it.
What is it now?!
Nothing.
Well, it's not nothing, is it?!
I just feel taken for granted.
Sometimes I think that you don't
notice that I'm human at all.
So it's my fault?
You talk to me like
when I first came!
But I know things now.
Things I taught you!
Maybe, but I learned 'em.
And I work well, but you wouldn't
know it, the way I'm treated.
It may be wrong to complain
with Mr Bates like he is,
but it reminds me that life's short
and I'm wasting mine.
Daisy, you're tired.
Why not get away for a day?
You told Mr Mason
you'd go to the farm.
Go, then. Breathe the air.
Have a rest.
I couldn't. I don't think William
would like it.
You got my note.
I'm so glad you're here.
I feel somehow we were, all of us, part
of each other's story for a while.
And now that story is at an end.
In what way?
Matthew doesn't want to live here.
And I'm moving away soon.
You mean to Haxby?
Wherever I go, the time we shared
is over.
And Lavinia was a part of that.
Let's take a moment to remember her.
Our Father, which art in heaven.
What on earth's the matter?
She's still in love with you,
you know.
I don't think so.
I'm sorry,
but it's as plain
as the nose on your face.
I thought you didn't like her
for throwing me over.
That's a different conversation.
Mother, it has to be like this.
I'm afraid I can't explain why.
At least... I'm not going to.
Something to do with Lavinia?
Maybe.
Well, you see, I think you're wrong.
Lavinia wouldn't have wanted this.
She was a sweet girl, a kind girl.
She wouldn't have wanted you
to be unhappy.
You don't understand.
I deserve to be unhappy.
So does Mary.
Nobody your age deserves that.
And if you are, and you can do
something about it and don't,
well, the war has taught you nothing.
That's your opinion.
Yes, it is.
But you can't have been false
to him.
You were his wife
for only half an hour.
It's difficult to explain, m'lady.
Well, try.
I led him on.
When he was wounded,
I let him think that I loved him.
Why?
I thought it'd cheer him up.
Give him something to live for.
And you did all this
when you didn't even like him?
No, I did like him very, very much.
Everyone liked our William.
So you married him to keep
his spirits up at the end?
I suppose I did, yes.
Forgive me, but that
doesn't sound unloving to me.
That sounds as if you loved him
a great deal.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Mama.
I've been outside.
I was looking for...
What was she doing?
Mending the fire and suffering.
She shouldn't be here at this hour.
Why isn't Thomas on duty?
I don't need you to tell me the
world is falling about our ears.
Is there any news on Bates?
Not yet.
Murray has a meeting with the
Home Secretary later today.
We should know something then.
I'm surprised there isn't more
in the papers.
Earl's valet to swing, and so on.
But I've seen hardly anything.
And nothing about you.
I quite agree. I can't enlighten you.
Is that why you're here?
Not exactly. I wanted to talk about
Rosamund and Hepworth.
Careful, she might come in.
Then I shall speak quickly.
I want to know one thing.
Is a woman of Rosamund's age
entitled to marry a fortune-hunter?
Does she know all the facts?
Yes. Yes, she does.
Then I would say yes. But for God's
sake, let's tie up the money.
My thoughts exactly.
What is the matter, Robert?
Isis has gone missing. I can't think
where she's got to.
In you go, Isis.
Good girl.
Will you stay on at Downton?
If they'll let me.
They'll let you.
And you have some money.
Mt Murray thinks you can keep it.
I want you to thank His Lordship
for trying to help me.
Yes, but what he said...
He didn't want to say it.
I won't blame him for not lying.
Give him my best wishes
for the future.
And wish all of them well.
I don't want you to hold it against
Mrs Hughes or Miss O'Brien.
If you think I can ever...
Even Miss O'Brien.
We've not been friends
but she doesn't want me here.
Please forgive them.
I'm not sorry, you know.
Not a bit.
I would marry you now
if I wasn't already your wife.
I would.
God knows I'm not sorry either.
Maybe I should be.
But no man can regret loving
as I have loved you.
No touching!
For God's sake, man.
You know where I am bound.
How dangerous can this be?
One kiss to take with me?
Still at it?
The secrets of the universe
are boundless.
Are they indeed?
All right, shove over.
You've changed your tune.
Have I?
Perhaps I have.
Now, let's get going.
Who's out there?
Here we go.
W.
William.
Is it really you, William?
Yes.
My lord!
My gosh. William, is it you?
What do you want?
Go...
To...
Farm...
Make...
Dad...
Happy.
Go to the farm, make Dad happy!
You can't say fairer than that.
Is it usually so specific?
Not usually, no.
Well, that's enough for me.
This stuff is thirsty work!
They're in the drawing room, sir.
I'm really only here
to see Lady Mary, Carson.
Is there any chance
of... cooking her out?
Leave it with me, sir.
Matthew, you should have come
earlier.
You could have had dinner.
Is something the matter?
My dog's gone missing. I was going
to go and look for her.
We should organise a search party.
Ask the men servants
to join us.
Then we can apply some real method.
Mm.
Isis! Come here, girl! Isis!
Poor Papa. I wonder
if she's been stolen.
What a horrid thought.
Thomas? What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
I'm afraid we'll have to call it
a night!
But remember, there's £10 for anyone
who finds her tomorrow!
For now, thank you all very much.
Poor Papa. It's terrible for you.
She may turn up.
She may be trapped somewhere.
We could still find her.
Get back to the house as
fast as you can and ask Mrs
Patmore to heat up some
soup for the searchers.
Thomas?
Yes, Mr Carson.
Why were you up at the house
this evening?
Did Papa summon you?
As a matter of fact,
I came to see you.
I wanted to find out what you meant when
you said you HAD to marry Carlisle.
And that I'd despise you
if I knew the reason.
Yes, you would.
Whatever it is, it cannot be enough
for you to marry him.
That's what Papa said.
So you told him?
Yes.
Does he despise you?
He's... very disappointed in me.
Even so... Please tell me.
You'd think the good
lord would have spared
him the loss of his dog
at a time like this.
Ours is not to reason why.
When will we hear about Mr Bates?
I don't know how they've kept it
out of the papers.
I suppose that will change...
if it... goes ahead.
I can't bear to think of it.
How will Anna bear it?
As the widow of a murderer.
She'll have to get used to a degree
of notoriety, I'm afraid.
And so will we as the house
that shelters her.
Then let me put you out of your
misery right away, Mr Carson.
By handing in my notice.
You don't mean that.
Yes, I do.
If I stay here,
I keep the story alive.
If I go away to... Scotland say,
or London,
it will die soon enough.
I'll just be one more housemaid
lost in the crowd.
She has a point.
Not one that I accept.
I mean it, Mrs Hughes. I do.
Say something, if it's only goodbye.
Did you love him?
You mustn't try to...
If it was love...
How could it be love? I didn't...
Then why would you?
It was lust, Matthew!
Or a need for excitement.
Or something in him that I...
God, what difference
does it make?
I'm Tess of the d'Urbervilles
to your Angel Clare.
I have fallen. I am impure.
Don't joke. Don't make it little
when I'm trying to understand.
Thank you for that.
But the fact remains
that I am made different by it.
Things have changed between us.
Even so, you must not marry him.
So I must brave the storm?
You're strong.
A storm-braver if ever I saw one.
I wonder. Sybil's the strong one.
She really doesn't care what people
think, but I'm afraid I do.
Papa suggested I go to New York to
stay with Grandmama to ride it out.
You can find some unsuspecting
millionaire.
Preferably one who doesn't read
English papers.
Go or stay, you must sack Carlisle.
It isn't worth buying off a month of
scandal with a lifetime of misery.
When is he due back?
Tomorrow.
He and Aunt Rosamund's beau are
returning for the servants' ball.
Will that still go ahead?
Not if Bates is...
Not if the worst happens.
Papa hasn't faced
that it probably will.
You were wrong about one thing.
Only one? And what is that, pray?
I never would...
I never could despise you.
Why didn't you go and find
the poor thing there and then?!
How? His Lordship was
in the way and Carson
sent me back with a
message for Mrs Patmore.
So you'll leave the wretched animal
all night?
What reason could I give
if I went and found her now?
Go first thing, once you're free.
And just pray nothing's happened.
For your own sake.
Do you think that was William?
Who else could it have been?
Who else would have known
you'd been asked to the farm?
That's true.
So will you go?
I feel I should. Don't you?
I think so.
Isis!
Good dog! Isis!
Good girl!
For God's sake, will you just
bloody come, you stupid dog!
You shouldn't have gone
to all this trouble. Not for me.
No? Not when you're the nearest thing
to a child of mine left on this earth.
I don't deserve it.
Not when I were only married
to William for a few hours.
You were there. You saw it.
You may not know this, Daisy,
but William had three brothers.
And a sister.
What?
All dead. At birth.
Or not long after.
I think that's one reason
why William married you.
So that I wouldn't be alone
with all my bairns gone.
Without you,
I'd have no-one to pray for.
I think William knew that.
So will you be my daughter?
Let me take you into my heart?
Make you special.
You'll have parents of your own.
I haven't got any parents.
Not like that.
I've never been special to anyone.
Except William.
That's right.
I were only ever special to William.
I never thought of it
like that before.
Well... Now you're special to me.
Isis! Where have you
bloody been?
What in God's name happened to you?
I've been looking for the dog.
A village child found her yesterday.
Somehow the silly animal got herself
shut into one of the keeper's shelters.
They took her back and claimed
their reward this morning.
That's good.
Did you really get yourself
into this mess looking for my dog?
I know how fond of her you are.
I'm impressed, Thomas.
It's good to know
there's some decency in
the world at a time like this.
Thank you.
That's all right, my Lord. The main
thing is, she's home and healthy.
Mm.
I could walk to the station.
I walked here after all.
I want to talk while we go.
If you're my daughter, you must
allow me to give you advice.
I suppose.
Well, then.
If you're not content with the way
you're treated, don't
sulk and answer back.
Tell them.
They wouldn't listen.
You don't know. You haven't given
them the chance.
Go to Mrs Patmore and
explain to her why you
think you're worth more
than you're getting.
Make your case. Put it to her.
But Miss Shore says...
Daisy, do me a favour.
Stop listening to that Miss Shore.
Are you here? Nobody told me.
Only just. The train was late. I'll
have to scramble to get changed.
I'm afraid it may be
a rather gloomy visit.
No news yet for the poor valet,
I'm afraid.
So the servants' ball
has been cancelled.
Never mind. I'm very flattered
to be asked back on any terms.
I hope I can read something into it.
Only my desire not to lose my maid.
Miss Shore wouldn't stop nagging
until you were invited.
You owe her a tip.
But I mustn't delay you.
What will you do in America?
What I do here.
Pay calls and go to dinners.
My grandmother has houses
in New York and Newport.
It will be dull,
but not uncomfortable.
M'lady,
I've been thinking.
If things go badly for us...
I thought I might come with you.
You mean you won't leave after all?
I have to leave Downton.
But I don't have to leave you.
But of course you can come with me.
You don't need to ask.
But let's not give up hope yet.
No, m'lady. Let's not do that.
My Lord?
I was only going to say
that if I do need a new
valet, I think I'd like
to give Thomas a trial.
Really, my Lord?
I think I've misjudged him.
There's more true kindness in him
that I give him credit for.
Is there?
I think so.
At any rate, let's give him a chance.
Everyone deserves a chance.
Even Thomas.
Sir Richard's back.
I haven't seen him yet.
He and Lord Hepworth only just
arrived in time to change.
Are you ready?
I think so.
I know what I have to say to him.
It's time.
I wish you'd take my advice
and fight for her.
But I know you won't.
I don't expect you to understand.
That's good because I can't.
But please, don't invoke the name
of that sweet dead girl again.
I've always wanted to see America,
so at least I've got a plan.
I suppose so.
I still can't be glad
you'll be leaving here.
But it's good news that you
won't be casting off entirely.
It's only...
I know.
Just so as you know,
you're highly valued by all of us.
Both of you. Very highly valued.
My God, Mary, what more
could I have done?
Nothing. But you must see we're not
well suited. We'd never be happy.
You won't be happy by the time
I'm finished, I promise.
I'm grateful...
So you should be!
I buy your filthy scandal
and keep it safe from prying eyes!
Why do the papers leave
you alone over Bates?
Why is nothing linked to the
great Earl of Grantham?!
I suppose you stopped it.
Threats, bribes, favours.
Yes, I stopped it.
Papa will be so thankful.
You don't think it holds now,
do you?
You don't think I'll save you
or him for one more day?
And you wonder why we wouldn't make
each other happy!
Mary, are you quite all right?
Here he is.
The man who can smile and smile
and be a villain.
Is she not to be trusted even
to get rid of me without your help?
I heard shouting.
Lavinia knew it, you know.
She knew you never loved her.
Don't you dare.
She said it once.
It was late. She was tired.
You two were locked together
in the corner of the room.
She said, 'If he could
just admit the truth
then all four of us
might have a chance.'
You liar!
I'm not a liar. No, I am many
things, but not that.
She regretted it, of course.
But she said it.
You bastard!
Stop this at once!
I presume you will be leaving
in the morning, Sir Richard.
What time shall I
order your car?
How smooth you are.
What a model
of manners and elegance.
I wonder if you'll be
quite so serene when the
papers are full of your
eldest daughter's exploits.
I shall do my best.
What on earth's the matter?
I'm leaving in the morning,
Lady Grantham.
I doubt we'll meet again.
Do you promise?
Sorry about the vase.
Don't be, don't be.
It was a wedding present
from a frightful aunt.
I have hated it for half a century!
Wait.
After last night's exhibition, I
rather hoped to escape unobserved.
I didn't want you to go
without saying goodbye.
Well then, goodbye.
I suppose you feel I've used you.
And I'm sorry if I have.
I'm sorry about Haxby,
about all of it.
I assume this is a plea
to stay my hand from punishment.
But I warn you, I'd feel no guilt
in exposing you.
My job is to sell newspapers.
Papa has suggested I go to New York
to wait it out.
So I'll be all right.
I just didn't want our final words
to be angry ones.
I loved you, you know.
More than you knew.
And much, much more
than you loved me.
Then I hope the next woman you love
deserves you more than I did.
Don't worry about Haxby.
I'll sell it at a profit.
I usually do.
He's still on at me to press
his case with the mistress.
He's very tenacious, I must say.
You know men.
And I know women too.
My Lord! My Lord!
What in heaven's name?
A telegram, my Lord.
Open it.
Thank God, he's been reprieved.
It's life imprisonment
but he's been reprieved.
Go and fetch Anna.
The Home Secretary finds
that many details
call into question the
case for premeditation.
The point is, he will not hang.
But it's still life imprisonment.
Don't dwell on that. Not now.
It's life, not death.
That's all we need to think about.
We've a task ahead of us, it's true.
Bates will live and he is innocent.
In time, we'll prove it
and he will be free.
I must go and see him.
Today. They'll let me, won't they?
I can't believe they won't. I'll
get Pratt to run you into York.
So that is the news.
It only remains for me
to add that we WILL be
holding the servants'
ball tonight after all.
Tonight? Are you serious?
Mrs Hughes thinks we can manage it.
I never thought they'd hang
an innocent man.
He wouldn't have been the first.
It's a relief. It is.
I don't mind saying it.
But he has to stay in prison?
Only until they prove
he didn't do it.
If you don't mind, we can worry
about that later.
Right now, we have a great deal
of work to do.
His Lordship means to work
with Mr Murray.
Will you stay at Downton now?
Of course. I'm sorry to let Lady
Mary down but I think I should.
There maybe some way I can help
them to overturn the conviction.
I don't know what I can do,
but there may be something.
I don't deserve you.
Because we will overturn it.
I won't rest until we have you out.
But it may take years.
That's if you ever manage it.
So there's one thing I must ask.
I can't have you grey-faced
and in perpetual mourning.
Promise me...
that you'll make friends.
Have fun.
Live life.
I'll try.
I promise.
Can I give you some whisky to
fortify you for the coming ordeal?
That's very kind. Is there anyone
I should dance with particularly?
Well, Cora opens it with Carson.
Not cousin Violet?
Not since my father died.
No. Mama ought to dance
with my valet but
we let it lapse while
Bates was here.
Perhaps Thomas will revive
the privilege.
He's certainly got the nerve.
Then I join in with Mrs Hughes.
So perhaps it
would be nice if you
were to partner O'Brien.
Crikey.
By the way, Mary told me
about Mr Swire.
At least I was with him.
And we'd made our peace.
I didn't deserve it.
I let Lavinia down.
You were ready to marry her, Matthew.
You would have kept your word.
You can't be blamed for feelings
beyond your control.
If Swire had any inkling of that,
he would have respected you for it.
Glug those drinks down,
we have to go in!
I gather Anna isn't gong to America.
No.
But of course, I'm glad for her.
Here he comes
to claim his prize.
My Ladyship, may I have the honour
of this dance?
Yes, it is a waltz.
I'm far too old
for that awful foxtrot.
What about the black bottom,
my Lady?
Just keep me upright.
Then we'll try to avoid it.
Daisy, I'm having trouble
understanding what you mean.
Are you saying you want to leave?
No, I don't want to leave
unless I have to.
But I want to move on.
I think I'm more than
a kitchen maid now.
I want to be a proper
assistant cook. I know I can be.
I've no objection
if the budget stretches to it.
I'll have to ask Mrs Hughes
and Her Ladyship.
I'll work for it, I promise.
Why couldn't you have spoken
of this sensibly the other night?
Instead of going off into a pet?!
Because I took the wrong advice.
I hope this isn't a practical joke.
It is a joke in a way, I'm afraid.
My dear, this... isn't what it seems.
Is there room for misinterpretation?
But I can promise...
Clearly, I have been managed
and steered by an expert hand.
Which I now see has not been yours.
Rosamund...
Don't. It's over.
Don't make yourself ridiculous.
Good advice. Why not marry her?
She'll more than cover any social
flaws with her resourcefulness.
Isn't that what I'm always saying?
You silly old whatnot.
There are no more trains tonight.
So you'll have to leave first thing.
Don't worry, we will.
Please forgive me but...
Damn!
Why? It's a lucky escape,
if you ask me.
That's true, of course.
I just can't stand it
when Mama is proved right.
Your Lordship, may I have a word?
Of course. How is Bates?
Relieved. Shocked.
Tired. Grateful.
I'm sure.
My Lord, I wonder if I might
withdraw my resignation.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Do you want to dance?
Why not?
How are your plans
for America going?
I'll book my crossing as soon
as I hear back from Grandmama.
Will you be gone long?
I don't know. I'll have to see.
Do you think we can go to bed?
I expect so.
I think we've done our duty. Mama's
gone home and so has Isobel.
The girls?
Edith's upstairs.
And the last time I looked,
Mary was dancing with Matthew.
Don't let's interfere with that.
I've written to Sybil.
Sent her your love.
I won't be kept away from
my first grandchild, Robert.
I don't know what you mean.
I didn't quarrel with her.
I gave my permission.
I didn't fight it.
But you wouldn't go to the wedding.
No.
It isn't what I wanted for her.
None of it is.
But this is what's happened
and we must accept it.
I want to go over there
and I want Sybil to come here.
And the chauffeur?
Him too.
It's been a happy day, Robert.
Let's end on a happy note.
Tired already?
A bit.
I was thinking about William.
He always loved the ball.
Miss O'Brien, Her Ladyship's
ready for bed.
I'm ever so glad Mr Bates
is going to be all right.
Well, he's alive.
I think we're quite a way
from all right.
Go on.
Are you pushing it?
No. Are you?
That doesn't make sense.
Yes, it does.
May they be happy.
With my love.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
I suppose a spirit wants
some couple to be happy.
You were moving it.
No, I wasn't. You were.
That was fun.
There will be a few thick heads
in the morning.
No doubt they think it's worth it.
You're really going to America.
Would Carlisle make your life
a nightmare if you stayed?
I couldn't tell you.
Maybe.
Even if he does let me go,
my story is still out there.
And always will be.
Would you stay?
If I asked you to.
Matthew, you don't mean that.
You know yourself we carry more luggage
than the porters at King's Cross!
And what about the late Mr Pamuk?
Won't he... resurrect himself
every time we argued?
No.
You mean you've forgiven me?
No, I haven't forgiven you.
Well, then.
I haven't forgiven you because...
I don't believe you need
my forgiveness.
You've lived your life
and I've lived mine.
And now it's time
we lived them together.
We've been on the edge of this
so many times, Matthew.
Please don't take me there again
unless you're sure.
I am sure.
And your vows to the memory
of Lavinia?
I was wrong.
I don't think she wants us
to be sad.
She was someone who never caused a
moment's sorrow in her whole life.
I agree.
Then will you?
You must say it properly.
I won't answer unless you...
kneel down and everything!
Lady Mary Crawley...
will you do me the honour
of becoming my wife?
Yes!
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.addic7ed.com
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.OpenSubtitles.org
www.tvsubtitles.net