Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Who will groan first when they
see it, Granny or Papa?
I should think they'll
howl at the moon in unison.
What in God's name is this?
Well I never!
Where did this come from?
I ordered it in London,
picked it up on the way back.
It's an AC.
Well, at least it's English.
Welcome back, my darling.
How was the honeymoon? My eyes
have been opened. Don't I know it!
Anna get back all right? Yes.
Who's that for? Why are you
doing it down here?
It's for Mr Matthew.
It was creased, I'm ironing it.
You're never looking after him?
What about Mr Molesley?
He's staying at Crawley House.
Why wasn't I asked?
Mr Carson thought it best. Did he?
I wonder how that came about?
If you're learning your job,
never open a shirt in a room
where it might be marked,
let alone put studs in it.
Do that in a dressing room
and nowhere else. Thank you.
Yes, you're always trying to be
so very helpful.
How did you enjoy the south
of France? It was lovely,
but almost too hot, even now.
It's a shame they close things
in the summer. I love the sun.
So we can see. You couldn't be in
Cannes in summer, it's unbearable.
I could. Just how long
is she here for?
Who knows? No guest
should be admitted
with no departure date settled.
You won't get any argument from me.
There's a hideous pile of post.
I've put it on the hall table.
Don't look at it tonight.
What have you been up to?
I've found myself a new occupation,
but Violet
doesn't think it's appropriate.
Can we talk about it afterwards?
Are there still forbidden subjects
in 1920? I can't believe this.
I speak of taste rather than law.
Well, it's not my taste.
What about you, Cora?
I agree with Mama.
Some subjects are not suitable
for every ear.
Oh, pas devant les domestiques.
Come on, my dear, Carson and Alfred
know more about life
than we ever will.
Can't we stop this? How?
She's like a runaway train.
Shall we go through?
What about poor old Strallan?
Have you seen him?
Why do you call him
poor or old? He's neither.
Isn't it dangerous to let
this Strallan nonsense simmer on?
To be fair, I don't think it's
coming from him. Ask him to end it.
He'll be more effective
than if we try.
Ooh, she ate it, then?
Never sure about Americans and offal.
She'll eat whatever you
put in front of her. What a gob.
Mr Carson was going to put a bag
over her head.
Oops. Mrs Levinson
knows you make fun of her
because she makes fun of you.
We're all square, then.
It's not drying properly,
the oven's not hot enough.
A bad workman
always blames his tools.
Are you busy? No. We're eating
in half an hour but it's all done.
Well, if you could spare a minute.
This is very good, you didn't open
it for me. Certainly I did.
To welcome you into this house
as my son.
I can't tell you
how glad it makes me.
I want us always to feel we can be
honest with each other.
Of course. Because Mary's told me
about your present difficulties.
Oh, she was right,
losing Downton will affect you both
more than anyone.
Has she told you about
the will of Lavinia's father?
Yes, your father told me
all about it,
but I cannot understand why so
much money was put into one company.
I couldn't agree more. Now we're
to be turned out of Downton.
Even Lloyd George can't want that.
I'm not sure he's a good example.
The point is have we overlooked
something,
some source of revenue
previously untapped?
If only we had some coal,
or gravel, or tin.
I can think of someone
who's got plenty of tin.
So you help women who have...
fallen over?
Not quite. Isabelle helps women who
have to degrade themselves
to survive.
There's a centre in York.
No addresses, please.
Alfred will make notes.
What do you do for these women?
First, we like to send them away...
to rest. I should think
they need it.
And then we try to find them
alternative employment.
The War destroyed many households,
thousands of bread winners died.
So you want me to contribute?
You don't have to give money
after every conversation. No?
Isn't that what the English expect
of rich Americans?
Why can't you benefit from the will?
You've done nothing wrong.
He didn't know I'd broken
his daughter's heart.
It was to reward my fidelity
when in fact I'd betrayed her.
If I kept that money, I'd be
no better than a common criminal.
I see.
If that's how you feel,
there's no more to be said.
I'm ever so sorry, my lord,
I thought you were out of here.
We should be. Please.
We're going now.
It's a lump, there's no point
dithering about that.
What are you going to do about it?
I don't know.
Tomorrow, you'll make an appointment
with the doctor and see what he says.
But what if it's...
If it is, and I'm not saying it is,
it's best to know now.
I suppose so.
Now, look, you'll not be alone for
a minute if you don't want to be,
but we have to get it seen to.
Then there's expense.
If you must pay money, better
to a doctor than an undertaker.
If that's an example of your bedside
manner, Mrs Patmore,
I think I'd sooner face it alone.
It seems shocking for Anna
to find me en deshabille.
I'm made of stout stuff, sir,
don't worry about that.
Are you seeing Bates today?
I am, and I can't wait.
Give him our best wishes.
It still seems odd
to be found in your bed.
But very nice.
Oh, as nice as nice can be.
I'm going to see Jarvis today
and find out what houses
are available. Do you have to?
These are our last days here. I
thought something might've turned up
while we were away
but it seems it hasn't.
Would you rather wait till we have
to go and find a new house then?
After all, darling, you're the one
who's pushing us out.
Not for me, thank you.
But Mary's only just got back
from honeymoon.
It's her family time. But you are...
Stop saying I'm family when I'm not.
I'll be there
for the big dinner next week.
What is it? I know
you don't mean to hurt me, but...
Of course I don't. That's
the last thing I'd wish to do.
Then why do you shove me away?
I don't want to, not at all, but...
If you're going to talk about your
wretched arm again, I won't listen.
It's not just my arm.
I'm too old for you.
You need a young chap
with his life ahead of him.
Your life's ahead of you. If you
knew how much I want to believe that.
Then it's settled.
You're not going
to push me away any more
and you are coming for dinner
tonight. That's all there is to it.
How did you get on with Vera's book?
I had a few answers
waiting for me when I got back
and two returned "address unknown".
Who from? Let me see, one was
a Mr Harlip, I think,
and the other was Mrs Bartlett.
He doesn't matter, he was a cousin
in the north, she never saw him,
but Mrs Bartlett's a shame.
She lived on the corner, she
was very friendly. I'll find her.
Tell me about France.
Did you eat frog's legs
and dance the can-can?
No, but I bought a garter.
You've had no other symptoms?
Not that I'm aware of.
You're not feeling ill or tired?
I can't swear to not feeling tired
but nothing out of the ordinary.
Very well.
I'm going to conduct
a preliminary examination.
Do you mind if I stay?
I should prefer it.
What have you got there?
Mr Matthew's tailcoat.
What do you think that is?
Hard to say.
I've tried everything
but I can't shift it.
I'll give you a tip, if you like.
Would you, really? Yeah.
Keep it to yourself, don't want
to give away all my secrets.
Oh, there you are, my dear.
Good morning, Granny.
I've been looking for you.
Now I want to know if we're serious,
about getting that woman, about
asking your other grandmother
to come to our aid.
She's made of money
and there's only Mama and Uncle
Harold to share it when she's gone.
We can't wait that long,
she'll bury us all.
No, we must act now.
We must make her feel
it is her duty to save Downton.
But how? What can we do?
Get her to sense its value,
its vital role in the area.
You're her granddaughter.
This will be your house
if it survives.
Surely you can make something
of that if she has a heart at all.
We'll come for tea this afternoon.
Then we can begin.
There are several stages to go
through before a cause for despair.
What stages? When you come back
in a day or two,
I'll remove fluid from the cyst.
With luck it'll be clear
and that will be that.
How will you do it? With a syringe.
Will it hurt? Since he has to do
it, whether it hurts or not,
there's no point to that question.
What I want to know is what happens
if the fluid is not clear?
It'll be sent away for analysis.
Because it may be... cancer?
It may be cancer
but I'm fairly certain it is not.
There you are. It's very, very
unlikely, isn't it, Doctor?
If the doctor treats me
like an adult,
why do insist on
treating me like a child?
Does this seem slow to you?
Not really.
Mrs Levinson's going to the
Dower House with the others for tea.
I think he likes me.
He's being friendly, that's all.
Are you all right? You seem to have
been slaving away for hours.
I want to be up to date
before I get back to the office.
Anything from Mr Swire's lawyer?
You can read it if you like.
So you are definitely
Reggie's heir?
Looks like it, but if they have
to get a death certificate
out of the Indian authorities, it
won't be settled by Tuesday. Good.
Why is it good? The delay may give
you time to change your mind.
Stop punishing me, Mary, please.
If I accepted the legacy, I'd take
money under false pretences.
I'd be stealing. Your father
understands now why can't you?
He doesn't understand,
he just doesn't want to beg.
Anyway, I'm off to Granny's for tea.
See you later.
I do love you so terribly much.
Yes, I know you do.
So what's Harold doing now?
His idee fixe is yachts.
Bigger yachts, faster yachts.
Something with yachts.
Is he happy? He's much
too busy to find out.
It always seems so strange to me
that Cora has a brother. Why?
If there's a boy, the daughters
don't get anything.
There's no such thing as
an English heiress with a brother.
Why do we never see him?
Harold hates to leave America.
Curious. He hates to leave America.
I should hate to go there.
You don't mean that, Granny,
when we're both so drawn to America.
Indeed, indeed we are.
Never more than now,
when the bond between the Crawleys
and Levinsons is so strong.
That's nice, if you mean it, Mama.
I do.
It is marvellous the way
our families support each other.
You mean you needed the Levinson
cash to keep the Crawleys on top?
I'm not sure we'd put it that way.
I'm quite sure we would not.
But I hope you feel Mama's fortune
has been well spent in shoring up
an ancient family. Hm.
You gotta spend it on something!
What happened here? I...
I just...
You just what? There was a mark.
I know there was a mark,
but you didn't need to burn it away.
What have you done?
I'll go down in my dinner jacket,
send it to my tailor in the morning.
Come on, nobody's died,
just find the dinner jacket.
There don't seem to be any glasses
for the pudding wine.
Are they having one tonight?
It's on the menus.
I don't write them
for my own amusement. I dare say not.
I am trying, and so far failing,
to persuade his lordship to bring
the staff levels back up to snuff,
but until he does it is vital
that you pull your weight.
Newport's not a jungle, not at all,
but it is a little less formal.
Matthew obviously wants you to feel
at home in his play clothes.
Don't blame me. Alfred and I
had a disaster earlier.
What happened? He managed
to burn a hole in my tails.
Don't worry, it can be mended.
Careful, Carson.
I beg your pardon, my lord.
I like dinner jackets, sometimes
it's nice to be informal.
Especially when a couple is alone.
People like us should lead the fight
to keep tradition going.
If you mean we can never change,
I can't agree. Nor me.
Accepting change is as important
as defending the past.
The role of houses like Downton
is to protect tradition.
That's why they're so important
to maintain. Don't you agree?
We must do everything in our power
to keep Downton going. Sure,
if you think it's worth it. Who's
coming to dinner next week?
Locals. We thought you'd like to see
Downton on parade.
That's right. I'm glad
we've planned a dinner.
We can show you
the real point of Downton.
I don't know what to say, Mr Carson.
What's going on here? Alfred has
embarrassed the family.
He forced Mr Matthew to appear
downstairs improperly dressed.
You make it sound quite exciting.
I will not tolerate vulgarity.
I'm sure Alfred didn't mean to. Hm.
I asked Thomas... Hey, what's this?
The stuff you gave me
burned a hole in the tails.
I gave you some soda crystals.
If you use them wrongly,
it's not my fault.
This is what comes of making him run
before he could walk.
If you want me to stay away
from her, I will.
I know it sounds harsh.
Please, I understand completely.
Edith's your daughter, you don't
want her seeing an old cripple.
Now you're the one who's harsh.
The trouble is
she calls round regularly.
I can hardly ask her
not to be admitted.
I suppose I could write to her.
I hope you won't feel
we can't be friends after this.
Let's leave it for a while. I'll
duck out of the dinner next week.
It might be best. Thank you.
That's the one you should've taken,
soda crystals.
But he didn't give me that,
he pointed to this one. I promise.
You don't have to promise,
I believe you.
So you think he's not ready?
He's just a lad, my lord.
He can see to the odd visitor,
but permanent valet to Mr Matthew?
It's too much. I'm pretty sure Mr
Crawley'd rather manage on his own.
They wouldn't like that
downstairs, my lord.
I was afraid you'd say that.
So what would you suggest?
Ask Mr Molesley to join us.
It'd be kinder to Alfred
in the long run,
kinder than asking
more than he can give.
How is that poor footman? I thought
Carson would eat him alive.
Very glum. To be honest,
he has been a clot.
I'll have to send the coat to London.
Get it done quickly.
This dinner has to be
the grandest of the grand.
What do you hope to show her?
Why Downton matters,
why it mustn't fall apart.
Hasn't Cora had her share
of Levinson gold?
What's left is headed for your uncle.
He's as rich as Croesus as it is.
So you mean to fleece her? Since you
could get us out of this hole,
I won't take any criticism,
thank you.
Will she do it? Granny
will make her or die in the attempt.
Now stop talking and kiss me
before I get cross.
You heard him,
you'll know at once.
I wish you could get
those maids under control.
They've broken one of the serving
dishes this time.
We're short of a footman, a kitchen
maid and one house maid at least,
that's if Anna's to be a proper
lady's maid, what Lady Mary wants.
Naturally. She likes things
done properly.
We can't do things properly until
his lordship allows us the staff
or until you and
the blessed Lady Mary
come down from that cloud
and join the human race!
I can only suppose
you are over-tired. Good night.
You see, she...
Good night, Mr Carson.
We will discuss the dinner
in the morning.
Hm.
And no, Mrs Patmore,
you may not tell him.
Oh. Have you finished
with Mr Matthew?
I have. He's in the dining room.
You won't need
to attend to him again, Mr Molesley
is coming up from the village.
Has Mr Matthew complained?
It's not your fault,
we've hurried you along too fast.
You mustn't feel badly.
This is Thomas's doing,
but don't you fret,
I'll make him sorry.
I'm on your side.
I'm glad somebody is.
No Mary? She's a married woman now
so she can have breakfast in bed.
Hm. I'm sorry about your tails.
Carson's sending them up
on the London train this morning.
They'll have to put a new panel in.
We thought we'd get Molesley
to come and look after you.
He knows your ways.
I'm perfectly happy...
I think it best if he comes. I must
talk to you about the staff we need.
Not now, Carson. Send for Molesley
if Mrs Crawley has no objection.
Edith?
Oh, Papa, how could you?
Crawley, do you know what that was?
I'm afraid I probably do.
I'm sorry but enough
of my father's money
has already been poured into Downton.
Why should Harold lose half
his inheritance for our folly?
So it's all Papa's fault? It isn't
my mother's or brother's.
I don't see why they should pay
for it. We'll still ask.
What are you so afraid of? If we
sell, we move to a smaller house
and a more modest estate.
We don't have to go down the mine.
You don't understand. Mary, a lot
of people live in smaller houses
than they used to. Which shows
you're American and I'm English.
I shall be Countess of Grantham
one day and the Countess of Grantham
lives at Downton Abbey.
'What job might you be suited to?'
We're not here to give you food, we
want you to find your place in life.
Do you want to speak to me?
Yes, Mrs Crawley, I do.
Have you come for our help?
You're very welcome if you have.
Wait a minute, I know you.
You were the maid who brought
your child
into the dining room at Downton.
Sorry, this has been a mistake.
I thought I was ready to ask you
but I'm not. I'm not ready.
Ask me what?
I'm sorry to keep you
waiting, ladies.
It's not quite as simple.
Oh, my God! Mrs Patmore, will you
please leave the hysteria to me?
I'm afraid the test
was inconclusive.
I had hoped the fluid from the cyst
would be clear but there's blood,
not enough to confirm the presence
of cancer but too much
to exclude it.
So what happens now?
I send it away for analysis
and this stage will take some time.
How much time?
Anything up to two months.
Oh, my...
Until then, try
to take it more easy.
Sit down and put
your feet up if you can.
Chance'd be a fine thing.
Would you like me to say something
to Lady Grantham?
No, thank you, Doctor, I'll speak
to her myself if I need to.
Thank you.
My darling girl, what's this?
I think you know, since you asked
Sir Anthony to write.
Edith, you understand I only want
what's best for you.
And you're the judge of that?
In this.
Sybil marries a chauffeur
and you welcome him here,
but when I love a gentleman, you
cast him out. She has a point.
Strallan is certainly a gentleman.
Besides which he has a house,
he has money, a title, everything
that you care about.
You make me sound very shallow.
Aren't you
when you make me give him up
because he has a bad arm?
He's quarter of a century too old.
Did she tell you that?
Your daughter is sad and lonely.
Now I don't mean to interfere...
Don't you?
If you ban him from Downton
I'll only go to his house.
I don't believe he'd see you.
I'll wait outside until he does.
How can you not like him
because of his age
when almost every man
we grew up with is dead?
Do you want me to spend my
life alone? I do like him very much.
So do I, Papa. So do I.
Please, ask him back.
He writes he's not coming
to Mama's dinner. Please make him.
Please, please, please.
Oh, all right, then.
I found Mrs Bartlett.
I wrote back to the tenant
of the house explaining
and they sent me
a forwarding address.
I don't know why they didn't before.
But it doesn't mean
she'll talk to you. Why not?
Audrey Bartlett was the nearest
thing Vera had to a friend.
That's why I want to meet her.
She won't see the real Anna Bates.
She's doesn't have to like me.
I need her to be honest.
I'm going to write
and ask for a meeting.
I can get to London
and back in a day.
She won't agree.
I've the rent from the house,
I can make it worth her while.
Why do you think Vera
didn't go and see her instead
of sending that letter? Eh?
When Vera was frightened
about your visit
she wrote that letter saying how
scared she was instead of seeing her.
Maybe she did both.
So...
what's the news at home?
I shouldn't tell you, really.
I haven't told any of the others.
It's breaking the code
of a lady's maid.
His lordship's in trouble.
It seems he may have to sell.
What? Sell Downton?
That makes me sad.
I wouldn't have thought much could
touch me in here, but that does.
It hasn't come. They promised
and promised and I thought
it was sure to be on the 7 o'clock
but it's not.
I'll just have to wear a black tie.
But Lady Mary, surely...
These things don't matter as much
as they did, Lady Mary knows that.
Thank you. I know I'm early...
Granny, come and see
what we've done. Oh.
What do you think?
Nothing succeeds like excess.
When shall we tackle her?
After dinner.
We'll get her on her own. She
wouldn't want to see all this go,
now it's for her granddaughter.
Never mistake a wish for
a certainty. Let's hope she won't.
Mrs Patmore. What is it now?
It's smoking, the range.
The wind's in the wrong direction,
rake it through.
Where's Alfred?!
In the servants' hall.
Where are they? His what?
His bloody evening shirts!
Where have you put them? I haven't
touched them. Why would I?
Have you done this? Why would I
know anything about his shirts?
When I find out... Keep your
histrionics to yourself. Hurry up.
Her ladyship's in the drawing room.
His lordship's not even dressed?
You can't have lost them all.
I haven't lost any of them.
They've been taken
by someone, stolen.
Why would they do that?
To get at me.
Are you not popular downstairs?
I wouldn't say that, my lord,
but you know how people can be.
They like a little joke.
This is quite unacceptable.
If you uncover the culprit,
refer them to me,
but for now what are we going to do?
Good evening, Sir John.
It can't be going out. There must be
a block in the flue.
The dinner's not cooked,
we haven't put in the souffles.
There'll be no souffles tonight.
What on earth is going on?
We've 20 lords and ladies
in the drawing room
waiting for dinner and we've got
no dinner to give them. Oh, my God.
Why are you not in white tie?
I'm afraid they never sent
my tails back.
You are not in white tie, either.
What have you come as?
I'm sorry, Thomas has lost my
dress shirts. Why is he still here?
I thought you gave him his marching
orders. I had.
My dear mother-in-law intervened.
I've a good mind to tell her...
No, she must have it
all her own way tonight.
You two are dressed for a barbecue.
I feel like a Chicago bootlegger.
That sounds almost
as peculiar as you look.
Come quickly. What is it?
The oven's broken down.
It can't have. What does that mean?
It means we have no food.
Oh.
Funny clothes and no food.
Should be quite an evening.
Thank you, Mother.
Nothing's cooked
and nothing's going to be cooked.
But surely...
Shall we tell them to go home?
No, they've come for a party,
we'll give them a party.
Clear the table,
go down to the larders,
bring up bread, fruit, cheese,
chicken, ham.
We're going to have
an indoor picnic.
They're going to eat whatever
they want, wherever they want.
Are you quite sure, madam?
It's not how we do it.
How you used to do it.
It might be fun. I agree.
We'll all pull together
and it'll be great fun. Yes!
I know what we need.
Does anyone play the piano?
This is so not
what we wanted it to be.
If it's the end of your undignified
campaign, I won't be sorry.
We can't just give up.
Certainly not.
Do you think I might have a drink?
Oh, I'm so sorry,
I thought you were a waiter.
Slice that finely, fetch some
parsley, cut the dry bits off.
Can I lend a hand?
I don't mind helping.
I think it's good to do other things
sometimes. I know you do.
There's not much left of this.
Cut it in squares, put it with ham.
You're very smart
in your valet's outfit.
Alfred, check the meat larder,
bring anything back you think
a human being could swallow.
Chop, chop, Mrs Hughes. We can rest
later but not yet. Mr Carson...
Mr Carson's right,
there's not a minute to lose.
Psst!
Do you want to know a secret?
The shirts Thomas thinks he stole...
I saw who took them
and I know where they are.
Who did take them?
Never mind that,
but I followed. I'll show you
if you want.
Why are you being so nice to me?
Because I like you. And you can
say it, just like that?
I'm an American, Alfred,
and this is 1920.
Time to live a little.
I thought you was trying to find
something about for Mrs Levinson.
Find out what when she reads them
like the palm of her hand?
She won't help, you know?
Help with what?
Never mind. Just kiss me again.
Now, all of you find whatever it is
that you want to eat
and take it wherever
you want to sit.
Anywhere? Anywhere.
If you have ever wanted to explore
Downton, this is your chance.
I'm sorry if it's all a bit casual.
It's exciting.
I feel like the bright young people
they write about.
Thank you, Lady Mellendorf.
Cheer up, she won't be here forever.
How much damage will be done
before she goes?
♪ Let me call you "Sweetheart"
♪ I'm in love with you
♪ Let me hear you whisper
♪ That you love me too
♪ Keep the love-light glowing
♪ In your eyes so true
♪ Let me call you "Sweetheart"
♪ I'm in love
♪ With
♪ You ♪
Is there anything for our supper?
I've taken a veal and egg pie.
Oh, I wish you'd let me talk
to Mr Carson.
I don't want to be a sick woman in
his eyes for the next two months,
or a dying one in the months
to come after that.
Shh. I know it'll be all right.
No, you don't,
but I appreciate the sentiment.
Are you sure you won't wake up
in ten years
and wonder why you're tied
to this crippled codger?
Only if you keep talking like that.
Do you know how much you mean to me?
You have given me back my life.
That's more like it.
You won't wait? To give you
the chance to change your mind?
Don't worry, I can get it
organised in a month.
Shall we tell them tonight?
No, no, I'll come back
in the morning.
Can I ask you something? Why do you
like that American girl?
Steady. Who says I do? Don't you?
I suppose I do. And it doesn't
matter that she's fast
or that you won't see her again
after she's gone home?
She made me feel good about myself
for the first time here. Alfred!
Hurry up, I need you
to take around the claret.
Won't they spill it on the floor?
If you ask me, we are staring
into the chaos of Gomorrah,
but we have to give them more wine
and you are going to help.
What's that? I have to take it
upstairs for his lordship.
Well, be quick about it.
I'll help you any way I can.
Thank heavens.
It seems our family owes Downton's
survival
to the Levinsons not once but twice.
No. I'm so sorry,
but you've misunderstood me.
I cannot rescue Downton.
It's a shame if it has to go,
but I can't. But why not?
Because your grandpa
tied the money down.
He felt the Crawley family
had quite enough.
But you said you'd help us.
I can entertain all of you
in Newport and in New York
and I can add to Cora's dress
allowance, but that's all.
My income is generous
but I cannot touch the capital.
Besides, Mary,
the world has changed.
These houses were built
for another age.
Are you sure you want to continue
with the bother of it all?
Quite sure. If I knew I was going to
lose it, I'd look on the sunny side.
Both of our husbands tied the money
up tight before they were taken.
Lord Grantham wasn't taken.
He died.
I suppose it's scraps
for the servants tonight?
Mrs Patmore's kept something by.
Who put them back?
What? The shirts,
who put them back?
They're back? You mean you
overlooked them in the first place.
Don't tell me what I mean.
I'm warning you. You sound like Tom
Mix in a Wild-West picture show!
Stop warning me and go lay out
his lordship's pyjamas.
What are you laughing at? Those
missing shirts went for a walk
and now they've come home.
Really? Have they?
You didn't see nothing. I agree.
Cos if you did I'll cut ya.
Oh!
Don't ever threaten me.
I forgot I was sharing a cell
with a murderer.
Don't forget it again.
This evening has made me homesick
for America.
It's time to go.
I don't suppose you want some whisky
to take to bed?
Oh, but I'd love one. No water.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I can't help you
keep Downton, Robert.
That's what Mary wanted.
Ah.
I thought there was something.
You know, the way
to deal with the world today
is not to ignore it. If you do
you'll just get hurt.
Sometimes, I feel like a creature
in the wilds
whose natural habitat
is gradually being destroyed.
Some animals adapt
to new surroundings.
It seems a better choice
than extinction.
I don't think it is a choice.
I think it's what's in you.
Let's hope that what's in you will
carry you through these times
to a safer shore.
Is everything all right?
Certainly.
Was there something you wanted?
The kitchen managed well tonight
in difficult circumstances.
His lordship sent his thanks.
Was the evening a success?
The odd thing is I think it was.
For me, everyone sprawled
on the floor
eating like beaters at a break
in the shooting isn't a party,
it's a works outing.
Where's the style, Mrs Hughes?
Where's the show?
Perhaps people are tired
of style and show.
Well, in my opinion,
to misquote Dr Johnson,
if you're tired of style,
you are tired of life.
Hm. Good night, Mr Carson.
You'd say if anything
was wrong, wouldn't you?
I know I've been a bit crabby,
but I am on your side.
Thank you for that.
You've just missed an admirer.
Mr Carson says you did well tonight.
Oh. Did you tell him?
No.
What is there to tell?
One day I will die.
And so will he. And you.
And every one of us under this roof.
You must put these things
in proportion, Mrs Patmore,
and I think I can do that now.
'Something happening
in this house is about me.'
'Strallan is
the traditional choice.'
Edith is beginning her life
as an old man's drudge.
This is the moment you receive
a huge fortune to save Downton
and you give it away. I hope
you can understand... I'm trying.
Downton Place. Where am I to go?
We still own the village.
I could open a shop.
Fashionably late is one thing.
So it is Cancer? Don't say anything,
'she'd hate to think
the doctor told you.'
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.podnapisi.net
www.tvsubtitles.net