Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Is there any news of Sybil?
She's still not coming.
She insists they can't afford it.
Mr Travis, can we move forward?
If I could just ask you to
come down the aisle again?
Can we get the troops organised?
That means me.
It seems rather hard on poor old
Travis when he's doing all the work,
but the Archbishop gets the glory.
Papa was the one who wanted
a prince of the church.
I'd have settled for Travis.
Is there really no way we can get
Sybil over? It seems ridiculous.
On the contrary, it's a relief.
Branson is still an object
of fascination for the county.
We'll ask him here
when we can prepare the servants
and manage it gently.
He's making a problem
where none exists.
No-one could care less whether
Branson's at the wedding or not.
You must think country life
more exciting than it is
if you imagine people don't care
when an earl's daughter runs off
with the chauffeur.
She has run off with the chauffeur
and they'll have to get used to it.
Mr Travis, are we ready?
Any moment, Your Grace. Any moment.
Can we... Please.
That treacle tart just hit the spot.
Thank you, Mrs Patmore.
So, Mrs Hughes and Anna
are getting the place ready to let?
That is the plan.
I'm surprised Anna held on
to that house.
I thought they'd confiscated
the profits of murder.
Mr Bates had the wisdom to transfer
it to her before the trial.
I don't think I'd have allowed it.
Then we must be grateful
you were not the presiding judge.
I still think it's funny, given
that he's a convicted murderer.
May I remind you, Mr Barrow, that in
this house Mr Bates is a wronged man
seeking justice. If you have
any problems with that definition,
I suggest you eat in the yard.
I suppose you agree with Robert.
Not for the first time,
you suppose wrongly.
The family must never
be a topic of conversation.
I'm afraid Sybil's already made
the Crawleys a permanent topic.
All the more reason.
If we can show the county
he can behave normally,
they will soon lose interest in him.
And I shall make sure
he behaves normally
because I shall hold his hand
on the radiator until he does.
I don't know this young man
aside from 'Good morning'
and 'Good night',
but he strikes me as a very
interesting addition to the family.
Oh, here we go. And why should
he be normal as you call it?
I say he should come here
and fight his corner.
I like a man of strong beliefs.
I think I'll send them the money.
Please don't. Robert's expressly
forbidden it. He'd be furious.
But it can't be as bad as...
Look, I'll come and see you,
tomorrow.
No, I insist.
Right. Goodbye.
Papa... What's the matter?
Nothing's the matter.
What should be the matter?
How was London?
We got it all done.
But I couldn't have managed
without my helper. Have you eaten?
We had a bite on the train.
Well, sit down anyway.
Have a cup of tea.
I'll start on the final list
for the wedding tomorrow morning.
I've got the last of the wine
deliveries coming on Tuesday.
How will you manage
without a footman? I agree.
But I haven't time to find one now.
I've had a letter from my sister
asking after a job for her son and...
Miss O'Brien, we are about to host
a society wedding.
I have no time for training
young hobbledehoys.
Her ladyship is ringing.
Well, I don't see why not.
I'll ask his lordship when...
There you are.
So I'll ask you now.
Ask me what?
Carson's in need of a footman
and O'Brien has a candidate.
Alfred. Alfred Nugent, my lord.
He's a good worker.
I think it sounds perfect.
Robert? Whatever you say. My dear,
I have to go up to London tomorrow.
I'll be catching the early train.
That's very sudden.
Do you want them to open the house?
No, I'll come straight back.
What are you going for?
It's nothing to bother you with.
It's all there, every entry.
Where did you find the book?
Behind the bureau.
We moved it out to clean
and there it was.
Vera must have dropped it
or something.
So what do you want me to do?
Make notes on all the names.
Close friend, relation.
Workmate, tradesman, and so on.
Then I'll copy those and I'll send
them with the book to Mr Murray.
Haven't you anything better to do?
I have not.
Because I'd rather work to get you
free than dine with the King
at Buckingham Palace.
So what news have you got?
What news could I have in here?
Oh, I've acquired a new cellmate.
To be honest,
I'm not sure about him.
Well, just remember
what my mother used to say.
Never make an enemy by accident.
Now, do you think you can get the
notes done before my next visit?
I don't see what can come of it.
Probably nothing.
And my next idea will probably lead
to nothing.
And the next, and the next.
But one day something will occur
to us.
And we'll follow it up.
And the case against you
will crumble.
Do you never doubt?
For just one minute.
I wouldn't blame you.
No.
I don't doubt that the sun will rise
in the east either.
You're too tall to be a footman.
No footman
should be over six foot one.
That can't be, can it,
since he's already been taken on?
Well, what have you done?
I was a hotel waiter after I was
discharged from the army.
But they've cut back.
I think that shows real initiative.
I suppose he can speak for himself.
Why? Is he on trial?
This isn't an interview, is it?
Not when he's already got the job.
No, it is not an interview,
Miss O'Brien,
but he is on trial
and if he cannot match our standards,
he will be found guilty.
I mean to try, Mr Carson.
As long as you do.
Right, go upstairs
and get settled in.
Your aunt will hopefully
find you a livery that fits.
Just at the start, so we've a place
to sleep after the honeymoon.
You can't object to that.
No, it's nice of them.
Though I doubt
I'll get used to taking you to bed
with your father watching.
He's so relieved we're getting
married, he wouldn't mind
if you carried me up naked.
Careful. I might try it.
I don't want to move to London
or anything.
I'm not kicking against the traces.
Just testing their strengths.
I want us to get to know each other.
To learn about who we both are,
without everybody being there.
Well, it's quite a big house.
It's a lovely house.
It's your home
and I want it to be my home too.
Just not quite yet.
Chancery Lane.
Yes, sir.
I've spoken to Frobisher and Curran
and, since I am a trustee,
should the estate ever need one,
we felt I ought to be the one
to tell you.
You make it sound very serious.
I'm expressing myself badly
if you think it is not serious.
Why did we invest so much?
Lord Grantham,
it was you who insisted we should.
If you remember,
we advised against it.
But war would mean a huge expansion
of railways everywhere.
Every forecast was certain.
Rail shares were bound
to make a fortune.
Many did.
But your principal holding,
which was very large indeed,
was in
the Canadian Grand Trunk Line.
It was the main railway in British
North America, for God's sake.
It wasn't just me.
Everyone said we couldn't lose.
We knew hard times were coming
for estates like Downton
and this investment would make it
safe for the rest of time.
Charles Hays
was the presiding genius
and since he died,
the management has not...
The fact is, the company
is about to be declared bankrupt.
And the line will be absorbed
into the Canadian National Railways
scheme.
Are you really telling me
that all the money has gone?
I'm afraid so.
The lion's share of Cora's fortune?
I won't give in, Murray.
I've sacrificed too much to Downton
to give in now.
I refuse to be the failure,
the earl who dropped the torch
and let the flame go out.
I hate to state the obvious,
but if there's not enough money
to run it...
Downton must go.
Unless you break it up
and sell it off piecemeal.
I couldn't do that. I have a duty
beyond saving my own skin.
The estate must be a major employer
and support the house
or there's no point to it.
To any of it.
Morning.
Lady Edith...
Hello.
What are you doing here? I'm meeting
a train, but I'm too early. Oh.
Oh. I mustn't hold you up.
I'm not doing anything.
I thought I'd get away
from wedding panic.
Don't you like weddings?
Don't be silly. Of course I do.
Only I've talked of clothes
and flowers and food and guests
until I'm blue in the face.
Yes, weddings can be reminders
of one's loneliness, can't they?
Sorry. I don't know why I said that.
So, how's it going?
Is your grandmother coming over
from New York for it? She is.
And Sybil... Is she here yet?
As a matter of fact, she wasn't
coming. But I think she is now.
Mary had a letter this morning.
Papa doesn't know yet.
He will be pleased.
I do hope so.
So you'll live at the big house
when you're back from honeymoon?
Not live. Stay.
We'll stay there until we decide
where to go.
It'll be on the estate,
I should think, or in the village.
Not here?
No.
But I shall expect you and Mrs Bird
to look after Mrs Crawley.
You'll not be taking me with you,
sir?
Only I thought you'd be needing
a proper valet, once you're married.
I've always thought of you as
a butler who helps out as a valet...
not the other way round.
I'd be happy to be a valet, sir.
Especially in the big house. We
won't be at the big house for long.
To be honest, Molesley, I want to
live more simply after the wedding.
And besides,
Mother absolutely relies on you.
Well, that's very nice to hear, sir.
Thank you.
You must be exhausted, my lord.
You can't have spent
more than two hours in London.
It was sufficient. The new footman
arrived while you were gone.
What?
Yes, he got the cable this morning
and came straight over.
Very eager.
And very tall.
But when did...
Never mind.
Did you know about the new footman?
Of course. He's already here.
Why did no-one tell me?
What do you mean?
We talked about it last night.
In my room.
Well, nobody else must be taken on.
Absolutely no-one.
Until things are settled.
What things?
How's the wedding going?
I suppose it's costing the earth?
Mary was never going to marry
on the cheap.
Oh, no.
Nothing must be done on the cheap.
I feel quite nervous.
Don't be.
You've got the skill
and you've got the willingness.
But he hasn't got the experience.
He's right.
Pay no attention. You've a nice
manner. You're not vain like Thomas.
They'll like that.
What's the matter with you?
I'm fed up.
They promised me promotion. She said
they'd get a new kitchen maid
and I'd be Mrs Patmore's assistant.
If they promised,
you should withdraw your services.
What do you mean? Like go on strike?
But don't say I put you up to it.
But what was in the letter?
Just that Sybil's coming after all.
She'll be here on Wednesday
for dinner.
Will she be coming alone?
Don't make trouble, Mother.
Can I do it?
If you wish, my lady. Of course.
Are you really that tall?
Yes, my lady.
I thought you might have been
walking on stilts.
When does Grandmama arrive?
She gets into Liverpool on the 15th
- the day before the wedding
I'm so looking forward
to seeing your mother again.
When I'm with her I'm reminded
of the virtues of the English.
But isn't she American?
Exactly.
Can I help myself?
You want to as well, my lord?
To be honest, I think you'll find
that we all do it as well.
What do you think you're doing?
You're not in a hotel now.
Did you train in a hotel?
I did, ma'am.
That will be useful.
Won't it, Carson?
Are you all set for the wedding?
Of course he is.
Carson's motto is, 'Be prepared.'
I'm afraid Baden-Powell
has stolen it.
But you have all the help you need?
Well, I wouldn't fight the idea
of a second footman, my lady.
I sometimes think it's time we lived
in a simpler way.
I agree. Much cattle, much care.
Always supposing we have the choice.
Oh, don't say that.
It's our job to provide employment.
An aristocrat with no servants
is as much use to the county
as a glass hammer!
I knew this would happen. Typical.
What's typical?
That I'd wind up looking after
Mr Matthew. That's all I need.
He hasn't thought it through.
I'm sorry to say, but he hasn't.
Are you worried for your job,
Mr Molesley?
Me? Oh, heavens, no.
No, no, no, I'm essential
to Mrs Crawley. She relies on me.
That's what he said.
Essential.
Oh, yes, we're all essential.
Until we get sacked.
How was it?
Alfred was confused.
He thought he'd been transported
to the Hotel Metropole.
Cheer up. You'll get the hang of it.
Will I?
Oh, you're still here, Mr Molesley.
I know. I only walked over
for a cup of tea and a chat.
But I've outstayed my welcome.
Nonsense.
Why not have a bite with us?
They won't be leaving
for a half hour or more.
No, I'd better get back.
I wouldn't want them to get home
and me not be there to let them in.
No, you wouldn't.
Not when you're essential.
Then why is he coming all the way
here?
Why not say it on the telephone?
I have no idea.
If Mr Swire's lawyer
wants to see you and it's urgent,
it means he's left you something.
I doubt it.
I would have heard long before this.
Anyway, I hope not.
Why?
Matthew. Do come on.
The chauffeur's freezing to death
and so am I.
Are you looking forward
to the wedding?
What do you think?
I'm looking forward
to all sorts of things.
Don't make me blush.
Matthew!
Dearest Papa.
Tell me, did you send the money?
Please say yes.
What money?
Hello, Tom.
Welcome to Downton.
I hope I am welcome, your ladyship.
Of course.
Alfred, would you take the luggage
for Mr Branson?
There's tea in the library.
Thank you.
Hello, Mr Carson.
Is that Mr Charkham I saw leaving?
Yes.
He said to make his apologies.
He was late for his train.
What did he have to say for himself?
I don't know where to start.
Basically, it seems that Reggie Swire
did not wish to divide his fortune.
So when Lavinia died, he made a new
will with a list of three heirs,
of which I was the third.
Why didn't the first name succeed?
He died before Reggie.
In the same epidemic
that killed Lavinia.
But at first they thought that the
second heir, a Mr Clive Pullbrook,
would be easy to trace.
How much money are we talking about?
A lot.
A huge amount. I had no idea.
You could never have told it
from Reggie's way of life.
Lucky Mr Pullbrook.
This is it.
Some time before Reggie's death,
Pullbrook travelled to the East,
to India, to some tea plantations
he owned there.
And?
He's never been heard of since.
They've made enquiries. They've sent
an agent out to visit his property.
There's no sign of him.
I'm sorry. I won't. And that's flat.
Then you'll have to do it,
Mr Carson.
I'm not dressing a chauffeur.
He is not a chauffeur now.
Anyway, you don't have to dress him,
just see he's got everything
he needs.
I'm not often as one with Mr Barrow,
but no.
Then Alfred must do it.
Alfred?
He wouldn't know what to do
beyond collecting dirty shoes.
Well, he'll have to learn.
Is it an Irish tradition?
What?
She means not changing.
Of course it isn't, Granny.
It might have been.
You don't change on the first night
of a voyage.
No, my lady,
I don't own a set of tails
or a dinner jacket either.
I wouldn't get any use out of them.
Well, I hope you own a morning coat
since you're here for a wedding.
No, I'm afraid I don't. We live
a different kind of life, Papa.
Obviously.
Could you lower it a bit, please,
Mr Carson?
You should buy a Downton wardrobe
and leave it here.
Then you won't have to pack
when you come. What a good idea.
I'm afraid I can't turn into
somebody else just to please you.
More's the pity. Oh, no,
why should you change to please us?
What is the general feeling
in Ireland now?
That we're in sight of throwing off
the English yoke.
Do you approve of the new act?
Would you of your country
being divided by a foreign power?
Well, won't it bring home rule
for Southern Ireland nearer?
Home rule on English terms
presided over by an English king.
Is keeping the monarchy a problem?
Would it be a problem for you
to be ruled by the German Kaiser?
Carson, are you all right?
I've been very clumsy, my lord.
I do apologise.
Is it true that Irish gardens
have more variety than ours?
Oh, yes. Don't you remember
Lady Dufferin's ball at Claneboye?
The gardens there were heavenly.
I thought them very down on him.
That is because you know nothing.
And wasn't he down on them,
insulting our country,
insulting the King?
I thought it was a miracle
his lordship held his temper.
But it must be hard, Mr Carson.
To sit up there
with people he used to drive around.
It is hard, Mrs Hughes.
Please, sit down.
Is there something we can do, sir?
I just wanted to come down
to say hello.
I wouldn't want you to think I'd got
too big for my boots. That's nice.
I hope you and Lady Sybil are well?
We are. Thank you.
And we've been following
the story of Mr Bates.
Mary keeps us informed.
Still, I mustn't interrupt
your dinner.
Thank you for coming down.
He's settled into his new life.
'Mary keeps us informed.'
Well, he knows her now.
What's that got to do with it?
His lordship would never call her
Mary when talking to me. Never.
If he wants to play their game,
he'd better learn their rules.
Tomorrow let's ask the servants
to come up and dine with us
to make things easier.
You must get him to stop calling
Granny 'my lady'. And Mama.
We need something that doesn't sound
too stiff and grand.
Lady Grantham, of course.
And he can call me Lord Grantham.
That doesn't sound stiff or grand
at all.
One step at a time.
So what did the lawyer want?
I presume he turned up.
He did, and it's rather complicated.
But you were right.
It was about Reggie's will.
So he's left you something?
Never mind that now. Sit down
and tell me about the relations
that are coming for the wedding.
I want to unscramble them in my head.
Go to bed when you're done.
I'll go to bed when I'm ready.
What's happened to you? Have you
swapped places with your evil twin?
I'd like to know where the new maid
is. That's what you promised.
They've got a footman.
Where's the maid?
I know and I'm sorry,
but I spoke to Mr Carson tonight
and they won't be taking
anyone new on.
Except a footman. I don't know
how Mr Carson managed it
because his lordship's
put his foot down.
But you're called my assistant now
and you've seven shillings extra
every month.
You've still kept me here
with a dishonest representation.
Oh, dear!
Have you swallowed a dictionary?
Somehow none of it seems to matter
when we're in Dublin.
Class and all that
just seems to fade away.
I'm Mrs Branson and we get on with
our lives like millions of others.
But here he feels so patronised.
And he hates it.
But you don't regret it?
No, never.
He's a wonderful, wonderful man.
I just wish you knew him.
Darling, we will know him.
We'll know him and value him.
I promise.
Anyway...
I'd best go upstairs
and make sure he's not too suicidal.
Good night.
Oh, by the way,
I don't know if Mama's told you...
But the whole Grey family's
coming tomorrow night.
Including Larry?
Crikey.
You'd better warn Tom.
Oh, and, Sybil, I wouldn't tell Papa
about being Mrs Branson.
But who are the Greys?
And why does it matter
that they're coming?
The father, Lord Merton,
is Mary's godfather.
But Larry Grey used to be keen on me,
when we were young.
Were you keen on him?
No. I don't think so.
I can hardly remember, to be honest.
So what are you saying?
Nothing particularly.
But we could run into Ripon
and find some tails.
We have the money.
I won't spend more of that money.
All right.
Please don't talk about Ireland
all the time.
I just want to make things easier
for you.
For me or for you?
Don't disappoint me, Sybil.
Not now that we're here.
Shall I order the car?
I don't think
I can refuse a lift with Mother
and then make the poor man
go out again.
I'll walk.
It might rain.
Then I'll get wet.
Now come and kiss me.
So, if they can't find Mr... Pillbox,
what will you do with the money?
Pullbrook. And they will find him.
But if they don't?
Then I'll decide what to do.
Or we will.
Because I can't keep it.
No, of course not.
Why have you so heavily invested in
one enterprise? Wasn't it foolish?
Has some of my fortune been lost?
Some.
All.
Almost all.
Oh, my dear.
How terrible for you.
It's not so good for you.
Don't worry about me. I'm an
American. Have gun, will travel.
Thank god for you, anyway.
You know what?
I'm glad we have a wedding
to celebrate.
Let's make sure it's a great day.
If it's to be our last,
let's make it a wonderful last.
Enjoy our lovely home and the lovely
people we spend our life among.
Bit early for drowning your sorrows.
I thought it might be better
if I moved down to the pub.
You're not serious?
I can't go through many more dinners
like last night.
You don't make it easy for them.
Do you really think you can recruit
cousin Robert for Sinn Fein?
I don't know what gets into me.
I can see them staring
and I know they don't want me here.
Well, don't include me. Or Mary.
She wasn't too keen on the idea of a
chauffeur for a brother-in-law.
Forget that. She's a pragmatist.
She could be a tough fighter, too.
Let's hope she's not tested.
Forget this and walk back.
We're brothers-in-law
with high-minded wives.
We'd better stick together.
It's all there.
Friends
- though there weren't too many...
tradesmen, acquaintances.
But I can't see
what you'll get out of them.
I do not believe,
when Vera decided to kill herself,
she never mentioned it
to another living soul.
We know she left no note.
I wish to god she had.
But why are you sure it was suicide
and not murder?
Well, I know you didn't kill her.
What's the alternative?
A thief broke in, cooked an arsenic
pie and forced her to eat it?
It's not a very likely scenario.
You can see why they convicted me.
I'm going to write to everyone
in the book,
in case she said,
or, please god, wrote anything
that could suggest a desire to die.
How long will that take?
Why? Are you going somewhere?
I should have gone into cooking.
I could pick it up in a trice.
Why didn't you, then?
It's a hard ladder for a man.
For every Escoffier and Monsieur
Careme there's a thousand dogsbodies
taking orders from a cross,
red-faced old woman.
Who's this you're discussing?
Hello, Mrs Patmore.
I didn't see you standing there.
Obviously not.
Sarah thought
I'd be better off as a butler
and that's what I'm trying for.
I think you're right.
I'd rather be giving the orders.
To a cross and red-faced old woman.
Yes, we know.
There. Is that what you meant?
Yes. Perfect.
Slightly new, but not too different.
We'll see if Sir Anthony notices.
I know they all think he's too old
for me, but he's not.
Bates is older than you
and you're as happy as lovebirds.
Our situation is hardly ideal,
but, yes, we're very happy together.
Which is all that matters.
As I keep telling them.
I've no time to talk.
His lordship's not come up yet.
Well? What is it?
I was hoping you could help
young Alfred to find his way about.
As a footman, you mean.
As a valet.
He's looking after Mr Branson now.
Though I daresay a chauffeur
can dress himself.
But you could tell him what he needs
to know, give him an advantage.
Why? What's the rush?
You've heard Mr Matthew
has turned down Mr Molesley?
Blimey, you don't want much, do you?
Can you remember what I had
to go through to be a valet?
Of course. I watched it, didn't I?
But young Alfred is to make
the great leap in one bound?
Well, I'm sorry, Miss O'Brien,
but I'm not convinced.
If you'll excuse me.
It's infuriating.
There's nothing he can do.
I don't agree. I think it's feeble.
He should will himself not to be ill
and then collapse the next day.
Whom will you ask instead?
I'm not sure.
I've known Sybil all my life.
You can imagine how curious I was
when I found out
you'd be here tonight.
Never thought we'd meet in person.
As opposed to what? In spirit?
Well, you see, to us,
in marrying you
it seemed like Sybil
had left Downton Abbey forever.
If you know what I mean.
I know exactly what you mean.
Did they lose your suitcase on the
way over? How maddening for you.
No, my suitcase arrived safely,
thank you.
Along with my manners.
He's still dressed as
the man from the Prudential, I see.
Yes, it's nice to have someone
from the real world, isn't it?
Hello, Mama. Can I tempt you
to one of these new cocktails?
I don't think so.
They look too exciting
for so early in the evening.
Don't you think so, Carson?
Better avoided, my lady.
I think so.
What a pleasure it is to see you
out and about, Sir Anthony.
I want to say,
'Can I be of any help?'
but you don't seem to need any.
He doesn't need help at all, do you?
He won't let me do anything.
Mustn't be a nuisance, you know.
Are you coming to the wedding?
Of course.
Well, if you really want me.
I do. I really do.
You look very nice. Have you done
something jolly with your hair?
I say. What the devil...
What is it?
Dinner is served, your ladyship.
How's it going?
Awkward.
Mr Branson's well away
and Lady Sybil doesn't like it much.
He's only had one cocktail.
Maybe he was drinking before
he came down to calm his nerves.
No, I don't agree,
and I don't care who knows it.
The Black and Tans are there
to restore order, are they?
Why don't they just murder
the entire population
and then you wouldn't hear a squeak
from them.
Is there any way to shut him up?
If I knew that,
he wouldn't be here at all.
Are you interested
in Irish politics, Lord Merton?
I was only just saying...
He's interested in Irish repression.
Like all of you. Look,
of course this stuff matters to you.
Yes, it does matter...
this stuff.
It matters a very great deal.
What's so funny?
Nothing.
I'm just enjoying this vivid display
of Irish character.
Please, Tom.
We don't need to wear everyone out.
Why? What's the matter?
Am I not being polite enough?
What a minute.
This was down to you, wasn't it?
I don't know what you mean.
Yes, you do.
You put something in his drink,
didn't you? Just before we came in.
That's not true, is it, Larry?
What a beastly thing to do.
Oh, come on, Edith. That's not like
you. You could always take a joke.
A bully's defence.
Listen, Mr Grey has given Mr Branson
something to make him appear drunk.
Could it be drink?
No, not drink. Some horrible pill.
Sybil, take him upstairs.
Il ne manque que ca.
Tom has been the victim
of a cruel prank
which I know you'll all
be kind enough to forget.
Forgive, perhaps. Forget? Never.
Is this true, Larry?
I don't know why you're getting
so hot under the collar.
He's only a grubby little chauffeur.
Be silent this instant, sir!
I apologise for my son, Mr Branson.
Unreservedly.
I only hope
you'll recover before the wedding.
I hope so too.
Since I want him to be my best man.
Bravo. Well said.
Do you really mean it?
Honestly?
I've told you. If we're mad enough
to take on the Crawley girls,
we have to stick together.
Thank you, Matthew.
Thank you so much.
That was rather marvellous of you
to expose Larry Grey like that.
You saved the day. I wouldn't
say that. Matthew saved the day.
No, it was you.
I do hope we'll see a bit more of you
once the wedding's over.
Well...
Wouldn't you like that?
I should like that very much.
Much more than I probably ought to.
Edith, let Sir Anthony go.
Goodnight, Papa.
Well, that's the last of them.
Where are the others?
They've gone to bed.
So's Edith. And so should we.
Golly. What a night
for the county to feed off.
It was good of Matthew
to show solidarity.
I suppose so.
We're going to need
all the solidarity we can muster.
When will you tell the girls?
I think I should tell Mary now.
Not before the wedding, surely.
I must. They're disagreeing
about where they should live.
It would be wrong for me
to keep it from them.
They can discuss it on the honeymoon
and decide more sensibly.
Should we say something to your
mother when she gets here? No.
She'll go into state mourning
and cast a pall
over the whole proceedings.
Thank god she missed tonight's drama
or we'd never hear the end of it.
Don't worry. She'll bring
enough drama of her own.
Hm.
It won't work, you know.
If you don't admit your guilt,
they won't let you go.
How can I admit what isn't true?
Why do you have to be so pious?
You're a touchy fella, aren't you?
Don't push me, Craig.
Is that a warning?
Yes. Yes, it is.
I'm warning you.
I'm not sure about the hat.
Is it supposed to look crooked?
Don't listen to her. I love it.
You're not to change a thing.
Anna?
I think you look lovely, my lady.
Stop. Wait. Who is it?
Your long-suffering papa.
I suppose he can come in.
What's this for?
Going away.
How does it look?
Expensive.
Twice the national debt, I'm afraid.
But I know you don't mind.
Can I have one moment alone
to give Mary my blessing?
That's lovely. Shoo, everyone.
Go on, bless me.
Of course. But there's something
I feel I ought to tell you first.
I wanted to wait until you got back,
but I don't believe I can.
That sounds rather ominous.
Hello, Mr Molesley. I got
a message to call on Mrs Crawley.
Very good, sir. If you'd like
to give me your hat and coat, sir.
Are you going up to the house
to welcome the Queen of Sheba?
Oh, I think so.
Are you?
No.
I'll pay homage at dinner.
I've always admired the way
Mrs Levinson is never overawed
by the set-up at Downton. Was
Napoleon overawed by the Bourbons?
Come in, Tom.
May I call you Tom?
Of course.
Good afternoon, my lady.
That is, Lady Grantham.
I'm glad to find you here because...
I want to apologise
for last night.
Oh, there's no need.
We know it was not your fault.
You weren't the first drunk in that
dining room, I can assure you.
Only the first republican.
Well, you've got me there.
Why was it you wanted to see me?
We asked Molesley to look out
Matthew's old morning coat.
He's confident he can make it fit.
That's very kind, ladies.
But I don't approve
of these costumes.
I see them as the uniform
of oppression
and I should be uncomfortable
wearing them.
Have you quite finished?
I have.
Good.
Please take off your coat.
Molesley, do help him.
If you'll just slip it off, sir.
Shouldn't he put the waistcoat
on first?
What's going on? They're forcing me
into a morning coat.
He has no say in it?
No, he doesn't. And nor do you.
Well, what do you think, Molesley?
It'll need lifting a little here,
my lady.
I'll move the buttons.
Fine.
I think the shoulders look odd.
Mm.
Come war and peace,
Downton still stands
and the Crawleys are still in it.
Cora.
Mother, how lovely to see you.
As long as it is.
Robert, aren't you going to kiss
me? With the greatest enthusiasm.
Tell me, where does this come from?
I hired it in Liverpool. Why?
I thought it might be a gift
from the US government
to help get Britain back on its feet.
Carson and Mrs Hughes. The world
has moved on since last we met.
And we have moved on with it, madam.
Really?
It seems so strange to think
of the English embracing change.
Mrs Hughes, this is my maid - Reed.
Sybil, tell me all about the
arrangements for the birth.
We do these things so much better
in the States.
Edith, still no-one special?
Oh, well, never mind. You must take
a tip from the modern American girl.
Mary, dearest Mary.
Now, you tell me all
of your wedding plans
and I'll see what I can do
to improve them.
What's the matter with you?
Mrs Patmore knows.
Shall I tell you Mrs Levinson's
requirements during her stay?
No, tell her.
Er, yes, Miss Reed. How can I help?
To start with I will need goats' milk
in the mornings.
Goats' milk? Fancy that.
She drinks only boiled water.
Really?
In England, that is.
Shouldn't Daisy do this?
I ought to take the tea up.
I'll have it ready in a moment.
No fats, no crab
and nothing from the marrow family.
Do explain again how exactly
you are related to all of us,
Mr Crawley.
Rather distantly, I'm afraid.
My great-great-grandfather
was a younger son of a third earl.
My. I'm going to have to write
that down, so I can study it.
Look at our page in Burke's.
You'll find Matthew there.
Good. Because I would
so like to understand
why he gets to inherit
my late husband's money.
I know. It's funny, isn't it?
Not everyone shares
your sense of humour.
Surely it doesn't matter
now that they're getting married.
In fact, we'd better turn him out
or it'll be bad luck for tomorrow.
Quite right.
You must be the chauffeur
I've heard so much about.
I am, ma'am.
Tom's a journalist now, Grandmama.
Oh, well, well. I've heard of those
journeys on my side of the water.
It's very pleasant to hear of them
happening here.
It's all right, Mama.
You can leave us unchaperoned.
After tomorrow,
all things are permitted.
Don't embarrass me.
Bye, Matthew.
Get a good night's sleep.
How many moments of Crawley history
has this room seen?
And many more to come.
I hope so.
In fact, what happened in the search
for... Mr Pumpkin?
Swire's heir.
Have you heard anything?
Yes, Charkham sent a telegram.
I've got it here, actually.
'Convincing proof
of Pullbrook's death. Stop.
Investigating date.'
What does that mean?
Well, if Pullbrook died after Reggie
then his heirs get the money.
If he died first, then I do.
But that's absurd. What right have
his heirs to inherit anything?
Darling, what right have I? Frankly,
what difference does it make?
I shan't keep it if I get it.
Well, actually, you will.
Because something rather terrible
has happened.
You see, apparently Papa
has lost a great deal of money.
Enough to ruin him.
Enough for us to lose Downton.
God, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. Yes, but surely if
Mr Pullbrook did die before Swire,
then we're saved.
Darling, I don't think
you understand.
Reggie Swire put me in his will
because he believed
I was his daughter's one true love.
So you were.
Yes, but...
But I broke Lavinia's heart
and she died. He never knew that.
How could I possibly allow myself
to profit from her death to...
to dine in splendour
because I took away
a woman's will to live?
So, you're prepared to destroy us
in payment for your destroying her?
Darling, please. You know
I would do anything for this family.
Anything except help us.
Except save Papa from living out
his days in humiliation and grief.
And what about us?
What about our children?
God, Matthew,
how can you be so disappointing?
Mary, please.
No! Don't you see what this means?
Don't you see what a difference
this makes?
It means that you're not on our side,
Matthew.
It means that deep down
you're not on our side!
How are you getting on
with your new companion?
I don't like him,
but so far I've kept it to myself.
So, who are the bridesmaids?
You don't care about all that?
You're wrong.
It's the stuff of my dreams.
The panic that a dinner won't
be ready, or a frock isn't ironed,
or a gun wasn't cleaned.
Do you know where you're going
for the honeymoon?
I want to talk about that.
They'll stay in London with
Lady Rosamund for a couple of days,
just to get used to each other...
and then they go
to the South of France.
I'll hire replacements in London
and then I'll come home instead.
Lady Mary won't mind. I'll pay.
Why would you do that?
Well, to be near you, of course.
Don't you understand?
While I'm in here you have
to live my life as well as your own.
Go to France, see some sites,
get us some memories.
But I wouldn't be home for a month.
Won't we have something
to talk about?
Go. I insist.
For my sake.
I was so afraid
I was going to be late.
Ah ha ha.
Violet.
Oh, dear.
I'm afraid the war has made
old women of us both.
Oh, I wouldn't say that. But then,
I always keep out of the sun.
How do you find Downton
on your return?
Much the same, really.
Probably too much the same,
but I don't want to cast a pall
over all the happiness.
How could you ever do that?
Tell me, what do you think
of young Lochinvar
who has so ably carried off
our granddaughter and our money?
Do you approve of him?
Not as much as you will...
when you get to know him.
Has he gone home to change? Oh, no,
we won't see him again tonight.
The groom never sees the bride
the night before the wedding.
Nothing ever alters for you people,
does it?
Revolutions erupt
and monarchies crash to the ground
and the groom still cannot see
the bride before the wedding.
You Americans never understand
the importance of tradition.
Yes, we do.
We just don't give it power over us.
History and tradition took Europe
into a world war.
Maybe you should think about
letting go of its hand.
There you are.
I see you've said hello to Grandmama.
She is like a homing pigeon.
She finds our underbelly every time.
Dreadful woman.
No, it wasn't me.
Someone sent Sybil and Tom
the price for the tickets to
come over.
Does it matter who it was?
It meant we could be at the wedding.
Of course I wish it had been you,
Papa. But I don't mind.
I thank them, whoever they are.
Well, I'm very glad you're here, but
it wasn't me either, I'm sad to say.
I love a mystery. Who could it be?
My guess is cousin Isobel.
She always likes to stick her oar in.
I'm going to ask her.
For heaven's sake. It was me.
You? But it wasn't your writing.
No. Smithers did it.
Like all ladies' maids
she lives for intrigue.
You wanted me to come here?
I wanted Sybil and her husband
to be here for Mary's wedding, yes.
Why keep that secret?
Silly, wasn't it?
I'm very touched. I'll admit it.
How democratic.
Makes me think
maybe I have been mistaken in you.
I am a woman of many parts.
After all, Branson is...
I mean, Tom...
You're a member of the family now.
You'll find we Crawleys
stick together.
Not always.
Mary, what is it?
Nothing, it's just...
Oh, Mary.
Oh, there you are.
That's all for this course.
Don't you think, Daisy?
Is Daisy all right, Mrs Patmore?
Oh, yes.
She's been such a big help.
Now, I think we should
check the pudding, Daisy.
Don't you agree?
It's nerves. Everyone cries
at some point before their wedding.
But what was the quarrel about?
I'm not sure. I know she accused him
of not being on our side.
Oh, well, I hope she's wrong.
That could be rather serious.
Of course he's on our side. It's
ridiculous. I'll go and see him.
No, I'll go. I'm his best man.
I should be the one to go.
What? I know what it is
to marry into this family.
I'm not comparing myself
to Mr Crawley,
but he is another kind of outsider.
Well, I hardly...
Well, why not? He's the one
who'll lose his job
if the wedding's cancelled.
I see what you're doing, you know?
What's that, then?
Not responding to my protest.
Oh... 'Not responding
to my protest.'
Very elegant, I must say.
Who've you been talking to?
Thomas?
Well...
Oh, just give me the cloth
and I'll dry.
Suppose he never gets the money...
It's not about the money.
It's that he won't save Papa
when he could.
But he has to be true to himself.
That's the point. He puts himself
above the rest of us.
Don't you see?
What I see is a good man, my lady.
And they're not like buses.
There won't be another one along
in ten minutes' time.
It seems big, but it's not big.
And if it happens?
I get the money.
I can't do what she wants.
It's strange for me to be arguing
about inherited money
and saving estates.
When the old me would like to put
a bomb under the lot of you.
But?
But you're meant to be together.
I've known that as long
as I've been at the house.
And at first this kept you apart
and then that kept you apart.
But please don't risk it
a third time.
Because I'll tell you this.
You won't be happy with anyone else
while Lady Mary walks the earth.
Call her Mary, please.
Never mind what I call her.
I know what I'll call you
if you let this chance slip
through your fingers.
I just need a word.
No. Go away.
I'm undressed. You can't come in.
One word. Come to the door.
Please. Just give him this chance.
I won't look at you.
It'd be unlucky if you did.
Only if we were getting married.
Which we are.
My darling, I refuse to quarrel
about something that hasn't happened
and probably never will.
That's what Anna says.
Then she's right.
My darling, I'm sure we will fight
about money and about Downton,
about how to rear our children,
about any number of things.
Then shouldn't we accept it?
Matthew, I've been thinking...
And I'm not angry now,
truly I'm not.
But if we can disagree over
something as fundamental as this,
then shouldn't we be brave
and back away now?
No.
It's not because you're afraid of
calling it off? Because I'm not.
No.
It's because of something Tom said.
That I would never be happy
with anyone else
as long as you walked the earth.
Which is true.
And I think you feel
the same about me.
Can I kiss you?
Because I need to.
Very much.
No. It's bad luck to look at me.
What about if I close my eyes
and you do too?
All right.
But you mustn't cheat.
Good night.
Right, I'm off to collect Matthew.
You look very smart. I hope so.
Because I'm extremely uncomfortable.
Branson...
That is, Tom.
I want to thank you for what you did
last night. I'm grateful. I mean it.
They're both strong characters.
I'd say we have plenty of slamming
doors and shouting matches to come.
Forgive me,
I was about to be indignant,
but you have a perfect right
to speak as you do.
I hope you mean that too.
I do.
Now, hurry up.
You'd ask if there was anything
you wanted me to tell you.
I mean, I'm sure you know.
More than you did.
And relax. There isn't anything
I need to hear now.
Because when two people love each
other, you understand, everything...
It's the most terrific fun.
Careful, Mama, or you'll shock Anna.
I'm a married woman now, my lady.
I think we should go.
What about Anna? How are you going
to get to the church?
They're waiting for me
in the wagonette.
I'll see you there.
I know mine was a wild
runaway marriage, darling.
And yours is the one
everyone wanted.
What's so thrilling is that
this is every bit as romantic.
Thank you, for always being so sweet.
Love and position in one handsome
package. Who could ask for more?
Never mind Edith.
Well, very, very good luck,
my beautiful daughter.
Now, you've a great big porter cab
all to yourselves. Think of that.
So we'll expect you to behave
as if you were quite grown up.
You can do that, can't you?
Got everything you need?
Yes.
Hop in, then.
Careful with your dress.
Settle down.
All right?
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
Good luck!
Have you got everything you need?
We do.
Now, be off with you
and enjoy yourself.
I wish we were going.
Who'll get the food ready
for when they come back?
Still, fetch your coat
and we'll see her off.
Right, see you in a minute.
We're just leaving now, my lord.
As soon as we've got Anna.
Here comes the bride.
Will I do, Carson?
Very nicely, my lady.
Thank heavens you got everything
settled. You had me worried.
It's not quite settled, I'm afraid.
He won't get off that easily.
But you're happy?
I am.
And what about you?
I'm so happy, so very happy,
I feel my chest will explode.
It's so lovely that you're here.
Come behind us.
I can't. I'm not family.
But you almost are.
Morning.
Thank you.
Molesley, I'm very grateful to you
for keeping Mr Branson
up to the mark.
We both are, aren't we?
We certainly are.
Thank you, sir.
This is a proud day, Mrs Hughes.
I don't know if I'm proud, but I'm
very glad you're happy, Mr Carson.
You're next, darling, you'll see.
Will I?
So encouraging
to see the future unfurl.
As long as you remember it will bear
no resemblance to the past.
Good luck.
You came.
To be honest,
I wasn't completely sure you would.
I'm glad to hear it.
I should hate to be predictable.
I'm sorry, it still seems odd
to be found in your bed.
Isn't it dangerous to let
this Strallan nonsense simmer on?
Ask him to end it.
Somehow the poor chap
managed to burn a hole in my tails.
This is what comes of making him run
before he could walk.
We've 20 lords and ladies
in the drawing room
and we've got no dinner
to give them.
♪ Let me call you 'sweetheart'
♪ I'm in love with...
His lordship's in trouble. He thinks
he may have to sell. Sell Downton?
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
www.tvsubtitles.net